DM: Right.
DM: Uh, yeah.
Delwath: Did you get a better view from up there?
DM: Yeah, I mean, you're 200 feet up.
Delwath: Yeah. I'm, let's climb... I'm gonna climb up and see what's up there.
Delwath: You wanna come with me?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Walk up.
Unknown: I'll go if you do.
Delwath: What?
Delwath: Can you climb?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: All right. Seeker, bye.
Delwath: [laughs] Um-
Kenzo: Kenzo walks up. Just starts just casually walking sideways up the-
DM: Yeah.
DM: So okay, two things you notice as you get to the top.
DM: One is that, um, you can see that at the,
DM: um... So at the
DM: ocean spots, so the, the
DM: statue is, like, standing with the cliffs go here, the statue's standing here.
DM: So the cliffs come up to, like, the base of its, the base of its legs,
DM: and then it goes-
Delwath: Yeah
DM: ... extends 150 feet out from there.
DM: Um, and you couldn't really see this before because it's blocked by the legs, but there's a ruin.
DM: It looks like there maybe once was up here, extending out, like in, nestled in between the legs.
Delwath: Mm.
DM: Um, all you can see now are the, like, pilings.
Delwath: Mm-hmm.
DM: But there's a clear row of stone pilings that extend out, and there's steps carved into the side of the cliff that go up to meet the base of the road.
Delwath: Can we see...
Delwath: How many of the other statues can we see from here?
DM: Um, from here, looking...
DM: So okay, here's something I used ChatGPT for.
DM: I was like, "Tell me what something would look like from 5, 10...
DM: What would the Statue of look like, Liberty look like from 5, 10, 15 or 20 miles away?"
Delwath: Oh.
DM: And then I asked it, "And what if somebody had supernatural perception like Wellby?"
DM: Um-
Delwath: 'Cause, right, 'cause it's, we presumably can't see the three on the other side at all-
DM: You can't
Delwath: ... 'cause they'd be blocked by the mountains.
DM: Those are blocked by the mountains. You can see, so you can see clear details of the two on either side of you.
Delwath: Mm-hmm.
DM: They're each about seven, eight mile...
DM: Or I don't know exactly the distance.
Delwath: Right.
DM: But it's, like, um, 12 miles away, and the one to the south is the Night Queen.
DM: You recognize that. The one, um-
Delwath: The Night Queen? [laughs]
DM: That's another one of the Lost Luguna gods.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Um, the one, um, to the
DM: north, um, is the Mother.
DM: Another one of the
DM: Lost Luguna gods. You can't see from a dist- But you can see the roads clearly running from them.
Delwath: Right.
DM: Um, it, your sense from up here, at least of those two, is it looks like there are also these kinds of-
Delwath: Right
DM: ... pilgrimage kind of-
Delwath: And can we see these two statues at all?
DM: You can see those two statues-
Delwath: But can't tell-
Unknown: ... but you can't see any detail on them.
Delwath: Okay.
DM: Um, and you put, you can't see anything around past the mountains right up here.
Unknown: I wonder how
Unknown: the different, like,
Seeker: areas of interest of each of these gods would affect, like, what's at each of these little landing spots.
DM: Mm.
Unknown: And would people have-
Unknown: Chosen the right one for their...
Unknown: Well, yeah. You know, like-
Kenzo: You know, it's like different gods represent, like, oh, this is the god of bounty or whatever.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: So if I need, like, a good harvest, I would go to this one or-
Seeker: Or, or is it more that there were sects that worshiped one in particular?
Delwath: But, but yeah, what's the-
DM: Well, I mean, in the modern day, it tends to be,
DM: um, at least in Chardin, where you're most familiar, um-
Delwath: But Wellby would know Sambara religion reasonably well, right?
DM: Yeah, so in, in Sambara it tends to be like each person has, like, a particular relationship.
DM: You know, there's somebody, some, one of the gods they tend to feel the closest to, for whatever reason.
DM: Like, that's...
DM: And, and they usually,
DM: um, would pray to that god to, like, intercede on their behalf with all the other gods.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: So, like, if your, if your personal deity is the Warlord and you need favor in a journey, which would be the domain of, um,
DM: The Wanderer, you would pray to the Warlord to ask for The Wanderer's favor.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: In Chardin, it's a bit less,
DM: um, centralized like that.
DM: There tends to be more kind of organized...
DM: You know, the temple of the, of The Wanderer has, like, the sort of,
DM: you know, The Wanderer's priesthood or whatever.
DM: That's a little bit more...
DM: It's, it's a little bit more centralized around.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: There's not the idea of, like,
DM: uh, like, the gods asking for favors on your behalf with each other.
DM: Um, it's a little bit more kind of,
DM: not exactly sects like most people would, but you would go to the temple of The Wanderer if you needed a favor of The Wanderer, that sort of thing.
Delwath: Mm. Um, but the vibe is always it's one religion-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... with eight sort of avatar divinities.
DM: Right.
Delwath: It's not eight different gods who you...
DM: Yeah, you wouldn't call yourself a Wanderer-arian or something.
DM: You would always be,
DM: um-
Delwath: Like, you don't, nobody would be like, "Oh, yeah, I worship The Wanderer, but not The Mother."
DM: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: Like, it doesn't, they're not-
Unknown: Are there any, like, conflicts between these eight?
DM: They're, they, nobody really...
DM: I mean, they're all kind of archetypes, right?
DM: It's very much not like the Dunmari gods, which are seen as, like, kind of personal and almost humanized, right?
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Like, nobody really... Like, the, the gods don't even have names, right?
DM: Like, they're just The Wanderer or The Mother.
Unknown: Ah.
DM: Right? And everybody sort of-
Kenzo: But are they real the same way the Dunmari gods are real?
DM: Yeah, of course. Like, I mean, they literally
DM: saved humanity, right? There's plenty of miracles.
DM: Like, there's priests that cast spells from these.
DM: They're just not,
DM: they don't have that kind of personal vibe.
Delwath: They don't have personal st- It's not like they were...
Delwath: There's no vibe that they were, like-
DM: There's not, like, a story that they're-
Delwath: ... born or had a story, like, did stuff
DM: ... there's not a story that they're siblings and they have, might have interpersonal rivalries.
Wellby: There's not even a sto- any story that they're a part of.
Unknown: Like-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: ... they don't exist within a narrative whatsoever.
Unknown: They're just the-
Delwath: Right. They don't, they don't do things
Unknown: ... embodiment of a-
Delwath: Right. They cause miracles
Unknown: ... force or a way of being.
Delwath: They don't do things for themselves.
DM: They cause miracles. They don't, they don't have independent life apart.
Unknown: They, there's no s- myths of their independent life apart.
Kenzo: When, when, when we do the, uh, the, the Downfall, um, uh, campaign, um,
Kenzo: it'll be like, like, we'll be characters that end up becoming, like, the new kings, you know?
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: 'Cause, like, there's no-
Delwath: Well, but they're already well established.
Delwath: They were already well established at Drankor during the Downfall.
Kenzo: Oh, well, anyways.
Delwath: We'll, we'll, we'll retcon.
Kenzo: Well, yeah [laughs].
Unknown: We'll, we'll retcon that.
DM: Um, so yeah.
Wellby: Do some gods, like, exist in time and some don't?
DM: So the, the, the theology of Taelgar is...
DM: Well, there's two very distinct kinds of gods.
DM: There's the embodied gods, which are like the halfling gods or the dwarven gods who like are f- have a physical reality and have power
DM: that can't be taken away that's derived from their divine domain, uh, divine, divine domains-
Delwath: Mm-hmm
DM: ... which are like planes, outer planes.
DM: And then there's the-
Delwath: But they also predate the cr- what's important, I mean, they're the first born
DM: They predate-
Delwath: ... because they predate-
DM: Predate the creation of-
Delwath: ... their own creations, right
DM: ... of other races. And they-
Delwath: The halfling gods came before the halflings.
DM: Right.
Delwath: The elven gods came before the elves.
Delwath: The human gods, on the other hand, came after the humans.
DM: Came after the humans.
Unknown: Right. Right, right, right.
DM: And the idea for the called in- incorporeal gods is they are only created by the power of belief.
DM: So when you, when peop- so there are very likely...
DM: In fact, like, the, Delwath's whole backstory, right, is like that, Yalvali, who was one of the,
DM: um-
Delwath: Taanshi
DM: ... the Taanshi, which are these like small gods,
DM: was basically non-existent because-
Delwath: Was super weak 'cause Delwath was his only worshiper
DM: ... the only person who knew about that, that god was just Delwath
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: That's why I had first level magic.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Wait, why are you strong now?
Delwath: Well, because, uh, first of all, he found the other gods.
Unknown: Uh-huh.
Delwath: He found the, a bunch of other Taanshi, and also I rescued
Delwath: Yalvali from being trapped in the shadow dimension-
DM: Right.
Unknown: Mm
Delwath: ... in our little solo quest. That's what Delwath did, is he rescued Yalvali and-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: ... reintroduced the cultural, the Deniquai, to Yalvali.
DM: To the gods who they thought were dead.
Delwath: So, so now they know about him again.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: So they're like, "Oh, the god that we stopped worshiping-"
DM: They had this-
Delwath: "... because he's dead"
DM: ... they had, the Deniquai had this term, the Mesdawi, the gods they thought were killed by Cha'mutte.
Delwath: Right.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: But so now the gods have grown.
Delwath: I mean, they're still not that powerful.
Seeker: Wait, wait, this raises a kind of question whether we could do some, make a similar move on a much larger scale,
Seeker: which is to say, like reawaken the power of certain gods by encouraging like religious fervor among like vast populations of humans.
DM: So theoretically, although part of the,
DM: the deep lore is that for whatever as of yet unknown reason, something about Hkar made
DM: this kind of divine creation much, much easier.
DM: So lots of different gods were born-
Unknown: Oh
Delwath: From the belief on Hkar
DM: ... from the beliefs of people on Hkar, but new gods don't really seem to appear in the modern day very much.
Delwath: I mean, or if they do, they're like a Taanshi.
DM: They're like small. They don't have very much power, right?
DM: So all of the like ancient powerful gods, like even the Dunmari gods, like the Dunmari lived on Hkar and then they left, but their gods existed before they left.
Seeker: So wait, you're saying what we need to do is find Hkar in order to birth a new god to help us in the conflict.
DM: Possibly. Although one of the theories about why Hkar sank was the-
Unknown: Oh, its power
DM: ... all the evil, like the hobgoblins and things were-
Delwath: I like that theory
DM: ... about to reach Hkar,
DM: and if they did, they could-
Unknown: Oh, they could birth an evil god
DM: ... exactly.
Unknown: They could birth... Right. And so the gods actually sank Hkar to save it.
DM: And so the gods were like, "We gotta destroy it to save humanity."
Unknown: Oh, that's amazing.
DM: That's not canonical, but that's one theory.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Wow.
DM: So the, so-
Kenzo: That's like, like, like humans aren't evil, but hobgoblins are evil, so like, you know, like, you know, there, they're not gonna be any evil, evil human gods.
DM: Well, so there is... I mean, there's this, like, so for example, the Binding Stones, right?
DM: So there was, there were of course
DM: many different kinds of gods on-
Delwath: Yeah. Remember Sargon, the god of slavery-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... that the Binding Stones were invented to bind?
Unknown: Mm.
DM: The, the-
Delwath: No, no, no, no, no. They weren't invented...
Delwath: Sorry. We got this whole story from the Philosophers Guild.
Delwath: Sargon was an ancient-
DM: I don't remember this.
Delwath: Okay, so there was this cult of slavery on Hkar,
Delwath: right, that was worshiped this god Sargon.
Delwath: And somehow, the phi- I don't think the Philosophers Guild was clear on how, Sargon was trapped in this plane along with...
Delwath: like trapped in some punishment dimension with his slavery, his slave enthusiast followers.
Delwath: And the Binding Stones were created from the energy that was used to bind a god.
Delwath: They're like the echoes-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... of the energy that this whatever power used to bind a god.
DM: But the basic line-
Delwath: So I mean, if we wanted to be evil, we could go free Sargon
DM: ... there was a lot of con- I mean, sure, there was lots of conflict on Hkar and plenty of not humans who were, you know,
DM: motivated by various kinds of bad philosophy, but eventually the Mos Numena and like a few other gods who were kind of
DM: the, represented the sort of nobler aspects of humanity won out.
DM: And so a lot of the...
DM: But the theory is there's lot, there's potentially lots of these like dead gods.
Kenzo: So wait, but how do we, how do we become these gods?
Unknown: I think we need to awaken-
DM: You gotta go-
Kenzo: Do we just need to, do we just need to get like a bunch of worshipers, and then do we start getting like divine powers?
Unknown: So, so-
Delwath: Well, Beryl became a god because of that.
Unknown: Is that what happened to Beryl?
Delwath: Yeah, Beryl's like semi-divine 'cause he has a bunch of worshipers.
Unknown: Isn't he just like totally divine?
Delwath: Well, I mean he's like weak.
Delwath: He's like the Taanshi, right? Like he's like a weak god.
DM: There's lots of weak, there's lots of weak...
DM: I mean, like, um-
Delwath: Like, um-
DM: Ishimaa became a god, right?
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Like she was a
DM: mortal who was the founder of...
Delwath: But it's just-
Kenzo: But how do we become the most powerful gods?
Seeker: And we only have a week to become gods.
Delwath: Why, why don't... So in more relevant news, is there anything else we can see on the island?
DM: Um, yes, so [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: Can, can we, can we see Hkar from here?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: 'Cause that would be, that would be-
DM: So you can also see-
Kenzo: I feel like this is a highly worthy side quest
DM: ... more detail about the, um-
Unknown: We should just sail off
DM: ... so, so more detail about...
DM: Let me see how far out this is.
Unknown: Sail west.
DM: You can just, you can see a bit more detail about the landscape in general, right?
DM: So the first thing you can see is that the, this area just to the north, like, you know, two, two, one to two miles to the north- Um,
DM: where you can see these, where you could see these towers before
Kenzo: Yeah
DM: ... like from this perspective up here you can see clearly what looks like a ruined town in the center of that.
DM: And the layout seems to be that there's a t- I mean, the town's been utterly destroyed.
DM: Like there's no bu- nothing has a roof.
DM: It's all just-
Kenzo: Right
DM: ... noth- there's nothing taller than one story.
DM: It's all just walls.
DM: But you can, you know, you can see-
Kenzo: Wait, what would-
DM: Look, those that are now-
Kenzo: But the towers are higher than one story
DM: Yeah. So they're in the town itself.
DM: It's support. You can see these like docks as well.
DM: Like-
Kenzo: Ah, okay. So this is on the coast
DM: ... there, there's clearly a sort of port infrastructure.
DM: Um-
Seeker: What would destroy things in a way that just rips the roof off and then leaves the walls standing?
Delwath: Like that seems like-
Wellby: Some sort of like magic blast.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Well, it's not, I mean, the walls are, not all the walls are standing.
Delwath: Yeah. Mm-hmm.
DM: And nothing's higher than, you know...
Seeker: So maybe like a, a very powerful storm.
DM: Yeah. Something like that.
DM: Um,
DM: and then surrounding this port-
Wellby: There's a dog on the porch.
DM: Hi, doggy.
Wellby: A dog out on the porch.
Delwath: That's weird.
DM: I think that the neighbor's dog, they were, I heard them calling it before.
DM: Surrounding this port, like for a few miles in every direction, it, you can see what look like the ruins of like towers and manors and various little
DM: estates on the outskirts of the town.
DM: And this is what these things you could see.
DM: Some of these seem to be less destroyed than the,
DM: than the town itself.
Kenzo: This is where we retire.
Delwath: Now, is this the only, like, is this the only town?
Delwath: Is this like the main town of the island or is there-
DM: That's the only town you can see, but there's more details.
DM: So the other is that on the far outskirts of the town, you can see what looks like a relatively intact, like very big structure, like a coliseum,
DM: um, to the north.
DM: Um,
DM: and it's, it's a, it's a bit of, it's maybe two or three miles from the town itself.
DM: Um, the town's not very big.
DM: But then you can also see from here the landscape.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Like you can see sort of stretching all through this kind of core segment of this kind of wedge of the, um,
DM: of the island. Like every, in a few different places scattered in the distance, you can see these little like ruins of what seem like maybe were
DM: estates or, or manors or something.
Delwath: [clears throat]
DM: It seemed like a lot of, at least this part of the island was...
Delwath: So this wedge here.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Between the Mother and The Wanderer.
DM: That wedge more. Um, and then extending into the burned region.
DM: So on the burned region you can see like what looks like a ruined villa on top of a little hill.
Delwath: Where's the burned region again?
DM: It's that squiggly thing right there.
Delwath: This?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Okay.
Delwath: So the burned region is
Seeker: not a huge fraction of the whole-
DM: No, no
Delwath: ... island
DM: It's like, it's like six miles across roughly.
Delwath: And if we look out like towards these other wedges, do they seem, like the south wedge between the Night Queen and The Wanderer, is that also like settled
Delwath: in or does it seem more wild?
Delwath: Can we tell?
DM: Um, the, so
DM: the shape of the forest is like a kind of, it's actually kind of like a semi-circle where in this, this segment, this sort of northwestern corner,
DM: the forest doesn't extend nearly as far from the edge
DM: and it extends maybe a bit further than you've drawn, drawn elsewhere.
Delwath: So it goes like that?
DM: It, yeah. Maybe more like, and in the north too, like maybe more like that.
DM: Um,
DM: uh, so it, it does, it, it does seem like this northwest quadrant, which is, after all, the, this is the
DM: closest part of the island to the mainland.
Delwath: Right.
Wellby: Mm-hmm.
DM: If you were sailing from the mainland-
Delwath: Right
DM: ... as you did to here, this is where you would land.
Kenzo: And remember, the forest is also weird.
Kenzo: There are like streams that go into it that don't come out.
Delwath: There's like streams that come out of the mountain.
DM: The forest is so weird.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, okay.
DM: Um,
DM: and, and you can't see anything on the other side.
Delwath: Sure.
DM: So if there's anything on the western edge, which is where Kenzo was like, "Oh, there's something like weird about that."
Delwath: Right, right, right.
DM: Like the nature is disturbed on the western end.
DM: Um,
DM: a- and the other thing you can see is on the, so on the north coast, there's a very long stretch of this beach.
DM: Like the, the tower of the Mother that you saw is on a beach.
DM: There's a long stretch of beach.
DM: Um, and it does look like there's...
DM: You can't see any details, but there are also on that northern coast some
DM: maybe structures, maybe ruined structures, but it's a little bit far away to
DM: depict any details.
Delwath: Right.
DM: Um, there, there doesn't seem to be nearly as much settlement
DM: south of the burned region.
Delwath: I need, um...
Delwath: Okay.
Kenzo: So all right. Random, random just like kind of meta game thing.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: What do you... Would it be cool or interesting if like we potentially like moved among a screen here so we can like...
Kenzo: You know, 'cause like normally we're like, when we're on our computers, we can like see like maps and things.
Delwath: Mm.
Kenzo: Or is that, would that be like distracting?
Delwath: Have some kind of shared display.
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying. Yeah. So that way it's like, you know, if we, we could, I could-
Seeker: Right now Mike is just like drawing handheld map.
DM: Yeah. Let's-
Kenzo: Which is great
DM: ... we could, we could fiddle with that this afternoon
Kenzo: We can do that later, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Let's see, let's see. Our radius is-
Wellby: Depends on what we want to look at
Delwath: ... 20 miles.
Kenzo: I think it's just more also just like scene setting.
Kenzo: So you know, it's like when we're playing D&D-
Delwath: The, the radius of our circle thing is 20 miles
Kenzo: ... it's actually pretty cool to have like a just shared display.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: So 125 miles all the way around.
Kenzo: So I mean, if we could sort of represent it at the table, it'd be nice.
Kenzo: Anyways,
Kenzo: figure it out later.
Delwath: So exploring in a circular fashion is gonna take us a long time.
Wellby: What did you calculate for the circumference?
Delwath: Well, it's, the circumference would be 125 miles, right?
Delwath: If the radius is 20.
Wellby: That's a long walk, right?
DM: It's about 15 miles in between each statue.
Wellby: Feels like our ultimate destination is the center.
Delwath: Yes.
Wellby: But do we want to check out the town, the ruined town?
DM: Okay.
Wellby: Do we want to check out the burned area?
Kenzo: Uh, one quick question too. Do you know for beast things, like are there, are there, is there, are there like birds and shit that fly around?
Kenzo: Is there anything alive flying around other than-
DM: Yeah, there's some seabirds. Sure.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. We saw them.
DM: 'Cause you didn't ask them, but you already used your beast questions.
Seeker: I forget to- We, we weren't able to put animal shapes on my-
DM: I did
Delwath: ... character sheet.
Delwath: Oh.
DM: I think I fixed it. Just try reloading your character sheet.
Delwath: That's what it is.
DM: Um, if this-
Delwath: So we have this option now to all
DM: Uh, also just to be clear, when I'm describing the burned region, it's not a region of the island that's burned, it's a region of the island that looks like a burn, so it's like scarred and reddish.
Delwath: Right, it's not black.
DM: It's not black. It's not like a fire burned the area.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: It's like there's this weird sort of garish red, orangey scar.
DM: So...
Delwath: We have, we're gonna have to go over there.
DM: So, so let's-
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. So clairvoyance, what's the range of clairvoyance?
Seeker: One mile, but I can double it
DM: three times.
Delwath: Theoretic-
Seeker: Three times safely. So that would be two, four, eight miles.
Kenzo: Do we have a version of clairvoyance that's like...
Kenzo: 'Cause it'd be cool to like send something like into the middle and just like have it report back like what it sees.
DM: I mean, that would only, that would be slightly risky, but not horribly risky.
DM: That would be doubling it four times.
Seeker: No, but I don't have that many ch- do I have more charges now?
DM: How many?
Seeker: I thought I only had three glove charges.
Delwath: Let me check.
DM: Oh, maybe.
Delwath: Oh, wait, no, there's five.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: How did that happen?
DM: I think I added more so you could do crazy things like send your clairvoyance a million miles away.
Delwath: How, when do you get back the glove?
Delwath: Do you get, is it once a day or?
DM: Long rest. Yeah.
Delwath: So I mean, using all your glove charges on one thing is probably not...
Delwath: I mean, h- how many days till Apollyon wakes?
Delwath: 12?
DM: 12.
DM: And it's about 2:00 in the afternoon right now.
DM: Hard to say if there's anywhere safe to rest, although
DM: the base of the-
Delwath: Water
DM: ... divine statue is probably a pretty safe place to sleep if you need a place to sleep.
Delwath: I think we should,
Delwath: I think we should head,
Delwath: I think we need to head towards the center.
Delwath: I don't think we, I don't think we have time.
DM: Skip the tower.
Delwath: Not,
Delwath: not necessarily skip the tower. I don't think we have time to try and like
Delwath: map the whole island before we start going in, but I do think exploring the town is probably, it won't take us, it's not that much of a detour, right?
Delwath: It's only a couple miles away, right?
DM: It's two mile, the, well, the town itself is, let's see, uh, like three and a half miles from here, but the closest estate is only like one mile, the closest tower.
Delwath: 'Cause it would potentially let us get some information about what was going on here.
Kenzo: Yeah, let's go, let's go to town. But I think maybe before, before we long rest, let's, uh,
Kenzo: send some clairvoyance as far as we can into the-
Delwath: Yeah, if we get to a point where we think we're gonna long rest-
Kenzo: Then we'll do it, yeah
Delwath: ... that's a good idea.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: We'll do it at the end.
Delwath: Okay.
Kenzo: Let's go to town. That makes sense.
DM: Okay.
DM: So are you, so you're leaving the road and heading north
DM: along the beach slightly inland.
Delwath: We're just gonna most direct route.
DM: Most direct route to the, to the ruined port itself or explore a tower?
DM: And are you trying to be, how sneaky are you trying to be?
Delwath: Why do you ask?
DM: I mean, there are little dragonets flying around.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: How much do you want to avoid their notice?
DM: They don't seem to be that i- I mean, they're not scouting, right?
DM: They're not like flying around looking, but...
Seeker: Let's just let them come to us so that we talk to them.
DM: But maybe it would be good-
Delwath: They've already seen us probably.
Delwath: Maybe it would be good to not...
Delwath: Let's, um, let's try a little bit of subterfuge.
Delwath: Why don't Wellby and Kenzo go off a little bit in each direction away from the main body, sneak,
Delwath: and then Delwath and Seeker will just walk obviously towards it.
Kenzo: Let's go ahead.
DM: Okay. So as you gather at the base at this, uh, pilgrim's hostel at the edge of, at the, on the edge of the road, and you can see...
DM: So basically, if you, if you hug the coast and just go straight along the coast, um, you can come to the,
DM: um, you can come to the, the port town itself in, in about an hour's walk if you're trying to be a little bit hidden and, and, and
DM: sneaky without crossing next to any of the, without coming more than half a mile from any of the obvious towers.
DM: If you cut inland slightly, there's a tower that's about a mile from your current location, but like diagonally inland about half a mile.
Delwath: Let's, let's go to the tower.
Delwath: We're gonna head to the tower.
Kenzo: Let's go to the tower.
Delwath: All right.
Delwath: I'm gonna, I'm gonna disguise self to an elven elf.
DM: Okay.
Delwath: Alter self to an elven elf.
DM: And you two are sort of a little bit ahead being sneaky.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: so as you, as you cross the road and you begin to enter into a little bit more disturbed terrain, um, there actually are still a few trees growing
DM: here and, uh, very quickly within about a 10 minute walk, um, you seem to be entering into what looks like the outskirts of,
DM: um, a large sort of manor grounds.
DM: The, the vibe is kind of like, um,
DM: you know, like those, uh, what Victorian English manors where it's like natural gardens, but clearly sculpted, right?
DM: So there's, there's trees, there's sort of not, not everything.
DM: I mean, some things are obviously have grown quite wild, right?
DM: But you can still get a bit of a sense of like, there's still a few paths that cut through the trees.
DM: Um, there's like a little lake that you can see on, in a depression.
DM: There's a statue that's been cracked and is like just mostly buried by the dirt, but that you can still see a little bit sticking up that looks like it used to be like a, you know,
DM: a little gazebo with a statue, like a sort of sitting point by the lake.
DM: Um, and, but rather than a traditional like English villa, about half a mile ahead of you, um, sort of perched a little bit on some high
DM: ground, there's
DM: a tower, like a pretty wide tower.
DM: It's probably...
DM: ... 100 feet in diameter or something like that.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: It only goes up about three stories, um, and then there's a sort of open roof, and then a smaller tower that extends up a- another
Unknown: 50 feet or so before it's cracked at the top.
Kenzo: So wait, like-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... what do you mean by an o- like-
DM: There's a roof
Kenzo: ... is there two towers?
DM: So there's one tower.
Kenzo: So there's like one tower-
DM: There's a second tower on top
Kenzo: ... coming up from the mi- Oh, on top
DM: ... but it's, it's like, it's like, you know, the Empire State Building or something.
DM: There's like clearly a place you can go walk around outside
DM: after the three stories of the bigger tower.
Kenzo: A roof deck.
DM: Right. There's a roof deck.
Kenzo: Ah.
DM: And then there's a smaller tower that goes up, but the smaller tower is clearly cut.
DM: Like it's, it's-
Kenzo: Sure
DM: ... it's cracked.
DM: It might have once gone up who knows how long, but it only goes up about like maybe 30 feet from the roof.
DM: Um, and you can see at this distance, um,
DM: Kenzo and Wellby go ahead and make stealth checks.
Unknown: Um, probably like 23.
Kenzo: Uh, 30.
DM: Yeah, okay. Um, and you two are sort of hanging back, but-
Kenzo: Yeah
DM: ... but trying to be stealthy.
Kenzo: Yeah. 23.
DM: What do you look like?
Kenzo: Uh,
Kenzo: are you wearing that like bright red cloak, that bright red like super cloak?
Unknown: No, I'm, I alter...
Delwath: You saw Delwath like change-
Kenzo: Mm
Unknown: ... his look into...
Delwath: I think like just a human in like a, in like pilgrimage-y type-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... dress. Like simple clothes.
Kenzo: I mean, that is a good, um, uh, cover story.
DM: Okay. So the, the, just to imagine the layout here, there's, there's like a, a, a dell with a, with a
DM: overgrown forest in it, and then there's a path that leads to the dell that goes up to the sort of a, a cleared hill.
DM: The tower is set upon the top of the cleared hill, and then just below the dell there's like a depression with this lake and some ruins around the lake.
DM: And you two are sneaking up towards the tower through the forest quite quietly, and you're just, you two are just like walking on the path.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Okay. So one thing you see as you two come a- and I assume at this point having...
DM: Before you s- before you come too close, you like take 10 minutes and telepathize so you've all got-
Kenzo: Yes. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: you two see and can alert them that there's, uh, as you come to the edge of the forest, on the
DM: ground in front of the tower, um, you can see four small creatures.
DM: They're about
DM: maybe two and a half feet tall, um, bipedal with like legs and, and arms, but also wings in the back, leathery wings, like dragon-like faces.
Kenzo: Ugh.
DM: Um, two of them are sort of brownish green, and two of them are sort of brownish red.
Kenzo: Two.
DM: Um, and they seem to be
DM: just kind of
DM: chilling. It actually looks like they're playing a dice game.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: What? They're playing a dice game?
Kenzo: Okay. That's awesome.
Kenzo: Are they playing fantasy football or is it like-
DM: They haven't, they don't seem to have noticed the two of you.
DM: They will obviously see you as soon as you emerge from the woods.
Kenzo: Um.
Unknown: Soul sight.
Kenzo: Soul sight.
DM: Okay. Um, yeah, you're, you're within about
DM: say maybe 80 feet of the base of the tower.
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, they're... So you soul sight one of them and they're not particularly powerful.
DM: They're like CR3.
DM: You could easily kill all four of them if you wanted to.
DM: The one that you soul sight is-
Kenzo: Why go there immediately, Tim?
Kenzo: Geez. [laughs]
Unknown: Just letting you, giving you information.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: What kind of party are you running?
DM: The one, the one, uh, that you soul sight is, um,
DM: currently worried that his companions or her companions are gonna notice that they're cheating at dice.
Kenzo: Oh, damn. Nice.
Wellby: What's the, like, evil potion?
Kenzo: Does that show up on soul sight?
DM: You don't really get an evil potion on soul sight.
Kenzo: Are they, are they cute, or are they like, are they like, are they like Ewoks, or are they like, you know, is it, is it like-
Unknown: Or gremlins? Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. [laughs] Thank you. Thank you.
Unknown: No, no, they're not gremlins.
Delwath: Ewok to gremlin continuum. [laughs] The Ewok to gremlin continuum.
Kenzo: Where do they fit? [laughs]
DM: They're, they're kind of in the middle of the Ewok to gremlin continuum.
Kenzo: Okay. Okay.
Kenzo: Interesting.
Seeker: Ken says they woke up on the wrong side of the tiny dragon bed.
Kenzo: Big time.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Do I speak Draconic? I speak Draconic.
Unknown: Kenzo speaks Drac- Draconic.
Unknown: You do, do not speak Draconic.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: You don't understand Draconic.
Wellby: Let's roll up, see if they want a couple more players.
Unknown: Do it.
Seeker: I have a really interesting set of dice, by the way.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: If you want to cheat at dice, that's great.
Unknown: We could wipe the floor with them.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: I don't know that we want to.
Delwath: I mean, should, should somebody stay hidden as a backup?
Kenzo: No?
Kenzo: Nobody wants to. Kenzo, Kenzo will, Kenzo will, uh, uh, will-
Seeker: We, we don't know how many friends they have that they could call over in a moment's notice, so.
Kenzo: Hundreds and hundreds, right?
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I mean, you've, you've s- you...
DM: Your estimate from what you saw is there's probably at least 100.
DM: There's gotta be at least 100 of these kinds of creatures around these towers, like between, based on-
Kenzo: But we can still kill them, right?
DM: 100 of them might be a challenge.
Seeker: What's, what's our sort of approach here?
Seeker: We're, we're asking them for
Seeker: just per, you know, their approval to explore.
Kenzo: I think we're making friends.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Make friends. I think making friends.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: So what can we offer them, I guess?
Wellby: Oh, what are they playing dice for?
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. What were they... Exactly.
Seeker: Wait, wait. We know something about what they like because of what happened with the monkeys.
Unknown: What did they do?
Kenzo: What do they like?
Delwath: Well, these are potentially different than the monkey creatures.
Unknown: Why?
Delwath: The monkeys would think we're fly- well, maybe these guys can fly.
Delwath: Oh, they have wings.
Unknown: They have wings, yeah.
Unknown: If this is the same creatures that would raid-
Kenzo: They're dimitars
Seeker: ... the jungle. But what would they raid the jungle for?
Unknown: We know.
Seeker: They were getting food, right? Didn't they steal the food from the...
Unknown: Like, and the bats?
Kenzo: I mean-
Unknown: So
Kenzo: ... well, you-
Unknown: I just don't remember.
DM: The, the bats would throw stones at them to dr- or the...
Unknown: Right.
DM: They didn't, they never really got in...
DM: The monkeys would throw stones at them to drive them off.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: But they would come...
DM: You know, they'd always seem like they were just trying to pick up, like, shiny things or like...
DM: They didn't come, they weren't coming to steal food.
Seeker: Shiny. I think we have shiny stuff we could give them probably as an offering.
Unknown: That's interesting.
Kenzo: Are they gambling with... What are they gambling with?
Unknown: So-
Delwath: But, like, what's our... We should have a story as to who we are.
DM: They are gambling, um, with what looks like, um, little polished pieces of
DM: just, like, the local marble or something that are cut into squares and have little marks on them.
DM: Little... Well, you can't read the marks because
Unknown: Little tokens
Kenzo: ... it's
Seeker: We, we have much nicer stuff we could offer them.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: I, I think either all of us or some subset should approach, but we just should have a story.
Unknown: Uh, tell about it.
Kenzo: 'Cause Wellby's got the portable hole.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: we have a few shiny things that-
Unknown: Yeah, I've, I've got a few, uh-
Kenzo: Just a couple, couple, couple coins, you know?
Wellby: We've got some Drankhonian coins, right?
Kenzo: There you go. That's a good idea.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: That's a good idea.
DM: We can assume, uh, you said you were leaving all your money on the island, but...
Unknown: On the ship, but, uh-
Kenzo: I mean, that's like-
Delwath: We're just walking around with it
Kenzo: ... that's exactly-
Unknown: I love how this happens immediately.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: No, no. No, no, no, no.
Unknown: But this makes total sense. We would have some.
Delwath: I know, we certainly wouldn't have done exactly that.
Kenzo: No. Hell, no. We wouldn't have left all the money.
Delwath: We wouldn't leave all the money.
DM: I said we've got... I'm just keeping track of the number of-
Kenzo: No, no, no
Unknown: ... actual-
Kenzo: But this doesn't... No, no, no, but this doesn't even count as one of the, the things.
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: Because what we left, which we did leave, is, like, our hoard.
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: You know, we're not bringing, like, our...
Kenzo: But we-
Delwath: We would carry some
Kenzo: ... we would carry some walking around.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Like, e- not in, even in the portable hole, right?
Unknown: Like I'm sure we all have little coin pouches.
Delwath: Right. We all have little coin pouches.
Kenzo: Yeah, I've got, like, Dran- Dran- Draconian coins-
Delwath: Walking around. Yeah
Kenzo: ... right in my pocket right now.
Kenzo: I don't have to go into the portable hole.
Delwath: Um, so
Delwath: I just think we should have at least a slight...
Kenzo: We're pilgrims.
Delwath: Who somehow happen-
Kenzo: You and I are pilgrims
Delwath: ... to have a portable carrying
Kenzo: And, and, um, yeah, and these are-
Delwath: Sure
Kenzo: ... our, our friends who are with us on a, on a journey.
Delwath: This makes sense and is prudent.
Wellby: Wellby's vote is for total immediate honesty.
Kenzo: We're here to find the, the Jade Hand.
Delwath: We're here to... Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Wellby: Hmm. It's a gamble, but they're gamblers.
Kenzo: I like it.
Delwath: Eh, hold on.
Delwath: I mean, yes, there's a pro for that, but-
Unknown: The key question-
Delwath: The only thing is should we mitigate the risk?
Delwath: Sorry, Eric. Um,
Delwath: we could split up, like Delwath's disguised.
Delwath: I could just walk up and be like, "I'm a pilgrim," see what happens,
Delwath: and then if they seem really bad and like they're gonna be, you know, terrible, then we don't tell them the truth, and then you guys come up secondly.
Unknown: I think the key question is are they-
Delwath: Is that too complicated?
Seeker: ... squatters on this island, or are they working for somebody?
Unknown: We don't know.
Delwath: Right.
Delwath: Like, if they're working for the big boss, we don't necessarily...
Unknown: We want to... Yeah.
Delwath: I think a little bit of subterfuge to start is not a bad thing.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But,
Unknown: but we could do and go with two phases.
Kenzo: I mean, there, there's four of them, right? So, so you could go the radical honesty approach, and if they're like, you know-
Delwath: We could kill them
Kenzo: ... just kill them.
Unknown: Oh, no. That, that makes... That's...
Delwath: I don't wanna just kill them 'cause we made a mistake.
Kenzo: Well, why did we make a mistake if they're actually our enemies?
Kenzo: If they're, if they're actually-
Delwath: [laughs] True
Kenzo: ... if they're actually, like, servants of the big boss.
Kenzo: What?
Unknown: We've killed dozens of people. [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: Seeker would like to register his discomfort with the accidental murder situations.
Kenzo: [laughs] Um, someone like Seeker.
DM: Well, let's... You're just standing around.
Kenzo: You should just, you should just talk to them.
Delwath: Just come talk to them.
Kenzo: Well, I'm, I'm... All right.
Kenzo: Kenzo will approach.
Delwath: Okay.
Kenzo: Kenzo will approach, um,
Kenzo: uh, slowly, but with, with coin in hand.
Kenzo: Like, with-
Delwath: Okay
Kenzo: ... with, with shiny coin in hand.
DM: Okay. So as you... They stop playing immediately.
Delwath: Um-
Kenzo: And Ke- Kenzo will say in, in Draconic, um,
Kenzo: uh, uh...
Kenzo: Can,
Kenzo: uh, uh... Are other players welcome?
Kenzo: And then shows the, shows the, the, his, his, uh...
Delwath: They, uh...
Delwath: So one of them-
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: One of them immediately flies up and starts heading for the top of the tower.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Um, the other says...
DM: And then, um, one of them, like, uh, one of the sort of brownish, reddish ones kind of steps forward and says in Draconic, like, surprised, "Uh, yeah, but
Delwath: who are you?"
DM: And meanwhile, make a, make a perception check.
Kenzo: Both of us?
Delwath: 20s?
DM: Uh, yeah, you're both, you're both close enough to them.
Kenzo: Dope.
Kenzo: Is that a six or a nine?
Kenzo: Six.
Delwath: Uh, 30.
Kenzo: Nine.
Delwath: Um,
Delwath: they're whispering something.
DM: The other two are whispering something to each other in Draconic.
DM: You, like, don't hear it clearly enough to understand it.
DM: Wellby hears it super clearly, but doesn't speak Draconic.
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: Perfect.
Delwath: So you don't know what they're whispering.
Kenzo: Uh, but Tim, uh, just, you know, Solside, are they, like, now, like, scared nervous or are they, like-
DM: The, mm, the one near Solside, I mean, yeah, no, they're, like, um,
DM: curious and kind of excited that something new is happening.
Seeker: Okay. Probably staring at whatever's in your hand.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: Okay.
Kenzo: Um, I'll say, uh, um,
Kenzo: uh...
Kenzo: I'm just gonna shoot, shoot out the truth here.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: no.
Kenzo: No.
Delwath: Well, let's just play, play it nice first.
Kenzo: We, we... Yeah, that's what I'm saying. Like, yes, man, I'm, I'm, you know...
Kenzo: So I'll, I'll say, I'll say, uh, I'll say, uh, uh, "I'm, I'm Kenzo.
Kenzo: I'm a, a traveler here."
Kenzo: Um, just arrived
Unknown: Well, yeah, obviously you don't live here.
DM: I mean, come on, we know.
DM: You've gotta be a traveler. Tell us a little more about that.
Wellby: They are related to the Dimitaur.
Kenzo: Surly, huh? [laughs] So surly.
Kenzo: Um, do you know of, uh, Dunmar?
DM: No.
Kenzo: Do you know of any place outside this island?
DM: I mean, there's stories about Drankor, but we haven't been there in a long time.
Kenzo: You've been to Drankor?
DM: I mean, there's a jungle.
Kenzo: Yeah, there's a jungle, but have you been there recently?
DM: You're pretty, uh, nosy for a newcomer.
Kenzo: I mean, I'm just-
DM: You haven't said anything about yourself.
DM: Where are you from?
Kenzo: I told you, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm, I'm from Dunmar.
Kenzo: Um-
DM: Oh, where is Dunmar?
Unknown: Telepathically.
Kenzo: East.
Unknown: I'm a monk collecting stories.
DM: East?
Unknown: To you.
Kenzo: Where... Wait, Dunmar's east, right?
DM: It's north.
Wellby: North,
Wellby: north.
Unknown: North and west.
Wellby: North. North and west.
DM: North, okay.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: And you're here because...?
Kenzo: I'm a monk collecting stories.
Kenzo: A monk of the Awakened Soul.
DM: They're, they're definitely, like, they're all three staring at the coins in your hand, like, pretty clearly.
Kenzo: And, um, I mean, I do play some dice.
Kenzo: I saw you, you playing a game.
DM: Okay.
DM: So that-
Kenzo: You interested in these?
DM: Uh,
DM: where did you get those?
Kenzo: Where'd we get these?
Unknown: Which, uh-
DM: The Dran-
Unknown: Are they Drankorian?
Kenzo: Yeah.
Wellby: We got them as part of a merfolk treasure hoard.
Kenzo: Ah, okay.
Kenzo: Um-
Unknown: Tell the truth about that.
Kenzo: Yeah, totally. Um, well, we're, we're, we're merfolk.
Delwath: I was collecting stories from the merfolk.
Unknown: Tell them you were-
Wellby: Where's the merfolk? West of Chardin, so very far west of Drankor.
Delwath: Yeah, tell them you were collecting stories from some merfolks.
Kenzo: So, uh, uh, Chardin, you know Chardin?
DM: No.
Kenzo: [sighs] Well, it-
DM: All these places.
Kenzo: I know. You don't seem to know very much about any of these human places, but that's fine.
Kenzo: [laughs] Give him some time.
Kenzo: Um, uh, but yeah, anyways, you know, Chardin, it's, it's, you know, you don't know it, but it's, uh,
Kenzo: it's actually where I'm from. Um, but west of that in the ocean, there was a bunch of merfolk that I was, uh, interacting with and, um, yeah, got these from the merfolk.
Unknown: They look cool, I will say.
Kenzo: Yeah. You recognize these?
DM: Yeah, let's play.
Kenzo: All right.
Kenzo: So wait, you recognize these coins?
DM: I said let's play.
Seeker: He recognizes them as something he definitely wants.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: Can I... Well, what are you guys playing with?
Kenzo: May I see your coins?
DM: He holds up one of these stone tokens.
Kenzo: Can I read it?
DM: Yeah, it's a... They're just notated in, like, with the Draconic runes for, like, one, five, 10.
Kenzo: Are they, like... Does it look like they were made by these creatures?
Wellby: Counterfeiting must be a serious issue.
Kenzo: Okay.
Seeker: I, I suggest we play some rounds to earn their trust, right?
Seeker: Win a few, lose a few, then go all in on, uh, free passage.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenza will commence a-
Wellby: Mm, mm,
Wellby: mm, mm.
Kenzo: Kenza will, uh, begin, will leverage his, um, his, uh, rune counting skills from when...
Kenzo: No, but actually, uh, as a street kid, for sure.
Kenzo: Kenza-
Unknown: Yeah, Kenza's got
Kenzo: ... Kenza, this is actually... He, he definitely does.
Unknown: Fun design.
Kenzo: Yeah. So, uh, what are you, what are you playing?
DM: They're, they're playing a, basically a variant of something like crafts, right?
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: It's like a pretty simple dice game.
Kenzo: Perfect. Perfect. Yeah. Kenza, Kenza, Kenza's like, "All right, let's do it.
Kenzo: Let's go."
DM: Yeah, you pick up the rules pretty quickly.
Unknown: Um-
Kenzo: This is awesome. This is great.
Kenzo: Uh, Kenza's kind of telepath's like, "Do you wanna join us or just let me, let me keep, keep talking with them?"
Wellby: I like keeping an eye on the perimeter, right?
Kenzo: Uh, yeah, you keep an eye on the perimeter.
Wellby: Keeping some watch.
Kenzo: The...
Kenzo: I, I... Anyways, yeah, I'm good.
DM: Wellby does notice that the one that flew up to the tower has disappeared inside the smaller tower at the top.
DM: But so far nothing's emerged from there.
DM: So, so you play for a few-
Kenzo: Oh, actually, uh, Kenza, K- really quickly, uh, can I do, like, a very, um, like, um, limited just, like, are there other...
Kenzo: Is there anything inside the tower, like consciousness wise, other than these little, these, these little dragoneth guys?
Kenzo: Is there anything else? There's something in there?
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Presences?
DM: You'd, you'd have to spend ki to do that.
Kenzo: I'll spend ki.
DM: Okay. Um,
DM: yes, there are another about
DM: eight or say 10 of these ins- at, in the, like, top part of the tower.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: Same kind of dragonets, and as you, like, sense out around, like, there's none, uh, none others in, in this immediate sort of villa.
DM: But, like, you can get a sort of mental layout of it seems like there's, like, little small groups that tend to live
Unknown: in each of these ruined villas, right?
DM: Like-
Kenzo: But any, and, and-
Unknown: ... there's 20 in a, 20 about half a mile away.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: There's-
Kenzo: Any, any, any-
DM: ... not in the town itself
Kenzo: ... any other, any other beings other than these dragonets?
DM: Um-
Kenzo: Entities of any kind
DM: ... so,
DM: uh, yes.
DM: Um,
DM: so now that you're closer and you're sort of focusing not quite so much detail on the, on the sort of burned region and the path, but trying to assess the general area, um, two
DM: things that you note.
DM: One is that the, the town itself and some but not all of the villas, um, but, but really mostly the town, like, you get these strong
DM: waves of
DM: this sort of echoing
DM: death and evil that reminds you very strongly of, like, Karson, like the plague echoes in Karson.
Kenzo: Whoa.
DM: And there's definitely, like, unquiet spirits that sort of haunt the s- the town.
Kenzo: Any inside this tower?
DM: No, no, no. The tower is the...
DM: Actually, you're, like, you have this sort of...
DM: You're, like, closing your eyes and...
DM: This is six ki, by the way, so m- you can mark it off.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: But the, the, the layout you see is it's like, it's like a sort of- ...
DM: tessellated map. Like there's regions of sort of unquiet dead plague echoes, and there's regions of dragonets, and they don't intersect.
DM: Like the dragonets don't go where the dead plague echoes are.
Delwath: But that's all just in this area here.
Unknown: Just in that ar- really mostly the town.
DM: Your, your sense actually is it probably correlates pretty strongly with ancient population density.
Delwath: So somebody destroyed the town with a plague.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: And the dragonets are living in the bits where the plague death doesn't still echo strongly.
DM: Perfect.
Kenzo: Um, all right, let's play some craps.
Kenzo: How do we play?
DM: Um, well, are you trying to win or are you trying to lose?
Kenzo: I'm trying to win.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: [laughs] Of course I'm trying to win.
Kenzo: Fuck these guys. [laughs] Of course I'm trying to win.
Seeker: My, my suggestion, like I said before, was to do a little of both to build interest.
Kenzo: I know.
DM: So, so-
Kenzo: Well, yeah
DM: ... so Kenzo's pretty good
Kenzo: ... well, Kenzo also needs to choose a strategy. Yeah.
DM: I mean, I would say roll a, roll a D20 and add,
DM: like, proficiency bonus and your intelligence modifier.
Kenzo: What, what's my, what's the proficiency bonus?
DM: It's plus five, and int is-
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: ... plus two.
Kenzo: I'm with you guys
DM: ... so add, just roll a D20 plus five.
Kenzo: Kenzo's gonna Kenzo. Kenzo's gonna Kenzo.
Kenzo: Yeah, no, no, but we should play like now.
Kenzo: [laughs] Like, like the... No, no, no. The, the, they should, they should roll in front.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, we should. We should. We should play. Yeah, let's- Like let's, let's, let's play.
Kenzo: I wanna see 'em roll. So what, what are we doing? Are we doing like, it's like whoever gets the highest wins type of thing or?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right, so, so what I... I'm rolling and then there's plus five, and they've got some unknown modifier?
DM: They've got some unknown modifier.
Kenzo: All right, let's fucking go. [dice landing] Wait, why you, why you rolling here?
Kenzo: I'm good at it. I just dropped-
DM: Why are you doing all that?
Kenzo: [dice rolling] Fuck. Fuck.
DM: Fuck yeah.
Kenzo: Thanks.
Wellby: No, no, this is good.
Kenzo: Wait, so-
Wellby: They can't lose.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Wellby: Now you're following Seeker's example.
Kenzo: [laughs] That's what I'm talking about.
DM: So you play, you play the first hand and, um, the, the, the biggest one, um-
Seeker: I have these two sweeper dice, but no way to get it to Kenzo
DM: ... who, who, who-
Kenzo: It's not a fight. I'm close
DM: ... the sort of biggest one, he's, has the sort of most greenish tint on their back-
Kenzo: How far away are we?
DM: ...
DM: um, wins the, the first round and, and seems very happy and you're clo- close.
Kenzo: I, I toss him a draconic coin.
Kenzo: I'm like-
DM: Yeah, so he wins a couple other coins
Kenzo: ... yeah. [laughs] Draconic coin.
DM: And he looks at them and he's like super fascinated by them and he like, uh, um, nudges over to, to his, his, the person sitting next to
DM: him. Uh, "Ra'ghemdros is gonna like these."
Kenzo: What's your name?
Kenzo: Call him.
DM: "Oh, my name?
DM: Well, I'm..."
Delwath: I would cast invisible, but that's burning all your spells.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: I feel like Kenzo and these guys are gonna be friendly.
Kenzo: I think so.
Wellby: I think it's gonna go well.
Kenzo: I'm, I'm excited about this, yeah.
Kenzo: I'm looking forward to these little fucking...
DM: Wait, I think it's the wrong thing.
Kenzo: Kenzo's like not very happy with that roll.
DM: He's very balanced.
DM: Let me...
Wellby: I like that, I like that first of all, the, like it's so Kenzo, that Kenzo's A, playing to win, and B, like very mad at himself that he lost the first round.
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. Of course.
DM: He gave it a chance.
Kenzo: He's like muttering, he's like, "How am I losing to these fucking little turds?"
DM: Uh...
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: I'm, uh, you can, you can call me
DM: Ghesh.
Kenzo: Ghesh, you're, you're fucking lucky.
Kenzo: Let's go again.
DM: Oh, yeah.
DM: I'm gonna win some more. This is gonna earn me lots of favor.
DM: [dice landing] Told ya.
Kenzo: Fuck.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Told ya.
Kenzo: Fuck.
Unknown: You don't know what you're doing, do ya?
Kenzo: You're getting really lucky.
Kenzo: I bet... I haven't played dice in a little bit.
Kenzo: You're just getting really lucky.
DM: Oh, it shows.
Kenzo: Yeah. Okay, okay.
DM: It does.
Unknown: Okay, that's fine. That's fine.
Kenzo: That's fine.
DM: Double or nothing?
Kenzo: Yeah, double or nothing. Let's go. [dice landing] I got you this time, Ghesh.
Kenzo: Goddammit.
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: Kenzo like throws some like rocks.
Kenzo: He's like...
DM: Hand it over.
Kenzo: Fuck.
DM: And he's like elbowing the other ones out of the way.
Kenzo: Ken-
DM: These are my coins
Kenzo: ... Kenzo throws a couple to this guy, Ghesh.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: "Well, you're annoying." You doing okay there, Kenzo?
Kenzo: Shut up, Delwath. Shut up, Delwath.
DM: I'm always happy to play dice with people who seemingly don't know the rules.
Kenzo: Do you, do you need some help? I mean, I know the rules, but you're just getting fucking lucky.
Kenzo: It's fine.
DM: Oh, I'm not sure luck has anything to do with it.
Kenzo: This is a one-on-one game or is it like everybody like?
DM: Um, it's, it's kind of playing one-on...
DM: Like they're, they're kind of-
Kenzo: Good, yeah, okay
DM: ... trading off, right? So it's one-on-one.
Kenzo: Okay, okay, okay.
DM: He's playing against the other-
Kenzo: So it's, there's three of them there?
Unknown: There's, uh, there's two of them there.
DM: There were four, but one flew up into the tower.
Kenzo: Right, right, right. Okay, so now...
Kenzo: All right, so are any of the other ones wanting to play?
Kenzo: Is, is, is, is it just, it's just been me and Ghesh one-on-one right now?
DM: It, the vibe that you get actually is that they, um, Ghesh is like the biggest and the bossiest of them, and seems to have by some maybe in that whispered conversation
DM: or by unspoken agreement sort of muscled them out of the game.
DM: And as long as he's winning, isn't gonna let anybody else try and take his place.
Kenzo: How far away are we?
Unknown: Um, if you're at the edge of the woods, if you're at the edge of the path and you don't wanna like-
Kenzo: Be seen. Yeah
DM: ... be seen, you're like maybe 100 feet away.
Kenzo: What's the name of the guy that he mentioned?
Kenzo: He said, he said, "Oh, somebody's gonna be happy."
DM: Ra'ghabdos. Ra'ghemdros.
Wellby: See what other languages-
Kenzo: Yeah
Wellby: ... can you figure out what other languages they speak?
Kenzo: Can I see what other languages?
Wellby: Can you fig- like try to like just...
Kenzo: Uh,
Kenzo: uh,
Kenzo: yeah, at, uh...
Kenzo: They're not gonna speak any lang-
Delwath: Do you speak Drankorian? That's the only language they would potentially speak, I think.
Wellby: Oh. No.
Wellby: No. Okay.
DM: They don't... It, your, your sen- they probably only speak Draconic.
DM: Like...
Kenzo: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, you don't get to keep these. You have to, you have to give them away to, uh, to Ra- what's the name?
Kenzo: What's the other name you said?
DM: Ra'ghemdros.
Kenzo: Ra'ghemdros. You don't get to keep these?
DM: Are you dumb?
Kenzo: [laughs] Maybe.
DM: You don't bring coin on this island.
DM: Every single shiny thing belongs to her.
Kenzo: Oh.
DM: Obviously.
DM: Wait, do you have more of these?
Kenzo: I mean, just a couple.
Unknown: Ask who r- who... Ask, ask Ra'ghemdros.
DM: Looks, looks around like-
Kenzo: Who's Ra'ghemdros?
Unknown: What else are you car- you're...
Kenzo: Who's, uh, wh-
DM: What else are you carrying?
DM: Maybe we should tell her about you.
Kenzo: Who is she?
DM: Oh, she's the boss.
Kenzo: She your boss?
DM: Oh, she's everybody's boss.
Kenzo: Huh.
Kenzo: Where does she live? Yeah, where does she live?
DM: Oh, there.
DM: She sort of, he points kind of- South-ish
Kenzo: South
Wellby: In the scar
Unknown: In the burn scar, like potentially towards the burn scar maybe
Kenzo: Potentially towards the burn scar
Wellby: Yeah
Kenzo: You know, I saw that, that area that looked like all kind of red and a little destroyed.
Kenzo: She lives in that place?
DM: Uh, destroyed
Kenzo: Or not destroyed, but you know
DM: It's, um-
Kenzo: Disturbed
DM: It's infused with her magic
Kenzo: Huh. Wait and, and is she your friend?
DM: Make a persuasion check
Kenzo: I'm gonna stop rolling this die
DM: She's similar
Kenzo: So
Seeker: Is she a similar size or like 10 times or 20?
Kenzo: All right, that's much better.
Kenzo: Persuasion. Plus one, 16
DM: Yeah. There... I mean, there are... You're, you're losing, so he's happy to talk
Unknown: Yeah. This is a... Yeah. [laughs]
DM: Um, friend,
DM: no, not so much friend.
DM: But she's gonna be my friend when I bring her this.
DM: There's like nothing, no coin left.
DM: There's nothing shiny left on the island for us to find, so sometimes she gets a bit grumpy
Kenzo: Huh.
Kenzo: But I mean, uh, d- does, is it...
Kenzo: Do you guys have like a...
Kenzo: Is... She's- she's your boss, huh?
Kenzo: So like if you step out of line is she mean at all or is she...?
DM: Well, I mean,
DM: if you're hoarding coins, yeah, she'll kill you.
Unknown: But like, you know
Kenzo: She's a dragon. She's a dragon
DM: ... she's pretty easy to please
Kenzo: She's pretty easy to please?
DM: Yeah. I mean
Delwath: So I mean, we should just go kill her, right?
Wellby: Yes.
Wellby: What color is she?
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Yeah. What color is she?
Wellby: Yeah. Yeah
Delwath: Red? Red, green? Probably red.
Wellby: Probably red. Yeah
Kenzo: Probably red
Wellby: Yeah
DM: You know, I- I- I heard a-
DM: a rumor from my friend Megren.
DM: She went to the mainland recently and came back with all sorts of great stuff, and now she's like got her own tower
Kenzo: Really?
DM: So maybe he's eyeing you-
Kenzo: Wait, wait
DM: ... suspiciously
Kenzo: Was he saying
Kenzo: his friend went to the mainland?
DM: Yes His friend went to the mainland, Megren, brought back all sorts of stuff
Kenzo: Yeah
DM: And now Megren has her own tower
Wellby: That's maybe a small coincidence but
Delwath: Uh, did Megren perhaps take a piece of jade?
Wellby: Wow. Wow
DM: And he's eyeing you kind of suspiciously, like trying to size you up.
DM: Like, how could he...
DM: could him and his friends jump you, and how much stuff do you have, and would he get his own tower?
Wellby: Wellby's silently nocks an arrow [laughs]
DM: [laughs] Let's keep playing.
DM: I have a good feeling about this game
Kenzo: I have a good feeling too. I've got a good feeling too.
Kenzo: All right, let's do one more
Wellby: If he wasn't there, couldn't they have all the towers?
Kenzo: That's a great question. [laughs] Kenzo laughs
DM: The game is... He like kicks his fist.
DM: The game is done
Kenzo: Oh, first I want to see some of yours.
Kenzo: Give me one
DM: He gives you like four of the stone tokens and does not give you back any of his coins
Kenzo: [laughs] Kenzo pockets them, satisfied.
Kenzo: That felt good
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: So, so, so wait, so is, uh, uh, is your boss, um,
Kenzo: they, they awake during the daytime?
Kenzo: They sleeping? Can we meet them?
DM: Oh, you want to meet them? Oh yeah, that can be arranged
Kenzo: Huh
DM: I think she'd be
DM: quite interested to talk to you if you're bringing the appropriate tribute.
DM: I mean, you got more of that?
Kenzo: Might be able to get some more. Is she, uh, uh...
Kenzo: So wait, um, he's like a little reddish, reddish-
DM: Reddish-brown
Kenzo: ... reddish-brown, huh? Is she red- reddish-brown like you?
DM: Oh, no, she's much scarier than me
Kenzo: Scarier. How so?
DM: Oh, she's like
DM: 10
DM: times my size and
DM: black as shadow
Kenzo: Black as shadow, huh? 10 times is not terrible
Wellby: How, how long has she lived here?
Kenzo: Ask... Yeah, yeah. How long has she been here, and how long have you been here?
DM: Oh, forever
Kenzo: Forever. What does that mean forever, 1,000 years?
Unknown: [laughs] How would I know?
Unknown: I was only born 17 years ago
Kenzo: You were only born 17 years ago?
Seeker: Huh. Ask if she likes to gamble
Wellby: Oh, yeah
Kenzo: Does she like to gamble?
DM: No. She just...
DM: Why would you gamble? She just takes your stuff.
DM: It's hers anyway
Kenzo: Huh.
DM: You brought it to the island, it's hers
Kenzo: Oh
DM: You think you own your possessions, you don't
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: Yeah. So she's a big black dragon
Wellby: I mean, ancient black dragon, 1,000-year-old black dragon
Kenzo: What do we know about black dragons?
DM: Acid
Kenzo: That's... I'm immune to acid.
DM: Are you? [laughs] No, you're not. You're immune to poison.
DM: That's not acid
Kenzo: Isn't, isn't acid poisonous?
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: I, I pref- I prefer not to contact acid generally speaking
Wellby: Really bad for your skin
Kenzo: It's re- it's-
Wellby: Mm. Mm.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah
Delwath: I mean, we could certainly kill a dragon.
DM: We've done it before.
Delwath: She's probably slightly scarier than the dragons we've killed before
Seeker: And she's what, 20 feet, 20, 30 feet long?
DM: I mean, who knows how good his estimates of size are
Kenzo: Fair
Wellby: We couldn't kill a dragon and fight off 100 dragonlings at the same time
Delwath: No, but I don't think we...
DM: So,
DM: um,
Delwath: do they have... Like, like I think we should
Kenzo: And they only know about Kenzo so far
DM: So-
Kenzo: So far they only know about Kenzo
DM: Yeah, they don't-
Kenzo: That's good
DM: ... they don't seem to be...
DM: Well, you don't know what the one up in the tower is doing.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah
DM: Maybe somebody's going off to report to
Kenzo: Y- if you guys had-
Wellby: Ah, they'd be going to report her
Kenzo: ... if you guys-
Wellby: If someone was off to report her, we should-
DM: Nobody's left, right?
Kenzo: Have you guys-
DM: She might be in there
Kenzo: ... have you guys had any other visitors-
DM: Ha
Kenzo: ... from the mainland?
DM: No
Wellby: Good question
Kenzo: Ever? Um-
DM: Not that I can remember
Delwath: We should get an introduction to his friend who recently went to the mainland
Delwath: Yeah. Ask if his friend likes to gamble
Kenzo: Yeah. Does your friend like to gamble,
Kenzo: that went to the mainland?
DM: Not anymore. She's got a tower.
Unknown: What does she need to gamble for?
Wellby: Where is the-
Kenzo: Can we, can we meet them?
DM: Does she like to show off her tower?
Kenzo: Yeah Could you tell us which one it is?
DM: He's kind of now annoyed that he lost and sort of is being a bit surly.
DM: Make a-
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo, Kenzo throws another dr- kinetic coin his way
DM: ... he smiles.
DM: He says, "Yeah, I'm sure she'd like to show off."
Kenzo: Yeah. Love to meet her.
DM: You wanna see it?
Kenzo: Yeah, I'd love to see it.
DM: It's a bit tricky.
Kenzo: How so?
DM: Well,
DM: there's a bad place in between.
DM: We have to go around.
Kenzo: What about this bad place?
DM: Um,
DM: you don't wanna go there.
DM: The statues are haunted by the spirits of the dead, and they'll kill you.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Kenzo: Huh. Has, has it been this way for a long time?
DM: Forever.
Kenzo: Forever? Hmm.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: Sometimes you have bad dreams if you sleep too close.
Kenzo: Huh. How close are we now?
DM: Not too close.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: It's like people choking and dying.
Kenzo: Red mist.
Delwath: Red mist.
Kenzo: And that's...
Delwath: Huh?
Seeker: Is that... The plague was created by...
Delwath: We don't know who created the plague, but it was what ended Drankor.
Delwath: Do we, do we know... Cha'mutte created the plague.
Kenzo: Cha'mutte.
Delwath: Cha'mutte created the plague to destroy Drankor.
Kenzo: Right.
Delwath: Possibly as part of ending Apollyon.
Seeker: Ends justify means in that case.
Delwath: Which they're... [laughs]
Kenzo: According to Cha'mutte.
Kenzo: Yeah. Let's go.
DM: I can take you though. Uh...
Kenzo: How far is it from here?
DM: Oh, you don't fly, do you?
Kenzo: I can fly.
Delwath: Little bit of a reveal there.
Kenzo: All right.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: It's fine.
Delwath: It is.
DM: It's not that far a walk, actually.
DM: It's just a little bit north... It's just a little bit west and then a little bit north.
Kenzo: Let's walk.
DM: Maybe, like, uh, an hour.
Kenzo: All right. I'll follow you.
DM: You wanna go now?
DM: I mean, unless you're gonna lose some more.
Kenzo: Let's go now.
DM: You got a few more of those coins?
Kenzo: Toss him another.
DM: Like two more?
Kenzo: You're killing me. Toss another one.
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: I mean, you probably should be paying me a lot more 'cause-
Kenzo: How about a little bit now and then more when we get there, huh?
Kenzo: Come on.
DM: Fair enough.
Kenzo: I'm not that...
Kenzo: Yeah, thank you.
DM: Fair enough.
Kenzo: Thank you.
Delwath: We should find out if one of them...
Delwath: So-
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: That's good
Kenzo: ... you're a lot taller than this little guy.
Kenzo: You can kind of-
DM: You're, like, staring down at him and he's like, "Hmm."
Kenzo: But-
Delwath: I mean, he's like... I like him. He's like...
Delwath: He-
Kenzo: I, um-
Delwath: He reminds me of, like, uh...
Kenzo: You know, he reminds me of, like, kids I knew growing up, you know?
Delwath: Just like-
Delwath: Are, are we assuming that one of his, one of his folk is gonna turn us to the dragon?
Kenzo: And should we try to stop it?
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Ken- Kenzo's... Look, we, we wanna get the jump.
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo's like, "Hey, and one, one more thing.
Kenzo: I know, um..."
Kenzo: What's the name of the, the person he's gonna introduce me to?
Kenzo: You, do you remember the name?
Delwath: Meg.
DM: Um, the name of the-
Kenzo: The dragon or the name of the friend?
Kenzo: The, the, the, the, the dragonet that we're gonna go see
DM: ... uh, Megren.
Kenzo: Megren.
Kenzo: Hey,
Kenzo: and, uh, just, you know, between me and you...
Kenzo: Toss a, toss like another couple coin.
Kenzo: Um, I know your boss is interested in meeting us, meeting me.
Kenzo: Meeting me, excuse me.
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: And, uh, and, uh...
Kenzo: [laughs] Little slip there.
Kenzo: And, uh, I wanna meet them too, but for now, can you just hold off on letting them know that I'm here for now until after I at le- at least Megren, at least, uh, meet Megren?
Kenzo: Yeah?
DM: Well, now it's a bargain.
DM: A few little coins isn't enough to buy my silence.
Kenzo: What else I have on me?
Wellby: Although the... Has- hasn't the word already gone up to the top of the tower, like?
Delwath: Yeah, but we're hoping that the top of the tower is under this guy's control.
Delwath: He... Did he send somebody up?
DM: I mean, you couldn't hear what they were whispering.
Delwath: Right, right.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: But he was with-
DM: But clearly the vibe was he was the sort of bossy one.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: And he was the one who insisted on gambling.
DM: You don't-
Kenzo: All right
DM: ... you just don't know whether he ordered somebody or if he-
Kenzo: So this, this is like kind of...
Kenzo: It's like, it's like his, his mini clan.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know? It's like his little-
Wellby: Yep
Kenzo: ... his little-
DM: The vibe from the gambling was definitely that.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Like, he was clearly the don.
Wellby: This is good.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah.
Wellby: All right.
Kenzo: Um, what else do I have on me?
Seeker: All right, Seeker has to walk over behind a tree.
Kenzo: I mean...
Wellby: How about some ancient elven silver coins?
Kenzo: Yeah, sure.
Kenzo: I toss him...
Kenzo: I was like, I, I show him this one.
Kenzo: You see this one?
Delwath: Do we have any gems?
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: You see, you see this one?
Kenzo: Elves.
Kenzo: Elven silver.
Kenzo: Bet you haven't seen one of these before.
DM: I don't know. There was a lot here once, but it's all gone now.
DM: I mean, a lot less.
Kenzo: I know she's got it.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, but I mean, you know.
Delwath: No, no, no, let's give him something real, something that'll get him his own tower.
Kenzo: No, I'm just buying some silence right now.
Kenzo: This is fine.
Unknown: He looks a little bit... Make a persuasion check.
Kenzo: Elves.
Unknown: He looks a little bit dubious.
Kenzo: About elven silver?
DM: No, no, like just in
DM: general.
Kenzo: [die rolling] Fuck.
Kenzo: [die rolling] I hate this die.
DM: He's just kind of standing there waiting.
Delwath: Like, what about giving him, like...
Delwath: We have tons of gems.
Delwath: If Tim's letting us just take stuff off our treasure list.
DM: I am, but it's counting as one of your retcon items.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: All right.
Delwath: Like, like we have a, we have, like, a...
Delwath: We don't, we don't have a lot of need.
Delwath: Like, five uncut gemstones from Agata's Lair.
Delwath: An amethyst, a quartz, a topaz,
Delwath: and I don't know what the other three are.
Delwath: Or, like, a jewelry, right?
Delwath: Like, we have, like, uh...
Kenzo: Kenzo pulls out, Kenzo pulls out...
Kenzo: Yeah, Kenzo pulls out-
Delwath: Ah, the golden circlet set with four green Alexandria gems from Grimbaskal's horde, worth at least 500 gold.
Kenzo: Whoa. Wow.
Delwath: Give him that.
Kenzo: Just to buy silence?
Delwath: Absolutely. It's worth it. That would get him his own tower.
Delwath: That... Look, if we give him something that if he turned it in and said he found it-
Kenzo: Yeah
Delwath: ... like, we could even, like,
Delwath: give him a story of where he f-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Like that, why would he turn us in?
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: Right?
Kenzo: Kenzo pulls that out.
Delwath: We're giving that-
DM: His eyes go...
Kenzo: You like this one, huh?
DM: What, what did Kenzo want?
Delwath: We're, we're giving him a golden circlet with four-
Kenzo: I'm not giving it yet. I'm gonna hold on.
DM: I like that one.
Kenzo: I know you do.
DM: It came from-
Delwath: Grimbaskal
DM: ... Grimbskall.
DM: No, don't tell me.
DM: He's thinking for a minute,
DM: clearly making up a story.
DM: It came from a hidden ruin that we just discovered in the jungle.
DM: That's perfect.
Kenzo: Hidden ruin in the jungle. That's what's funny, that is where you found it.
DM: That's amazing.
Delwath: Look at him.
DM: He's like clearly holding it in his hand.
Kenzo: I'm gonna give this to you after you introduce me to your friend.
Delwath: No, no, no. After he order, after the people who went up-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... have his whole clan come down here.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: So they don't fly off somewhere.
Delwath: When they're all standing around, you'll give it over.
Kenzo: Okay.
Kenzo: I just want, I just need to make sure that you're not gonna tell, uh, tell your boss.
DM: He like whistles, and like eight of them come down, and he like turns and
DM: says, "Give me a minute." And he turns, and he like gives this speech in Draconic, which of course you can't understand.
DM: He's like, "Look, guys,
DM: we've got an opportunity here."
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: I like the used car salesman vibe.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: So just be patient.
Delwath: Slightly reptilian creature.
DM: And soon we'll have
DM: better digs,
DM: and we won't-
Kenzo: Better digs. [laughs]
DM: We won't have to be constantly moving around and sharing our territory.
DM: Can you-
Delwath: Today is our day.
Delwath: [laughs]
Kenzo: Is it expe- can you tell...
Kenzo: [laughs]
Delwath: You can't, you can't check whether there's still anything up in the tower for free, can you?
DM: No. But, but you're, you do, you counted exactly how many there were.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
DM: And there's exactly that many.
Delwath: Okay. Okay.
Unknown: Yeah, that's what I was thinking. All right.
Kenzo: Nice move.
Delwath: All right.
DM: So you give it to him?
Kenzo: Do I give it, do I give it now?
Delwath: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: No, when you, when you get there.
Delwath: No, because why when we get there?
Delwath: This is not to, this is not to get to the other tower.
Delwath: This is to get them all to not go fly off and tell the dragon.
Kenzo: As soon as I give it to him I kind of lose the leverage, don't I?
Delwath: Nah, 'cause he still wants to introduce us to his friend, right?
Delwath: Why does-
DM: It's up to you. It doesn't matter which way.
Delwath: I would just give it to him now.
Kenzo: I'm gonna give it to you, I'll give it to you as soon as we get to your, the tower.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: All right?
DM: He says to his friends, "If I'm not back by tonight,
DM: one of you go tell her what happened."
Kenzo: Totally fine. Totally fine.
Kenzo: We'll be back. We'll be back for sure.
DM: And he look, he's like smiling, he's like puffing up his chest, and he goes to leave you.
DM: So what's everybody else doing? As far as you know, they've not noticed you at all.
Delwath: Where is the path?
DM: So it, it, what it, it looks like what they're gonna do actually is go, um, sort of o- off the other side of the tower and then down the hill,
DM: and then he describes the way.
DM: It's like if you keep going north that direction, you're gonna hit a plague zone.
DM: So we have to cut west through like a really ba- the edge of a really badly ruined manor, and then like basically go...
DM: It's like there's, it's like one, one manor over.
DM: You can actually see the tower that he's talking about.
DM: Um-
Delwath: I mean-
DM: ... it's only about a, it's like
DM: a mile and a half or two miles away.
Delwath: Right. Okay.
DM: But there's like a, a sort of badly ruined plague zone manor in between.
Delwath: Quick telepathic check-in, right?
Delwath: One, the more people who know about us and the more valuable we appear, the harder it is gonna keep them from telling the big boss, right?
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Big boss is gonna find out sooner or later.
Delwath: Yeah, but-
Unknown: No, but it's better for it to be just me as opposed to like the four of us-
Delwath: I think it's better
Kenzo: ... flying out.
DM: True.
Delwath: I think it's better 'cause...
Delwath: But what are we... I mean, are you gonna...
Delwath: We might have to pay off the guy we're going to visit too.
Delwath: Why would... So what if he has a tower, right?
Kenzo: Well, we're gonna learn a little bit more. Do they come back?
Kenzo: Do they bring the jade back?
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: It, it wasn't an accident, you know?
Delwath: But-
Kenzo: Let's-
DM: Can we gamble for information?
DM: This, this
Seeker: mini boss is probably also a gambler, right?
Delwath: Mini boss?
Kenzo: What mini boss?
Delwath: Well, the, the Megren.
Delwath: The, the other like-
DM: She's just like a friend.
Kenzo: She's another dragon.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: But she's the one that went to the mainland-
Delwath: We think
Kenzo: ... and basically got the jade.
Delwath: So-
DM: She... Yeah, Ghesh said she went to the ma- mainland recently and brought back something that was valuable enough.
Kenzo: That she got her own tower.
DM: She has her own tower.
Delwath: 'Cause I actually think we could get out of here without the dragon knowing about us if we carefully stay hidden, and Kenzo,
Delwath: once we talk to, we talk to the one other tower, and then
Delwath: book it away from this zone.
Wellby: I mean, I could trail Kenzo without being seen.
Delwath: All right.
Wellby: So now if I get there and back again, we got some backup.
DM: The, the, I mean-
Wellby: You guys just tuck in here
DM: ... the terrain you're going through is like...
DM: I, I think Wellby,
DM: it, it wouldn't be easy to hide, but what's your minimum DC?
DM: What's your minimum roll?
Wellby: 25.
DM: Yeah. Wellby can definitely sneak through it, but it would be a challenge for the rest.
Delwath: I mean, we could-
DM: Unless you were invisible.
Delwath: I was just gonna say, we could just invisibilize, but I just don't know if it's-
DM: Worth the risk
Delwath: ... what does it get us?
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Well, you two should go, uh, explore that scary town.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: Go fight the plague racetrack by yourself.
Kenzo: Maybe not. Maybe later.
Delwath: I think planning a rend- rendezvous spot, I don't think we all need to be...
Delwath: I think it would be good if we were close enough that if everything goes horribly wrong-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... there's like-
DM: The only downside is your tel- telepathy is gonna run out by the time Kenzo gets to the tower.
Delwath: Hmm, right.
Kenzo: So I...
Kenzo: Hmm, and then I have to be-
Delwath: Well, now
Seeker: ... in range to re-up it, right?
Delwath: Yeah, we would have no contact.
Kenzo: Well-
Delwath: But that's a little tough
Kenzo: ... we can still communicate.
Delwath: The two of you still get to communicate.
Kenzo: And then you can communicate to them.
Delwath: No. Your telepathy's only-
Wellby: It's 120 feet
Delwath: ... yeah.
Unknown: It's only 120 feet, yeah.
Delwath: Well, maybe it's worth invisibilizing then.
Kenzo: So the two of us.
Wellby: Even invisible, stealth is a challenge.
Kenzo: For some people.
Wellby: For some person.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: [laughs]
DM: If you, if you, it depends. Like-
Kenzo: I'll be really careful again
DM: ... if you, if you hang back pretty f- like if you hang back far enough, it doesn't seem like-
Delwath: I mean, invisible's pretty good from somebody 300 feet above you 'cause they won't hear anything anyway, right?
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Well...
DM: Yeah, you have to be, you have to all be within 30 feet of Seeker to renew the, right, telepathic bond.
Unknown: But I think...
Delwath: I, I'm trying to envision, so we're in a forest, they're gonna go some way.
Unknown: We could...
Delwath: I mean, how hard would it be to, like, circle around and end up 300 feet away from the tower?
DM: If you-
Unknown: Not going on the same path
DM: ... Yeah, yeah, that would be pretty easy.
Unknown: If-
DM: So, so, like-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... what, what... You can't, you can't see this because it's on the other side of the hill.
DM: So like what you see is the hill with the sort of ruined tower.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And then you can see beyond that there seems like a more intact tower.
Kenzo: Ugh.
DM: Which is like two miles away, that seems like your destination.
DM: But in between-
Unknown: There's a-
DM: ... there's like a, a area that's, there's like what used to be like a villa, not a tower-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... that had like carefully manicured, like, Italianate, like, gardens.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But it's just completely ruined.
Kenzo: Overgrown.
DM: Right? It's like overgrown and the plants...
DM: There's like s- weird statues that-
Unknown: They're, like, moving around and killing people
DM: ... they're not moving around, but they're, like, weirdly intact.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And there's-
Unknown: They have, like, grotesque looks on their faces.
DM: Yeah, exactly.
Unknown: And they will kill people if you go near them.
DM: Right. And there's, like, the hedges that have sort of gone wild.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: And it, like, very looks...
Unknown: Evil
DM: ... clearly looks dangerous to walk through.
Unknown: I think we just-
DM: But if you go around it-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... you know, you pass, you basically are passing through sort of open land.
Unknown: Right.
DM: So if you're
DM: far away so that you, even if you make noise, you won't be heard.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Stealth is easy, but if you're, if you're invisible.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But if you're not invisible, stealth would be quite challenging because, I mean, not challenging for Wellby, but for like a thief with 25.
Delwath: I mean, I'm just gonna cast invisible then.
Unknown: May as well just cast invisible.
Kenzo: And so we will catch up with them basically.
Unknown: So we'll catch up.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But you can be invisible too. There's n- I get f- three invisibilities, so.
Kenzo: All right, let's go.
Delwath: I mean, I can't do Kenzo 'cause he's too far away, but I can-
Kenzo: Well...
DM: It would be pretty weird if he turned invisible.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: How long is that last?
Unknown: An hour. [die rolling]
Kenzo: So just as, as we're, as we're walking, um,
Kenzo: uh, his name is Ghesh again?
DM: Ghesh, yeah.
Kenzo: Uh, yeah, Kenzo's just like, you know, is just like shooting the shit with him.
Kenzo: Just like, you know, it's like, "Tell me more about, like, so you got eight friends, you know?
Kenzo: Is this, or is this your clan?"
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: "Is everybody related to you, or are you, you're...
Kenzo: I mean, it seems like you're the boss here."
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: You know?
DM: Yeah, so you talk for a little bit.
DM: Like, the vibe you get is, like, I mean, there's, there's hundreds of, um,
DM: of these,
DM: of these, um... And he's, like, pretty, you know, he's pretty happy to talk to you now.
DM: He's like pretty-
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah
DM: ... pretty chill.
Kenzo: Well, Kenzo's also genuinely just like, you know-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... it's like, it's like he's, like, genuinely making some friends here.
DM: The, the vibe you get is like mo-
Kenzo: What's going on with this guy?
DM: Like, all his friends anyway, like a lot of them are kinda-
Kenzo: By the way, this is feeling pretty full on Ewok right now, but let's go.
Kenzo: Yeah, so [laughs]
DM: Yeah, so, so he said, I mean, he-
Kenzo: But it's mings, right?
DM: Yeah. The vibe you get is-
Kenzo: Yeah
Wellby: Ewoks do kill and eat humans.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: They do kill and eat humans, yeah.
Unknown: [coughs]
Kenzo: That's true.
DM: [coughs] There are, like, there's, you know, there's some that he, there's some
DM: of these dragonets that he kind of talks about as, like, the true believers that, you know, like Raegyndis has like her little army, right?
DM: Like there's some people, there's some of them who are like very-
Delwath: The first person we're going to meet is a true believer
DM: ... but most-
Kenzo: True believer of Raegyndis
DM: ... but his friends-
Unknown: Mm-hmm
DM: ... are just trying, you know, just trying to get by.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's kind of a boring place to live.
DM: They've been living here forever.
Unknown: Kenzo-
DM: The story is this is their homeland.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Whether that's true or not, nobody knows.
Unknown: Right.
DM: But, like, they claim this is where they've lived forever,
DM: and you know.
Unknown: What's the name of the dragon again?
DM: Raegyndis.
Kenzo: Raegyndis. And Raegyndis has been here forever, huh?
DM: Yeah. She, she's been here forever.
DM: We've been here forever. It's just the way it is.
Unknown: And you've never seen any other people here, huh?
DM: No.
DM: Where would they come from anyway? We gotta fly through a storm to get to the mainland.
DM: That's why not many people bother.
Unknown: So what-
DM: It's dangerous
Kenzo: ... this plague dead thing over here, so there, 'cause there used to be humans here, right?
Unknown: Oh, yeah. A long, long time ago.
DM: They're all dead.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Nobody, nobody really know, I mean...
Kenzo: So then you, you've got this one clan here.
Kenzo: Are there, like, hundreds of clans here? How many clans are around here?
DM: Uh, there's, you know,
DM: dozens. Not hundreds.
DM: There's not that many of us.
Unknown: You all gamble?
DM: Oh, we gamble.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Not everybody.
Unknown: All right.
DM: There's,
DM: you know, if you really wanna see something, you should, you should go see the games in the arena.
Unknown: There are games in the arena?
DM: Oh, yeah.
Unknown: You know-
DM: Oh, yeah
Kenzo: ... you know, I've played in games myself.
Kenzo: What kind of games? [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: I got some things right.
DM: Yeah.
DM: Ah.
Kenzo: Like, uh, like, you know, also games of luck or games of, uh-
DM: Oh, you couldn't play in these games.
Unknown: Why not?
DM: Um,
DM: you have to fly.
DM: Oh, you said you can fly. Let's race.
Unknown: Right now?
DM: Yeah, right now.
Unknown: Fuck it, let's go.
DM: One, two, three, go.
Unknown: Kenzo goes.
DM: Kenzo's like
Unknown: way, way faster than him, just totally crushes him.
Unknown: He's... I thought you said that you could race.
DM: But Kenzo can only...
DM: You're using the raven whistle, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So he flies up to you and he tries to smack the whistle out of your mouth.
DM: He's like, "You're cheating."
Unknown: I'm not cheating. I said I could fly.
Unknown: I'm flying.
DM: Okay. Well, how long can you fly?
DM: Well, you can't talk while you're-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... blowing on the whistle.
Unknown: [coughs]
Unknown: So Kenzo's like, "Ooh, ooh."
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo will, like, uh, take the whistle out of his mouth and fall for a bit to, like, say something and then put it back in his mouth.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: [coughs] Hey, that's a neat trick.
Unknown: Pretty good.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Still cheating.
Unknown: What the fuck are you talking about?
DM: Give me that and let's see if you can then fly.
Kenzo: Give me your wings and let's see if you can fly.
DM: Yeah, try and take them.
Unknown: You try and take this.
DM: Nah.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Kenzo starts doing like circles around him and he's just like, uh, like kind of taunting him, like, as he's like, you know, clearly, like got more speed.
DM: Okay.
DM: Well, it's kind of like flying tag or flying wrestling.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: I can do that.
DM: Yeah, maybe you'd be good.
Unknown: When are the games?
DM: Oh, whenever we feel like it.
Unknown: Ugh.
DM: Like I said, it's kind of boring here.
Kenzo: Huh, but when are there gonna be any games soon?
DM: You can ask around.
DM: Nobody's, nobody's organized one recently.
Unknown: [laughs] Nobody's...
Delwath: Just be careful you don't turn into like the hero that everybody's talking about.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Word'll get back. [laughs]
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: Kenzo's like, "I don't really care if we ruin the quest if I'm famous among the dragonets."
Unknown: I feel like-
DM: [laughs]
Delwath: That's more important than surprise.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Uh,
Unknown: are, are we getting close to the-
DM: Yeah, you're getting close. It's been, it's been about an hour.
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, so anyway, just to, um, on the conversation, like you, um, so you, you get the sense that like most of the...
DM: A- anyway, his friends, like he's not really friends with the True Believers.
DM: He finds them weird and off-putting, right?
Unknown: Nice. I like that.
DM: They're the ones who are-
Unknown: I like this guy. I like this guy.
DM: They're the ones who are always just like, you know,
DM: Ra'ghemdros, she's like the best.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: You know, what can we do to make her better, right?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: And most of his friends are just kind of like, you know, she's easy to manipulate.
DM: Like, you give her shiny stuff and she leaves you alone.
Unknown: She's like the Trump of dragons.
Unknown: I guess all dragons are just Trump, right?
Unknown: Ra- Ra'ghemdros?
DM: Ra'ghemdros.
Unknown: Is the dragon? Okay.
DM: You give her better shiny stuff and she rewards you, and she's like, you know, she, she never really comes here.
Unknown: All dragons are Trump.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: She w- never really, like, flies over here is your impression, but she has, you know, she's powerful enough everybody's afraid of her.
Unknown: Everybody knows she could kill you without much of a-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... doubt, so if she says this tower is yours, nobody-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... takes it. But your sense is, like, a lot of the towers, it's like constant jostling for who gets to-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... possess something. So like he's got a pretty good place right now, but there's some, like, bigger groups that are kind of eyeing it, and so he's like, "We gotta get-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... backup," right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: "We gotta get Ra'ghemdros to say this is ours and then we'll be nice and..."
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Interesting.
Unknown: Interesting.
DM: But the other thing you said, the other bits of information you learned is, like, there are literally no coins, gems, jewelry anywhere on the island.
DM: Like, they've been scouring this island for generations.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And there is not... Like, that's why people started going to the mainland.
Unknown: Ah.
Unknown: 'Cause there's like literally nothing left to find.
Wellby: Ask him what's in the towers at the center of it.
Unknown: Yeah, what's in the center of this place?
DM: Oh, in the forest?
DM: That's, that's kind of a strange vibe.
DM: There's like a monastery there.
Unknown: A monastery? Huh.
Unknown: A monastery.
DM: I mean, nothing left to find, but...
Unknown: A human monastery?
DM: Yeah, I think it's human.
Unknown: Huh.
DM: It's got like eight buildings with like stat- with like statues that look like the statues.
Delwath: Is this in the forest or on the top of a mountain?
DM: On the top. The forest we don't really go into.
Unknown: Why not?
DM: Um,
DM: sometimes if you're flying around, like, the elvish voices tell you to leave,
DM: and we don't mess with them.
Unknown: Elvish voices.
Unknown: Are they scary?
DM: I mean, yeah, when a tree says, "This is my garden.
DM: Leave," I wouldn't mess with them.
Unknown: True.
Unknown: A tree, a talking tree.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: And is Ra'ghemdros in the center of the island?
DM: No, we know-
Unknown: Or on the west
DM: ... that the tower's just to the south.
Unknown: Oh, we're on the south.
DM: That's her, that's where she lives, right over there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Is anyone in the tower, like in the monastery at the center, or is it totally empty?
Unknown: No, it's totally empty.
Seeker: Maybe Ra'ghemdros is the entity that is both guardian and, and trapped.
DM: Yeah, I think so.
Seeker: You could just free her instead of killing her.
Unknown: I mean,
Unknown: free her to go
Delwath: fly around rampaging Talgar?
Unknown: I mean-
Seeker: Well, who knows what her motivation is, really
Unknown: ... what's, what's going on on the west side?
Delwath: Kill people and take their stuff?
DM: Oh, that's the one place we don't go.
Unknown: That could just be a hobby. Who knows?
Unknown: Why does she, why don't you go there?
Wellby: [laughs] There's, there's like 11 one places that we don't go.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Feels like there's a lot of hostile stuff going on on this ta- this island.
DM: Um,
DM: it's like some ancient war.
DM: Uh, I don't really know the details, but Ra'ghemdros told us not to bother with it.
Unknown: So none of you have snuck over there?
DM: I haven't.
DM: I don't know. Maybe somebody has.
Kenzo: But you must have like, you know, searched for coin there.
DM: Um,
DM: no.
DM: So
DM: we're told
DM: that that's the one place where
DM: if we go,
DM: we might provoke real danger.
Kenzo: What does that mean, provoke real danger?
DM: I don't know. I think it's something Ra'ghemdros doesn't wanna deal with.
Unknown: Hmm.
Unknown: Ancient danger?
DM: I mean, everything's ancient here, right?
DM: Nothing's changed on the island for generations and generations and generations.
Unknown: Do you know who made the island?
DM: I think we did.
Unknown: Really?
Kenzo: You made the island? You guys made this island?
DM: Our ancestors.
Unknown: Are you magic?
DM: I mean, I can fly.
Kenzo: Yeah, you can fly, but can you like cast spells?
Kenzo: Can you do anything cool? [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, damn.
DM: Really?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: That's what you want to know?
Unknown: I'm curious.
DM: I mean, I can fight.
Unknown: Like how?
DM: A little bit.
DM: Like, you know...
DM: [whooshing]
Kenzo: [laughs] Come on. What else can you do?
Unknown: You cast any spells?
Unknown: I beat you at dice.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah. I'll give you that.
Unknown: You beat me at dice. That's fine.
Kenzo: But come on, me and you in a fight, let's be real.
Kenzo: I'm not saying that you're not, you know, you don't have any things going for you.
Kenzo: I mean, it's pretty fucking cool that you can fly.
Kenzo: I need a whistle to fly. You can just do it yourself.
Seeker: That's pretty sweet. We definitely need to, like, indenture a group of these guys to do stuff.
DM: I mean, yeah, some people can cast spells.
Kenzo: Well, if we kill- Oh, really?
DM: Huh
Seeker: ... some of your friends can cast spells. If we kill the dragon, they'll be free all of a sudden.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Kenzo: We'll just adopt them. Yeah.
Kenzo: That would work.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: We, we-
DM: A few people.
Seeker: We have little corners for 100 tiny dragons under here
DM: ... I mean, not, like, humans. Like, some humans can cast spells, right?
DM: I've heard stories anyway. I mean, if you look in the, some of the buildings, there's clearly, like, paintings of people casting spells.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Wellby: What would they do if Ra'ghemdros left?
Kenzo: I was just gonna say.
Kenzo: So, like, what if, what if Ra'ghemdros wasn't here?
DM: How is that possible? [dice rolling] I, I've never even considered the possibility.
Kenzo: Yeah, but what if she left?
DM: I mean, that's like saying what if there was no sun.
Kenzo: Yeah, well, I'm asking.
DM: I don't know. It would be different.
Kenzo: But would you, would things be better?
DM: I mean,
DM: I can't say I'm, like, fond of her.
Kenzo: That's what I'm saying. It feels like she, I mean,
Kenzo: s- j... I mean, again, I'm, I'm, I'm new here, but just feels like
Kenzo: you kinda gotta run everything by her.
Kenzo: She controls who gets what.
Kenzo: You gotta get, you know, it's like, feels like somebody like you in particular, y- you, you know, you're, you're...
DM: I, I would not mourn at her funeral.
Kenzo: That's the feeling I get. It's the feeling I get.
DM: There are some who would.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Kenzo: Hmm. Fair.
Kenzo: It's fair.
DM: So-
Kenzo: Let's get to the tower
DM: ... you get to the tower. Um, there's definitely more...
DM: So you can see as you approach, like he flies up and he, like, you know, talks to a few people and, and introdu...
DM: you know, g- gives them a little bit of a story and like, you know, don't, this is hush-hush.
DM: Like, you can tell he's trying to pr- preserve his, like-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... his edge here.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: this is a, this is, this is much nicer.
DM: So the, the tower here is, uh, this looks like a sort of traditional wizard's tower, right?
DM: Like it's-
Kenzo: Hmm
DM: ... uh, you know, 100 feet tall.
Kenzo: Wow.
DM: Um,
DM: c- basically completely int- intact except for, um, it looks like there once might have been a spire or something on the top [dice rolling] that's sort of cracked
DM: and has been crudely re-roofed, um, with just sort of s- like jumbles of stone and stuff, so there is a, is a roof.
DM: Um,
DM: the, the grounds have clearly been like recently,
DM: uh,
DM: t- sort of tended. Like, there's a few, there's, um, what look like, uh,
DM: kind of, they're not really
DM: houses, but there's like almost like lean tos, like little places where people could shelter from bad weather that have been built with like just stone that's been carried, big slabs of stone that have been carried from elsewhere,
DM: just kind of dropped and arranged.
DM: So like it almost looks like there's a tiny little, um,
DM: uh, small village around the base of this tower and the, um, like there's been...
DM: There's no trees here. This was once, there's like a, there was once like a long, um, reflecting pool that went from the base of the tower that's sort of lined with marble, which is,
DM: still has water in it and there's, like you can see a couple of, of, um, dragonets like diving and, and bathing in it.
DM: This is like much nicer than the other tower.
DM: And, um, there's probably 30 dragonets around here, um, a bigger group, and Megren flies down after,
DM: um, Ghesh introduces you.
DM: She's wearing, um, a, like a chain around her neck-
Kenzo: Hmm
DM: ... that's no- nothing like gold or metal or shiny, but it's like a, it's like a rope chain that then has this like very nice
DM: sort of polished wood, um, sort of amulet, um,
DM: that like clearly is like some, you know, some reward that was not shiny enough to be importantly kept in the hoard-
Kenzo: Hmm
DM: ... but was gifted to her.
DM: It looks old. It looks like,
DM: um, actually, it looks vaguely Elvish to your eyes.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: Um, and she's sort of a, a slightly bigger than Gresh, slightly greener than Gresh, more of like an olive color.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, and she flies down and, um,
DM: kind of gives you a little bow and, "Welcome to my humble abode."
Kenzo: Kenzo also bows and, and looks up.
Kenzo: This is more than humble. This is
Kenzo: very, very beautiful. Very nice.
DM: Well, we have been working over the past few weeks, uh, since...
DM: Well, now it is mine, in fact.
Kenzo: You are quite fortunate to live in such a place.
Kenzo: It's beautiful.
DM: I think it has potential.
Kenzo: I would say so.
Kenzo: So, uh, uh, Gresh here was sharing that you, uh, recently went to the mainland.
Kenzo: That's where I'm from.
DM: I heard.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: That was told to me.
DM: I'm quite interested, although not so much for myself.
DM: Some of my more ambitious followers are perhaps interested in their own towers.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: I don't think I'll brave the storms anymore, but others might like to know
DM: where else to look. I heard you found some
DM: golden crown in some ruins in the jungle that we were not aware of.
Kenzo: I did find something. I did find something there, and there are definitely other places to look.
DM: I'm very interested.
Delwath: Tell her you want to know the s- You're collecting stories, right?
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: Tell her you're, like, collecting the story-
Kenzo: So-
DM: ... of her amazing heroism.
Kenzo: Yeah, so, so when you, when you came to, uh, um, to the, uh, uh, to the mainland-
DM: You're... Are you carrying your staff?
Kenzo: So, yes. So I am carrying my staff, but I've been, um...
Kenzo: Like, I can carry it in a way that's, like, like, uh, I'm-
Delwath: But there's pieces of jade, I think, on the top.
DM: Is that correct?
Kenzo: There is on the top, yeah. I mean, that, that's the-
DM: There's four pieces of jade on the top.
Kenzo: Yeah. The, the top is the most, uh, the most...
Kenzo: But, but I, I've been keeping that-
DM: Okay
Kenzo: ... the, the top, like, not...
Kenzo: You know?
DM: You can probably use Dreamcraft to cause a flower to grow on the staff.
Wellby: Oh, you could.
Kenzo: Oh, perfect.
DM: That's smart.
Kenzo: That's perfect. I'll, I'll do that instead.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Yeah, so it's just, it's just a more-
Unknown: So it looks like it's, like, the flowers are-
Kenzo: It's all, it's all, uh, it's all wooden.
Kenzo: It's all... looks like just-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... a full, totally wooden staff.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: but, uh, but yeah.
Kenzo: But, uh, but Gresh says you, uh, you found some interesting things in the, uh, uh, your, your last visit.
DM: Yeah. It was quite an interesting...
DM: So I've been a few times.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, it's hard to get too far inland, 'cause there's...
DM: You know, the monkeys are annoying, and you've got to fly very high, and then all the interesting places to look have, like,
DM: bothersome people living in them.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: But I found this cave that seemed empty.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: I flew around a little bit, and like, mostly it was boring stuff.
DM: It was, like, dried mango or garbage like that.
DM: Nobody would care about that here.
DM: Um, food's never really a problem, right?
DM: Um,
DM: what do they eat?
Kenzo: Probably fish.
DM: Hmm. Or do they just-
Wellby: Or the circles
DM: ... sit down on one of the arcane circles?
Unknown: Oh, right. Of course. [laughs]
DM: Oh. Uh, but there was this
DM: big green gem that was just sitting there.
DM: Like, whoever found it didn't even know what they had found.
DM: Why would you just leave that sitting out and not protect it or anything?
DM: I mean, she holds up her hand.
DM: It was, like, the size of my claw, just like the size of all the other dragons.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: But by the way, um, the, the wood, you know, that's just how it always looks.
Kenzo: The staff normally does not look like it's got, like-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Kenzo: ... four giant huge pieces of j-
DM: So it's... Right
Kenzo: ... it, it's, it's got, you know, in its everyday use, it is-
DM: Right. Well, there's nothing about Dreamcraft that says when you cause something to bloom, the bloom dies.
Kenzo: Right. Right.
DM: So you just, like, make... This is, like, what the...
DM: You know, remember when you were on the ship sailing to Chardin and the halfling druid was, like, touched your staff and made, like, something bloom from it?
Kenzo: Cool.
DM: Like, Kenzo wants to do this, so Kenzo learned how to do that, so now you can, like, summon forth.
Kenzo: That's great.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: But that way it's just not-
DM: Yeah, yeah
Unknown: ... it's not so conspicuous. Yeah.
DM: Uh,
DM: so
DM: I grabbed it.
DM: Who wouldn't, right? I'm, I know, I know what side of the...
DM: what side of... Well, she, uh, what's...
DM: Whatever the dragonet metaphor for, like, you know, which is the right side up.
DM: Like, what side of the
DM: bread is buttered or whatever the metaphor is, but not bread and butter, 'cause they would kill each other.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: You know, I, I know who's in charge, right?
DM: But I got a pretty good trade for it.
DM: I don't think Regendros has found new gemstones in a while.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Um, in this area when we were in the jungle, uh, just like, uh, so 'cause again, I think that last time I was, I was, like, checked out.
Kenzo: Are there... Were there other, like, kind of interesting...
Kenzo: Did we get anything there?
Wellby: No.
DM: You didn't really explore.
Kenzo: We didn't explore. Okay.
DM: You did hear that there were other...
DM: Like, further to the west, there was, like, other territory from the Awaken jungle people that
DM: might have things.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
DM: But you were pretty focused on just tracking the jade.
Kenzo: Right, right, right.
DM: You explored the caves, but-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah
DM: ... she obviously had been to those caves.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, I assume, by the way, the jade, if Kenzo senses the direction, it's pointing to The Scar.
DM: Oh, yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, this is pretty... I mean, now I think it's pretty much just gonna-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... point to The Scar anyway.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: So probably we should regroup, maybe try and get out of there pretty soon.
Wellby: Well, I, I wonder if there's anything else... Like, when,
Wellby: when this person took the jade, they went to Regendros-
Kenzo: Yeah
Wellby: ... to steal it. Like, what-
Wellby: ... what was that like? How did they get there?
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Wait, what is-
Wellby: Like, pri- prying... Like, what's the approach?
Wellby: What's the lair like? Can we sneak in and kill her in her sleep?
Kenzo: [laughs] Yeah.
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Wellby: But without making it sound like an-
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: So, so-
Seeker: You could, you could appeal to the vanity part.
Kenzo: Right.
DM: Like, oh, this tower's pretty cool.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: But what does Regendros have?
Wellby: Yeah, exactly.
Seeker: Like, it's like, must be, must be a little nicer, right?
Kenzo: Yeah. So Regendros must have been pretty happy about this, that, uh, that, that jewel, huh?
DM: Oh, yeah. For sure.
DM: I mean,
DM: she, like, waves her wings around.
Kenzo: I mean, this is pretty nice here, but Regendros' place,
Kenzo: it's gotta be a little bit nicer, right?
DM: Oh, no, it's way worse.
Kenzo: It's way worse?
DM: I mean, she lives, like, underneath a...
DM: What is it?
DM: A... She, she points to the pool.
DM: It's like that, but bigger. But you have to, like, swim.
DM: You gotta, like, get her
DM: guards to show you. You swim down, and then it's, like, this nasty, swampy, acidic mess of a cave.
DM: Like, ugh.
Kenzo: Wow, she-
DM: This is way prettier.
Kenzo: Why would she stay down there?
Wellby: Hmm.
DM: Well.
Kenzo: You s- But she's got... You said that, uh, you can't just fly there yourself.
Kenzo: You said there are people that have to let you in.
DM: Well, I don't know how you would get...
DM: I don't know. Maybe you could.
DM: I wouldn't wanna go into her lair unannounced.
DM: [coughs]
Kenzo: When, when does she come out?
Wellby: Yeah, why not?
DM: 'Cause she'd kill me.
DM: What, are you crazy?
Kenzo: You said, you s- But there are a bunch of, uh, people that need to let, that need, would need to let you in, that need to let you in?
DM: So when I went there, I did the thing that any sensible person would do.
DM: I talked to her guards that were perched on the columns around this, like, baths or something, and they were like,
Unknown: "Br, br, br, I'll talk to her.
DM: Yeah, okay. You can come."
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: "That's good."
DM: And then they, like, said, "Okay, follow me."
DM: And then we dove down beneath the surface of this water, and I have to hold my breath, and then suddenly we were in a- ...
DM: cavern dripping acid and we flew over an acid lake and passed some like nasty, dark, shadowy tendrils of gooey evil.
DM: And then
DM: her lair is like this horrific mass of g- acidic geysers that she, like, drinks from for no reason.
Kenzo: We need to get her out of there.
Unknown: We do.
Kenzo: We need to fight her not in there.
Delwath: There's... She probably can't leave.
Kenzo: We gotta get her out.
Unknown: That's the prison guard.
DM: [gasps]
Kenzo: Oh.
Seeker: Oh. Uh, or, well, just a- let's find out.
DM: When does she come out? But when I gave it to her, she did like seem pretty happy.
Unknown: So she never comes out of there?
DM: [sucks teeth] I don't know.
Kenzo: Has anybody ever seen her not in there?
DM: Yeah, once.
DM: Well, I didn't see it.
DM: Friend of a friend told me a story.
Kenzo: What's the story? How'd she get out of there?
DM: Well [laughs] this is a good story.
Kenzo: Huh. Well, anyway.
DM: This just shows why you shouldn't mess with Regemdros.
Kenzo: Well, let's hear. I'm curious.
DM: This is why I try and stay on her good side.
Kenzo: I mean, I'm curious.
DM: Look how she rewards me.
Kenzo: I'm curious. Okay, go ahead.
DM: These aren't my friends, just so you know.
Kenzo: Okay, that's fine.
DM: I want to make it clear, like, like,
DM: you know, like-
Kenzo: Hey, it doesn't, it, this does not [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: This does not in any way reflect upon your reputation or my perception of you.
Kenzo: Put it that way.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Okay, so
DM: a f- a friend of mine.
Kenzo: Not you. A friend of yours.
DM: Not me.
Kenzo: Yeah, a friend.
DM: A friend of mine.
Wellby: Not a friend friend, but a friend.
DM: Yeah. Yeah, sort of a friend.
DM: Um,
DM: you know,
DM: his, his name was, uh [clears throat]...
Kenzo: Henry. [laughs]
Unknown: That's, no, that's [laughs] a good one.
DM: Um,
DM: um, his name was Zadar.
DM: [clears throat] Uh,
DM: so he told me a story once.
DM: I, I, I, I...
DM: Ghesh says you're collecting stories, right?
DM: Here's a, here's a good one.
Kenzo: I, I'm, I'm definitely, uh, I'm, I'm loving these stories.
Kenzo: And by the way, by the way, too, you know, Kenza is like, kind of is like, "I, I know, I know Ghesh doesn't have a very high opinion of you," but, um, like as, as we've been talking he's been like kind of whittling like a little, a little,
Kenzo: you know.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: And he makes like a really like kind of pretty, pretty like nice looking like [clears throat] thing of Ghesh and is like [clears throat], you know, "I, I'm really good at, uh, translating your stories into these, these little..."
DM: Yeah, that's not bad. I like that.
Kenzo: I know, I know. You know, it's just-
DM: That's a good material to work with there
Kenzo: ... yeah. And he just, he just tosses that to Ghesh.
Kenzo: Says, "This one, that one's for you."
Unknown: Oh, maybe... Can I get one?
Kenzo: Oh, duh, of course. I'll make you one.
Kenzo: Just keep talking. I'll make one right now.
DM: So, so here's the story that Zadar told me.
DM: Zadar says
DM: there were some, some folks who had a plan.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Or-
Unknown: A concept
DM: ... maybe just a concept.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: And they said, and I, this is, I know this isn't true, but they believe
DM: that maybe
DM: there was something more than life under Regemdros and there were stories of an elder who had tales
DM: of the outside world from before Regemdros arrived.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: And so they said, "Let's go find him."
Kenzo: Hmm. Let's go find.
Unknown: Wait.
Kenzo: Find the elder.
Unknown: There.
DM: Go find the elder.
DM: And they needed supplies.
DM: I don't know why. That part isn't clear.
DM: But they were camped,
DM: uh,
DM: heading towards the forest,
DM: and somehow word got out that they were going to find this rumored elder who clearly doesn't exist.
DM: And Regemdros came,
DM: flew over their camp and burned them all to a crisp and now all that's left is a pool of acid where they used to be, and you can go visit that pool, so I know at least
DM: that part's true.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: I think they were actually trying to escape the island.
DM: I think they were gathering supplies to escape, like go make a living somewhere else in the jungle.
Unknown: Huh.
DM: And they got turned into a pool of acid.
DM: So unless there's another way that pools of acid can just appear,
DM: my... I have never seen it, 'cause I'm like, "Why waste my time going to look at pools of acid?"
DM: But my friend Zadar, he says he's seen the pool of acid and the story is.
Kenzo: Huh.
Kenzo: So this elder that they were trying to go visit, is the elder on the island?
Unknown: We need to bring this to Dragonite Rebellion.
Kenzo: Huh? What's that?
Unknown: Sorry. Dragonite Rebellion.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: We, we need to like get it all together.
DM: Well, the elder doesn't exist, clearly.
Kenzo: But why, why do you say that clearly?
DM: Well, 'cause Regemdros would've killed him.
Kenzo: Hmm. Huh.
DM: That's why I think they were actually fleeing, but the story they told was they were going to find an elder who lives with the elves.
Kenzo: Lives with the elves where?
DM: Well, you know those elves that talk in the forest.
Kenzo: Right, right, yeah, yeah.
DM: Uh-huh.
Kenzo: I was hearing about that, the elves talking in the forest.
Kenzo: Uh, so
Kenzo: this happened when?
DM: Oh, this was years ago.
Kenzo: But, but your, but in your lifetime?
DM: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: Oh, so, okay. So Regemdros has left, left the lair.
Kenzo: I, I'm... All I'm saying is you all are rightfully scared.
Kenzo: I mean, it sounds like a big bla- black acid dragon.
Kenzo: But also if he comes out once every 20 years, like are you really, you know?
Kenzo: It's like, like what's the, you know, why, you know?
Kenzo: It's like,
Kenzo: it's kind of-
DM: I, you know-
Kenzo: It feels more like the threat of him doing, of them doing something, her doing something.
DM: But if you want to take a risk, you can take risks.
DM: I don't want to be turned into a pool of acid.
Kenzo: I'm just saying if in your entire lifetime she's only come out once, you know?
Unknown: Just, you know, just, just putting it out there.
Kenzo: Putting it out there. I mean, she sounds scary.
Kenzo: Don't get me wrong. She sounds scary.
DM: Hey, you do you.
Kenzo: I, and I will.
Kenzo: I will. You know, I'm a human. I'll, we do human things.
Kenzo: Um- Anything else we wanna learn?
Delwath: I'm not... I think we should, we need to regroup before we do anything
Kenzo: Hey, this, uh, this, uh, um, the, the friend of yours that, uh, was looking for the elder, are they around?
DM: Zadar?
Kenzo: Zadar, yeah.
DM: Oh, he wasn't looking for the elder.
Kenzo: But Zadar was-
DM: He would never do that
Kenzo: ... he would never do that, but his friend, Zadar's friend.
DM: He, he visited the acid pool and the rumor is that people who used to be people before they were turned into acid were trying to find this elder.
DM: But I think that was a smoke screen.
DM: They're actually trying to escape the island.
Kenzo: Anybody else know more about this elder?
Kenzo: Zadar? Would Zadar?
DM: I don't think Zadar would.
DM: I mean,
DM: seems kind of risky to try and learn something about...
DM: Information is risky.
Kenzo: I think we... He lives with the, he lives with the elves in the forest
Delwath: Back out, like-
Kenzo: Okay. All right
Delwath: ... I think it's better to-
Kenzo: All right
Delwath: ... we could probably learn more from the Dragonets, but only at the cost of absolutely certainly being told about to the dragon.
Delwath: I think we get out of here.
Kenzo: Yeah. Kenzo, uh, you know, Kenzo continues to chat with them for a little bit.
Kenzo: Tells them a little bit about, you know,
Kenzo: life on the mainland.
DM: Yeah, yeah
Kenzo: ... and, uh, gives a se- you know, and, and now, you know, pulls out this, this thing that, that he found, you know?
DM: Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Kenzo: And kinda gives, gives, uh, Gresh?
DM: Gresh, yeah
Kenzo: ... a, a l- a little wink, you know.
Kenzo: Yeah, 'cause when I found this in that cave, uh, you know, there's definitely more out there.
Kenzo: There's for sure more human treasure and even some elvish treasure as well.
Kenzo: And, you know, Kenza shows one of the, the elvish coins that he has.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: And, and just, you know, uh, for gratitude gives a, gives an elvish coin to the, uh, um-
Delwath: Magrin
Kenzo: ... to Magrin and then also, you know, ca- carves like a really beautiful-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... you know, kind of little statuette for, for...
Kenzo: And, uh, and says to, you know, Gresh, "Well,
Kenzo: listen, this has been great.
Kenzo: I wanna, I'm gonna come back and visit you.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: but, you know, this, a deal's a deal.
Kenzo: This, so this is for you." And kinda, you know.
DM: Um, Gresh is like, smiles pretty happy.
DM: Uh, Magrin actually flips the coin to him and says, "I don't need to go
DM: talk to Ra'ghemdros anymore.
DM: I'm happy to stay away from her," and like just is like, "Take this as part of your loot that you're trading for your tower."
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: They, they definitely seem to be friends and she's, she's happy about him-
Kenzo: Yeah
Unknown: ... getting, getting the native territory.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Yeah. Cool, cool.
Kenzo: Yeah. So, so Kenzo, uh, yeah.
Kenzo: Kenz- Kenzo's-
DM: But she keeps the statue.
Kenzo: Of course.
DM: The little-
Kenzo: Of course
DM: ... compliment.
Kenzo: Yeah. That's great. Cool.
Kenzo: Nice. We got some goodwill amongst some, uh,
Kenzo: some, some
DM: And they just let you know, they don't really care what you do.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
DM: They don't seem interested. She does definitely doesn't s- I mean, she is friends with Gresh.
DM: She's not gonna mess up his-
Kenzo: Right, right, right
DM: ... deal.
Kenzo: Perfect. All right.
Kenzo: Kenzo reunites with the party,
Kenzo: now with a few like, uh, kind of Dragonet, uh, coins to, to show for it.
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: So the acid dragon.
Delwath: Yeah. I, I think it's possible that story is fake.
Kenzo: Which, uh, which-
Delwath: There's plenty of ways in which a dragon could potentially cause acid to appear far away via magic or whatever, without necessarily being able to
Delwath: escape.
Kenzo: Yeah, so you think the acid dr- the dragon's trapped still?
Seeker: But also crucially, it seems very likely that the jade is in the possession-
Delwath: We're sure of that. I mean, yes. The jade-
Unknown: The jade is in that dragon
DM: The jade is definitely in the possession of the dragon.
Delwath: Yes.
DM: She, Magrin handed the jade to-
Delwath: Yes, to the dragon
Seeker: So another question is can you, can one sneak into a dragon's lair and...
Delwath: So I think there's four things we could do.
Delwath: We could sneak into the dragon lair and try and steal the jade.
Delwath: We could go kill the dragon.
Delwath: We could just pile up on a whole bunch of gems and go trade, see if the dragon would trade a whole bunch of gems for our jade.
Unknown: Interesting.
Delwath: Right? The tricky bit on that is just why would the dragon not just kill us and take the gems and not have to give anything up?
Delwath: But if we could have a plausible story, that would make it a little, uh, hard to achieve.
Seeker: What if, what if we insist on making the trade, we build up our reputation as having good shit with the Dragonets and insist on the trade
Unknown: at her entrance?
Kenzo: Ah.
Wellby: We could send Gresh.
Delwath: We... Actually, so if we wanted to do that-
Wellby: Yeah. He doesn't really go in like that
Delwath: ... the thing to do would be actually build a r- it would be to go actually spread a m- we...
Delwath: So I don't know if I wanna do that 'cause it seems like we should just kill her, but...
Seeker: Well, it's gonna end up chaotically resulting in a combat, but we want the combat to happen where in, you know, on our terms.
Kenzo: We do not want the combat in her fucking lair.
Delwath: That's what I'm saying.
Kenzo: I do not want to go fight her in her fucking acid lair.
Delwath: But I, I think-
Seeker: We're just not willing to go underground.
Delwath: I-
Unknown: We need some story about that
Delwath: ... I, I don't think-
Kenzo: That we can trade with her if she, if she'll come out and meet us
Unknown: ... yeah, like we just can't swim.
Delwath: Well,
Delwath: none of those strike me as plausible in the sense that
Delwath: why would she...
Kenzo: What if, what if I show her that we've got four more of those g- like I've c- c- carrying a fucking staff that's got four more of these things.
Delwath: But, but, and then for what end?
Kenzo: To get her out of the cave. We're gonna have to kill her.
Delwath: Why, why would she come out of the cave?
Kenzo: To come and get the four gems.
Delwath: Why wouldn't she just send 100 Dragonet...
Delwath: I mean, we don't know what, what power she has, right?
Delwath: Maybe she can turn any spot on the island to acid.
Unknown: I will address that. [laughs]
Delwath: Right? So like maybe what happens is she just starts, acid pools just start popping up everywhere we walk.
Unknown: I think you're being paranoid though, like...
Unknown: Do you have a way to like open a hole into the cave?
Delwath: Uh, I, I think-
Kenzo: Teleport. Can we just teleport directly there?
Seeker: We could attempt to. Failures are, are bad.
Delwath: I mean, we could dimension door.
Seeker: Oh, I could, I could possibly clairvoyance into the, into the lair and then teleport us in.
Unknown: Is that true?
Delwath: Or we could dimension door.
Unknown: Ye- yes.
Seeker: Still we'd wanna know exactly where to, where we-
Delwath: I mean, we could clairvoyance
Unknown: ... yeah, yeah.
Wellby: Clairvoyance the treasure hoard, dimension door the jade.
Delwath: I mean, in theory you could just dimension door, dimension door.
Delwath: You could just do a theft, but I don't think we'd-
DM: Just keep in mind exactly how
DM: Magrin described it. You swim down to the bottom of the pool,
Unknown: and then you suddenly appear in an acid pool.
Delwath: Oh, it, it could be, uh, extra planar.
DM: Oh.
Delwath: Oh, that's true. It could be extra planar.
Seeker: Yeah, you didn't... There was no surfacing from the pool.
Unknown: It was-
DM: You didn't surface from the pool anywhere.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You swim down, and then suddenly you're in a tunnel.
Unknown: So it's probably-
Delwath: Right. It was probably extraplanar in some fashion.
Unknown: Fuck me.
Delwath: See-
Kenzo: Yeah, but there are also these, um, tendrils of death.
Delwath: Yes.
Unknown: What you go... How'd you describe it?
Delwath: Evil tendrils of-
Unknown: Evil shadows.
Delwath: Yeah. So,
Delwath: so
Delwath: I think there's three strategies to approach with the dra- I mean, the fourth thing that we could do is ignore the dragon for right now and go find D- Dimitar.
Unknown: Uh, the idea being that's the elder.
Unknown: But what we need is the jade.
Delwath: But the idea being maybe we'd learn more.
Unknown: But going into the Elvish-
Delwath: Yeah
Unknown: ... um, forest,
Kenzo: that feels like a potentially-
Delwath: So
Delwath: it, it-
Unknown: ... good thing to do.
Delwath: Right. It, it feels like we either...
Delwath: The first question is, do we go into the forest and investigate the monastery in the forest first
Delwath: to try and get more in...
Delwath: Like, this was clearly paid off in terms of getting information.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Right? That could give us more information.
Unknown: But we know where the jade is.
Delwath: Right. Or we just go straight for the jade right now, and if we're going straight for the jade right now, it's either subterfuge, violence, or t- or trading.
Delwath: Right? So if we're going with subterfuge, that's probably we need to think of some complicated plan.
Kenzo: Outside of the game, it would be cool just to, uh, kill the dragon and then talk to Dimitar at the end.
Delwath: You think other way?
Unknown: A bit.
Delwath: I think killing the dragon-
Seeker: We were joking about fomenting rebellion, but I think actually the combination of offering to trade with the dragon and then, like, kind of secretly getting all of the dragonets
Seeker: on our side with respects to their freedom,
Unknown: uh-
Kenzo: But they're the true believers' dragonets.
Delwath: There are true believers.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: But it's most of them, basically.
DM: Yeah. So there's a fraction that are true believers, but-
Kenzo: We happen to get to talk to, like, the kind of, you know, the, the Jersey Shore dragonets.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: But-
DM: Well, your sense... So, so to be fair, your sense from the...
DM: Now whether the, whether Ghesh is giving you an accurate picture or not is unclear, but your sense is that
DM: at least in the town, most, most of the dragonets that sort of live in these surviving non-plague ruins pretty much seem to just want Ragabash to leave them alone, right?
DM: The true believers are the ones who, like, hang around her lair.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Right?
Unknown: And are powered.
DM: Now, maybe there's other true believers and he's just not friends with them, right?
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: But it didn't seem like it was, like, 50% of the dragonets were true believers.
Delwath: Right.
DM: It was definitely not that high.
Delwath: Oh, not, not that high.
Unknown: Not 50%.
Delwath: Yeah. Mostly not.
DM: Whether it's like, whether it's like 10% or 25% or something like that, it's hard to tell.
Delwath: But-
DM: But, like, clearly it's not like there's constant wars between the true believers-
Delwath: Right
DM: ... and the non-true believers on the-
Delwath: The, the problem is any th...
Delwath: Like, if we tried to foment a rebellion, that might work, but for what?
Delwath: But in it, they're greedy enough that inevitably if 500 dragonets knew about us, why wouldn't somebody go, "Somebody's gonna go tell the dragon about it."
Kenzo: You know, the, the, the only useful thing about the any, quote-unquote, "rebellion" would be if we didn't want to have to fight the true believers and we had a bunch of other dragonets to, like, kind of, you know, whatever, dragonets civil war
Unknown: so that we didn't have to deal with them.
Delwath: Oh.
Unknown: You know?
Seeker: Just get them to fight each other while we're fighting the dragon.
Unknown: Yeah. Exactly.
Delwath: Yeah.
Unknown: Exactly. Just so we don't have to deal with them in return.
Seeker: I mean, that's actually quite useful.
Kenzo: That's true. Which is not nothing.
Delwath: But it... I mean, but are we...
Delwath: Are we...
Delwath: So we could attempt-
Kenzo: Hold on. One other key critical thing.
Kenzo: If we believe that the acid dragon is trapped, what is trapping it?
Kenzo: Like, is it like... Is there an active, like, thing or is it just like a, like a cave?
Delwath: This is why I think the immediate next thing to do is go into the forest.
Unknown: Talk to... Yeah. We'll learn a little bit more about the trapping mechanism.
Delwath: Right. Learn more 'cause I, I think it's very hard to know whether subterfuge is even possible.
Unknown: Mm.
Delwath: Like, if you think about it, basically there's three ways we could get the jade, right?
Delwath: Violence, subterfuge, or a bargain, but it's very hard to know whether subterfuge is possible, and it's hard to make the best possible plan for violence or a bargain
Delwath: because we don't know-
Kenzo: Actually, before I leave, ask the dragonets, like-
Delwath: Fair
Unknown: ... do you think she would trade?
DM: I mean, yeah, 100%, the whole vibe is she definitely would.
Unknown: I mean-
Unknown: No, no, the, the dragon would trade.
Delwath: Ragabash.
DM: Yeah. I mean, that's like the whole economy of the island is trading things to her for her favor.
Delwath: Right.
DM: Now, whether she'd give up part of her hoard, it would have to be something pretty valuable, right?
DM: Like, she wouldn't, she wouldn't give an even trade for something in her hoard.
Delwath: Of course. Of course.
Unknown: It would have to be something she wants-
Delwath: Of course
Unknown: ... really badly.
Delwath: Of course.
Unknown: So we can-
Unknown: But 100%, like, definitely.
Seeker: We could say we have, like, several more pieces of jade, but we just want the one she has.
Unknown: We're not gonna give anything to her.
Delwath: Well, but I think, I actually think if we're doing trade, we should do it honestly.
Delwath: We should not attempt, right?
Unknown: The, the-
Unknown: We actually trade something to her?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: The value, the, like-
Unknown: What do we have that we could trade her?
DM: The, like... You know, your sense is, like, it'd have to be at least, like, 10 to one.
Unknown: Yeah. Totally. Of course.
Unknown: But 10 to one might not-
Kenzo: But she doesn't know that, that this is more than just jade, right?
Unknown: I mean, she might know that it's magic jade.
Unknown: She probably knows it's magical.
Unknown: Yeah. But she doesn't know that it's, like-
Unknown: But-
Unknown: ... you know
Delwath: ... if we were going to do a trade, the thing to do would be to actually go in amongst the dragonets and start offering out little bits of treasure for others of them, so we get a rumor of people who have a ton of stuff.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Delwath: And then-
Unknown: That's already happening.
Kenzo: No, but the question is, do we have actually, do we actually have something that we could trade that the dragon would even care about?
Delwath: I mean, we'd have to poke around and see what we have, but we either would tr...
Delwath: I mean, in theory, we could trade a pretty significant chunk of wealth.
Delwath: We have lots of gems,
Delwath: right?
Unknown: That is true.
Delwath: Or we could try and think, do we have magic we don't actually need anymore?
Unknown: Magic items.
Delwath: Right? Like-
DM: Just keep in mind, if you're offering to trade something that you have on you, there is always the, why doesn't she just kill you and take it?
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. No, we'd have to have some plan for-
Kenzo: But also is, if she's trapped, right?
Unknown: I keep going back to that whole bit.
Delwath: But it also goes back to kill us and take it, fine.
Delwath: Like, but if-
Kenzo: We want that. If she can leave the lair and come out and try to kill us, fucking come kill us and take it.
Delwath: If, if-
Kenzo: You know? That's the other thing we could do is just flaunt around and be like, "Hey, we're a bunch of dudes with, uh, all this fucking treasure, all this stuff.
Unknown: Dragon, come get us."
Delwath: But we have to be careful about her sending 50 or 100 dragonets.
Seeker: That, that's why that's the two-part strategy.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: We flaunt our wealth.
Seeker: I think it's Dragonets on our side, or at least some of them.
Kenzo: Yeah
Delwath: But I, but I think that plan works better if we're honestly willing to trade if she takes it, with a backup plan of basically trying to negotiate.
Delwath: I mean, just being upfront with her.
Delwath: Like, "Okay, we're willing to trade, but we don't wanna come in your lair and just get killed, so
Delwath: what do you, what is your plan here?"
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: And if we come across scary enough that she thinks that out of her lair it might even be a fair fight...
Delwath: I mean, the way to do it would make her think that if she came after us out of her lair, she would feel like it's an even fight, and she doesn't wanna take a 50/50 shot at dying.
Kenzo: Totally.
Delwath: Right?
Delwath: So I mean-
Kenzo: Well, we... Uh, so far, I mean, the, uh, the only thing I've shown is like I've got a whistle and I can fly around.
Delwath: Yeah, yeah. No, we haven't-
Kenzo: That's, uh, there's no... And it's only game.
Delwath: The, the strategy would be like-
Kenzo: It's a deep cut
Delwath: ... go fight in the coliseum and defeat 20 of the Dragonet.
Delwath: Like, just we'd have to like build ourselves up as uber powerful.
Kenzo: No, but-
Delwath: Tons of stuff
Kenzo: ... no, no, we don't wanna be uber powerful.
Kenzo: We just wanna have tons of stuff.
Delwath: No, we do wanna be uber powerful because we want her to be scared.
Kenzo: The drag- the dragon?
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: Why do we want her to be scared? We want her to feel confident-
DM: Yeah, no, in the-
Kenzo: ... so that she'll leave her lair.
DM: To think she could just kill us with a touch.
Kenzo: To think that she could just wipe us out.
Kenzo: Like, oh, these like fucking-
Delwath: But why would she leave her lair if she thought that?
Kenzo: This is the whole like, oh, like if anything you have, like she'll just take it.
DM: But you're forgetting about the Dragonets.
DM: If she thinks the Dragonets can just kill you,
DM: why wouldn't she just send Dragonets after you?
Delwath: Why wouldn't she send henchmen after us?
Kenzo: Mm. Yeah.
Delwath: Right?
Kenzo: Uh.
Delwath: I mean, we could maybe kill her hench...
Delwath: Like, but
Kenzo: But we can kill hundreds of Dragonets.
DM: Can we?
Kenzo: I think so.
Kenzo: Five of them, yeah.
Delwath: I mean, I don't know. They were-
Kenzo: Or hundreds at once might be tough
DM: ... almost 10. 10, maybe But there probably aren't...
DM: I mean, who knows? Like there's, if there's 500 of them,
DM: yeah, 100 all at once would be difficult.
Delwath: 100 at once we would depend-
Kenzo: We'd want that to-
Delwath: ... fundamentally on strong positioning so that they could not get to us
Kenzo: Or like fireball
DM: And preparation
Kenzo: To guide me to one of the necks with fireballs
Wellby: I wonder if she would want the, um...
Wellby: What's the f- do we have any freak bottle?
Wellby: What's the thing?
Delwath: Oh, yeah.
Wellby: That potentially we have a wish.
Delwath: Yeah.
Wellby: I mean-
Delwath: Like-
Wellby: ... if a, if that's the sort of thing that could get her undrapped, that could be a really powerful incentive
Delwath: Trade
Kenzo: Oh, as a trade?
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: Right.
Delwath: I just-
Wellby: Ooh
Kenzo: Oh
Wellby: ... like that could get her off the island.
Delwath: Right
Wellby: ... potentially.
Kenzo: Maybe
Delwath: I, I just think we... If we're trying to negotiate with her, I think it's better to negotiate with...
Delwath: 'Cause why wouldn't she just be like, "Come to my lair," and then decide to kill us?
Delwath: Which is fine at some level if we decide we're just gonna fight her in her lair,
Delwath: right?
Kenzo: Okay.
Wellby: I don't wanna fight her in her lair.
Kenzo: Yeah. We do not wanna fight her... In the acid lair, that sounds so gnarly.
Kenzo: That sounds just like horrible.
DM: Ooh, that's terrible.
Delwath: This is like the opposite of the last dragon fight.
Kenzo: It's the worst.
Delwath: I was like, "We need a way to get him out of the lair," and all three of you were like, "No, no, no, we're just gonna fight in the lair."
Delwath: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, we'll be fine with that one.
DM: But in the last dragon fight you didn't have easy ways to fly.
Delwath: True.
DM: The problem with fighting a dragon out of the lair is that they can just fly above you-
Delwath: Yeah
DM: ... and breathe on you from above.
Delwath: Yep. We did.
DM: You're just dead.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: Right.
DM: You have to be able to fly.
Delwath: True. But we can fly pretty well.
DM: But you have easy... You all have easy ways to fly, so...
Kenzo: All right. So, um, but do we s- do we now still go and talk to the elves to learn more about like-
Delwath: I think so.
Kenzo: I think so too, right?
Delwath: Yeah. I think the next move-
Kenzo: 'Cause, 'cause now there's like we gotta figure out like what the fuck is going on.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: Like is it trapped? Is it...
Kenzo: 'Cause that's the other thing too. It's like if it's just trapped and it's sort of like Apollyon and it's just that's it, then okay.
Kenzo: But if there's like an active entity that is like trapping the more powerful-
Wellby: Right
Kenzo: ... like dragon, or-
Wellby: If we're trying to lure her out and we think the incentive is getting her freed, we need to understand more about what's trapping her.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right. Let's go talk to the elves.
Delwath: And we're not even sure she can leave her lair, right?
Kenzo: Right. Exactly. I mean, that was a...
Kenzo: Nobody's seen her, right?
Delwath: Right.
Kenzo: So I double-check with all of them. Has anybody ever seen her outside of the lair?
Delwath: N- no. 'Cause like if she could easily leave her lair, why wouldn't she just like overfly occasionally to scare them, right?
Seeker: Yeah. How does she control them in the first place if she's never coming out?
Delwath: Well, she has this acid pools appearing.
Delwath: She did something to do something to make people at least think that there's an acid pool, right?
Seeker: But is that a thing? I'm checking Delwath's paranoia here.
Seeker: Is that a thing, like remote acid pools?
DM: I mean,
DM: ancient dragons can have all sorts of magic.
DM: Yeah, they could do a, pretty much anything.
Kenzo: All right. It's a thing. Damn.
DM: For all you know, she can scry anywhere on the island immediately without having to expend any energy.
Kenzo: Why would you say that, Delwath?
Wellby: I spend the ever spinning top.
Wellby: Are we being scried right now? [laughs]
Kenzo: Okay.
Delwath: [laughs] Oh, actually, my other idea was to attempt to scry her.
Kenzo: Feels like a... I mean...
Wellby: If she's on a different plane, is that a problem?
Delwath: Scry?
Delwath: I don't remember.
DM: It is for teleport. I don't know if it is for scry.
Delwath: I don't remember if scry works over, across planes.
Wellby: Well, it is for teleport.
Delwath: Um, I mean, I, she'd have a decent chance at making the save 'cause she'd be plus five, but I only know of her secondhand.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: So where are you heading?
Delwath: Into the forest.
Kenzo: Forest. Yeah.
DM: So basically sort of... So if you head sort of-
Delwath: Same plan
DM: ... due west
DM: from where you are,
DM: um, you're talking about like a t-
DM: 10-ish mile walk to the edge of the forest.
Kenzo: You guys wanna take a quick like, uh, 10 minute break or something like that?
Kenzo: A little stretch break.
Delwath: Yeah.
DM: Yeah, sure.
Kenzo: I think this is a good, good spot.
Kenzo: We've been playing for two hours.
NOTE Recording part 2: Session-108-Chunk-02.identified-v2.vtt
Synthetic offset 01:55:22.603; preserve native timestamps via the source timeline manifest.
DM: It worked out story-wise quite well
Unknown: Yeah, it was, yeah, it was great
DM: He might've been less friendly if you had just one from the beginning
Unknown: Yeah, it, it worked out the way it was
DM: It was Seeker strategy unintentionally.
DM: [laughs]
DM: Um, okay, so
DM: over the course of the next two hours you invisibly make your way across the landscape to the eaves of the forests.
DM: Um,
DM: you do see one pair of dragonets flying overhead, but they do not see you, as you are invisible.
DM: They seem to be heading south and unlikely to be related to any of your doings.
DM: Um,
DM: and the terrain, you know, so as you get further from the city the, the manors spread out.
DM: You pass a couple more of these, um,
DM: those things that look like
Unknown: possibly ancient tent sites with-
Unknown: Is this yours or...?
Unknown: No.
Unknown: Okay. I'm doing my duty
DM: ... with these arcane circles.
DM: Um,
DM: there's no, there isn't any-
Unknown: Gotta protect
DM: You don't pass anything that looks like farmland, although of course ancient farmland, if it was farmland thousands of years ago, would be overgrown.
DM: But it seems, it seems very dry.
Unknown: Like, there's no rivers, there's no water anywhere.
DM: There's har- oh, like only the occasional spring, so this is like scrub.
DM: It's like sort of very little,
DM: um-
Seeker: The forests are trapping the rivers
DM: Very few,
DM: uh, plants grow, just like little scrubby grasses and things.
DM: Um, the only animals that you see regularly are like little lizards that are s- scurrying around eating bugs.
DM: But as you, so as you approach,
DM: so it's a pretty smooth journey.
DM: I mean, the terrain's not that difficult to navigate.
DM: Um,
DM: you can see the forest getting closer.
DM: You, you reach the edge of the forest just about where the pilgrim's path that comes from the north enters the forest
Unknown: Right
DM: And you, I mean, you can see the road from some distance off, right?
DM: It's just as nice as the other road you passed.
DM: And
DM: so the forest itself, um, it's, at least here it's fairly open and airy and light, and the sun is shining.
DM: Um,
DM: you know, it's, it's not...
DM: It's sort of tall,
DM: sort of jungly trees, but
DM: light. Like, there's a lot of light coming through.
DM: There's like flowers growing in the under- understory.
DM: It's not like a real rainforest where you've got this closed canopy and then it's like really dense beneath, right?
DM: It's a pretty open
DM: forest. Um,
DM: but still when you s- I mean, when you step inside at 7:00, like you know, sun- sun sets quickly in the tropics, and you know, it's already start, the light is starting to get low, and so
DM: there's long shadows that are kind of cast across the, the,
DM: you know, the few open clearings that you pass through.
DM: Um, and you can actually see, so the, the pilgrim's path, you can see it goes straight,
DM: you know, kind of through the forest for,
DM: um,
DM: you know, for a while. Like, for
DM: a few miles anyway.
DM: You can... But it's like looking up like a cleared road, right?
DM: So there's no, there's trees that sort of form a canopy above it, but there's nothing growing on the road.
DM: There's no like sprouts sticking up.
DM: There's no roots that are disrupting the pavement, so it's like a very, you can't see very far in any other direction.
DM: But you can see
DM: quite far in that distance.
DM: And, and what you f- what you see is like it comes after maybe five or six miles,
DM: it sort of meets, it begins to like s- like it turns, and you can't see how it turns, but it looks like it joins with all the, probably your guess is it joins with all the other paths and it begins to sort
DM: of spiral up the mountain.
DM: But this now is, because it's not a straight path, right, we can't see it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Um,
DM: but otherwise, like the, the forest is, I mean, there's some birdsong.
DM: Like, there's the sound of buzzing insects at this time of day with the hot sun.
DM: It's pretty warm.
DM: You don't hear any, like, owls singing or anything.
DM: So where do you wanna go?
Unknown: Follow the road in from there?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. I think we get on-
Seeker: Oh, we use, um, our jade direction sense presumably?
Unknown: But we know where the jade is. It's not there.
DM: The jade, the jade's in the lair
Unknown: Oh, oh, oh. I thought we were trying to help.
Unknown: We're talking about the elders.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: No, no, no. We went into, we're going to try and find-
Unknown: Oh, sorry
Delwath: ... check out the monastery and see if we can find the elder dragonet, AKA Divitar
Unknown: AKA Divitar. Got it.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: let's just walk on the path
Unknown: No longer invisible?
Delwath: Yeah. Once we come into the forest.
Delwath: But actually we haven't been invisible for a little bit.
DM: Yeah, for a couple miles
Delwath: 'Cause I only did it, it covered eight of the 10 miles invisible.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: But we were long off the, like,
Unknown: flight path by the time it disappeared
Unknown: 'Cause the dragonets don't come into the forest.
Unknown: No.
Unknown: So.
Delwath: Yeah. Or yeah, let's just walk
DM: Yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: so, so you walk along the path.
DM: it's actually quite easy walking.
DM: It almost feels like you're-
Unknown: Hold on.
DM: Yeah
Unknown: How
Unknown: well,
Delwath: if I asked my wings to go bring a message to the elder, the eldest dragonet
DM: You have to at least be able to describe the person.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: You don't have to, like, know their name or anything.
Unknown: It can't just be everywhere.
DM: It can't just be everywhere.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: Does it have to be something you've seen?
Delwath: No, but just an actual...
Delwath: Somebody who had met... If I had a description from somebody who had met this dragonet, then I could.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: But you've seen a vision of it.
Kenzo: Or I've seen a vision of it.
Delwath: Have we connected in game your vision with this?
Kenzo: Yeah. Maybe.
Seeker: Well, we don't... We certainly don't know for sure that it's the same creature.
DM: Maybe. But-
Kenzo: I mean, when in the vision it was a...
Kenzo: It was literally one of these creatures, but, like, old looking.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: It was a pretty unusual type of creature, so.
Kenzo: Also hanging with the fucking, like, wizard guy that's, like, in my dr- Like, that's-
Delwath: Can I, can I send a message to the person that Rai describes to me and from his vision?
Delwath: Or did we all see that? Did we all see one of those visions?
DM: No, it was Rai's dream. It was Kenzo's dream of Rai.
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: To me.
DM: Um,
DM: I [laughs]...
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I don't know. Maybe.
DM: I mean-
Kenzo: No, this, this is pretty reasonable.
Kenzo: It's like, I mean, 'cause it's like
Kenzo: the one that I saw in the vision was, like, an old one of these, right?
Kenzo: And the one that we just saw was like 17 years old.
Kenzo: Like, were there any, like, old looking one?
Kenzo: Oh, one thing I should ask them, or maybe I did ask them, is like, you know, how old do they live, typically live to?
Unknown: Mm.
Kenzo: The dragonets.
DM: Um, they don't, I mean they, they, they're sort of like human-ish lifespans.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: Typically. Maybe a little shorter.
Kenzo: Wait, but Dimitar would be super old.
DM: Would be super, super old.
Kenzo: But was he magical? He was, right?
DM: Yeah, like Rai's familiar.
Kenzo: Oh.
DM: Seeker.
Seeker: Di- yeah, Dimitar would be 200 something right?
Kenzo: Could he, like, cast spells and do shit? What did he do other than, like, be a pain in the ass?
DM: Mostly he just, like, was a pain in the ass.
DM: [laughing]
Kenzo: That's what I thought, right? He was kind of a pain in the ass.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Yeah, aren't familiars supposed to be, like, useful and do, like, useful things?
DM: Well, Rai made a bad choice, I guess.
DM: [laughing]
Kenzo: Must be counterbalance for Rai, I guess.
Kenzo: Or, like, ultra powerful, but...
DM: I think it's a little too meta game.
Kenzo: What?
Kenzo: No, but, well, no, no, but I actually don't, right?
Kenzo: 'Cause it's like the only time we've seen...
Kenzo: Like it would, it would've clicked for Kenzo that the only time we've ever seen, like, any of these things before is in this vision with the drag- With, with, um...
Kenzo: And if this guy's talking about an elder...
Seeker: But it's just like Kenzo's gotta describe this particular creature to Delwath, and then describes the creature-
Kenzo: To the links
Unknown: ... to
Unknown: the links.
Kenzo: Yeah, that might be too much. But I think, I, I don't think the c- like, our characters...
Kenzo: I think it'd be reasonable for us to guess that the-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... that the-
DM: But the, I mean, the intent is not to be able to determine whether somebody is real or not by sending them messages with that.
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: That,
Kenzo: that's fair.
Unknown: Right.
DM: That's right.
Kenzo: That's fair.
Unknown: That's a fair point.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: So I don't think you can use it to send a message to somebody who might exist or might be close by,
DM: right? The intent is to use it to send messages to people you know exist.
Wellby: How far can you scan for consciousnesses?
Kenzo: 30 mile.
Kenzo: Anywhere on the island.
Wellby: Can you look across the whole wood to see if there's, like-
Kenzo: You know, that's actually interesting.
Kenzo: Could I, could... That actually would, I potentially could do, would be to try to suss out the specific, um,
Kenzo: aura of a sp- Actually, that's what it's for.
Wellby: Right.
Kenzo: I could try to, I could, I could, I could try to find the elder, the elder, um.
DM: Um, yep.
Unknown: Mm. Mm.
DM: You'd have to spend another 6 ki, so it's, it's getting...
DM: Well, you could always take a short rest.
Kenzo: Yeah. Why don't I short rest real quick?
Unknown: Let's walk for a little bit.
Kenzo: The whole thing? But no.
Unknown: Let's mope.
Kenzo: Like, if I can find Dimitar now, like I'll just know where he is.
Wellby: If you know where any, like, sentient being in the forest is.
Kenzo: Actually-
DM: Well, you have to have q- Like you can either get a general sense or you have to search for a specific-
Kenzo: Short... How long is a short rest?
Unknown: An hour.
DM: An hour.
Kenzo: I, right now I've still got like nine ki or whatever, so how about, how about I do, um...
Kenzo: Yeah, just I'll, I'll, I'll do a, a search in the forest specifically for, um, looking for the energy, actually over the whole island actually, specifically looking for the energy
Kenzo: of an elder, the oldest bit dragonet energy-
DM: Okay
Kenzo: ... on the pl- on this, this island.
DM: Mm.
DM: Um, in the monastery on the top of the mountain.
Kenzo: Wow.
Unknown: Huh.
Kenzo: Fuck yeah.
Wellby: All right. Let's hustle.
Unknown: Are we going up?
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
Unknown: Now can I send... I mean,
Delwath: I don't know if I actually want to send a message or what we would say.
Kenzo: Well, n- n- now I know, we know exactly where he is now.
Delwath: But we should be able to send a message knowing-
DM: Yes. Now you could send a message.
Unknown: Should we send a message ahead?
Kenzo: To say what?
DM: So you walk, as you talk, you walk along the forest road.
DM: And again, like I was saying, it, it feels
DM: almost as if your pace is quickened by the road you're walking on.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: And you're covering ground surprisingly fast as the sun sets.
DM: Over the course of about an hour, the sun sinks.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Sunset lights up the sky,
DM: and you hear to the right of the path, so west, as you're heading to the mountain, what sounds like the
DM: sound of running water
DM: and a waterfall.
DM: Keep walking? [laughs]
Kenzo: Last time we didn't investigate the waterfall.
DM: Continue-
Delwath: No, I think, I, I think I am gonna send the links ahead with a message to this creature saying...
Kenzo: Saying what?
Unknown: Um, "We're
Unknown: coming to visit.
Unknown: Are there dangers?"
Kenzo: We could be a danger.
Kenzo: That's why we, we wanna like-
DM: Should you mention Rai maybe?
DM: Or coming.
Unknown: We can say who we are
DM: I'm trying to follow Rai's mission
Delwath: We're, we're, we're, we're seeking, we're coming...
Unknown: I just feel like we should announce ourselves.
Unknown: They can't fly away.
Kenzo: But like...
Delwath: And like we don't know is, is,
Delwath: is this creature like tra- I mean, your detection doesn't tell us anything about-
Kenzo: No, no
Unknown: ... right?
Kenzo: But I'll, but I'll, okay. But okay, I mean, I think it would be reasonable for, for us in game to be like, "Hey, this is like the thing."
Kenzo: But like, I would wanna wait to like,
Kenzo: like converse with it more when we see it, you know?
Delwath: See, I wanna find out if it is
Delwath: able to converse or like trapped by some evil monster.
Kenzo: Okay. Okay.
Seeker: As we get closer, I can clairvoyance also.
Kenzo: Yeah, that feels useful. That feels more useful.
DM: But then-
Unknown: Maybe we clairvoyance first
Wellby: I think 'cause it's, it's like the one way nature of the message just makes it difficult.
Kenzo: Yeah. 'Cause then we, we don't know, like-
Unknown: We can send a response
Wellby: But like we can't anticipate-
Unknown: Yes, I know
Wellby: ... all the possible situations that it might be.
Kenzo: Let's get closer and clairvoyance
Unknown: No, that's actually better
DM: You're, you're about eight miles away right now from the summit of the mountain.
Kenzo: What's the range for clairvoyance?
Seeker: Well, technically one, and then I can double it up to five times burning all my slots that I'm gonna need for other spells
Kenzo: Yeah, don't do that
Unknown: Wow. I would double it
Unknown: once maybe.
DM: So we'll do it at, at a two mile range?
Unknown: At two miles out.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: Yeah, I was thinking like a similar thing, yeah.
DM: So you keep walking into the night and you actually like feel
DM: the, the, it, you almost feel as if there's many other people walking with you and you sort of have a feeling like
DM: the traditional sort of pilgrim's route was to walk through the night and reach the summit of the
DM: mountain at dawn.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: And every now and then you do hear sort of like whispers.
DM: It almost sounds like the wind rustling to the trees sounds almost elvish.
Unknown: What, what did the elves have to do with these human goddamn?
Delwath: The elves, as far as I know, the elves had nothing to do with these people.
Kenzo: Then what the fuck are they doing all up in this?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: I don't know.
DM: So you keep walking as the darkness sets and the moon rises.
Kenzo: Once we get to two miles away, let's clairvoyance inside.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Yeah, I think so.
DM: So another-
Unknown: Mark those off
DM: ... um, another, another, you know,
DM: hour or so-
Delwath: So, so like 8:00 at night
DM: ... walking, it's like 8:00 at night, um,
DM: uh, you pass again,
DM: um,
DM: a place where, um, a stream seems to flow like on the right side, or sorry, on the left side now 'cause the east seems to s- s- flow close to the, very close to
Unknown: the, the, um, the road.
Delwath: Does the, does the forest keep going up the mountain or-
DM: About halfway up the mountain
Unknown: Okay. So we're still in the forest.
DM: You're still in the... You haven't hit the part where it spirals yet.
DM: When-
Kenzo: And is the stream, and the, is the stream flowing up or down?
DM: Down, but it's stopped.
DM: Like it's stopped.
DM: You can see it flowing and it stops.
DM: And by the side of the,
DM: by the side of the road, there's this big pool which the stream flows into, but doesn't exit from.
Kenzo: Huh. Should I go to the pool real quick?
DM: Um,
DM: okay, hold on. Sorry.
Unknown: I, I have to do something.
Unknown: Roll initiative.
DM: Um-
Kenzo: God, I can't wait to roll my plus 10 initiative.
Unknown: With advantage, right?
Kenzo: With advantage, yeah. That's crazy.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, you walk, you walk over to the pool,
DM: um,
DM: and as you get closer, you see that the,
DM: the water is kind of murky and filled with like debris.
DM: And there's two stones that are sort of standing next to it, like sort of an entryway to a little viewing area over the pool that are actually cracked.
DM: One has fallen in half and part of the stone has, um, fallen into the pool itself.
DM: And you can see staring out at you from the pool, like the reflections of people with hollow eyes,
DM: their faces contorted in pain.
DM: Make a wisdom saving throw.
Unknown: Everybody or just-
DM: Just Kenzo. He's the only one who's
Delwath: [laughs] Well, I don't know. I was thinking we might have all followed him, but I guess not.
Delwath: [laughs] Thanks for being the, um, guinea pig, Kenzo.
Kenzo: Plus eight.
Kenzo: Wait, and also I get to, I get, um, advantage, right?
DM: From what?
Kenzo: Oh, I guess I can just roll this.
DM: You can roll a-
Kenzo: I can use my heroic
DM: ... if you want. Yeah
Kenzo: ... my heroic, uh, whatever.
Unknown: Oh, fuck. I forget which one. I'm gonna try this one.
Kenzo: [dice rolling]
Unknown: Nice.
Kenzo: 26.
Kenzo: Oh, sorry.
DM: You feel a bit uneasy, but nothing bad happens to you.
Kenzo: 24. Wait, sorry.
Kenzo: So I see the reflections of these, these like, like tortured souls or whatever in the thing, but there's no...
Kenzo: It's, I'm just seeing their reflections.
DM: You're just seeing the reflections. There's nothing standing around the pool.
Kenzo: Do I sense anything standing around the pool?
DM: Nope.
Kenzo: Um, do I have the heebie-jeebies?
DM: Yeah, a little bit.
Kenzo: Did I have the heebie-jeebies before?
DM: No.
DM: I mean, it's a creepy image, right?
DM: It's like people who died in pain looking back up at you and kind of screaming at you.
Delwath: But they're not underwater looking up, they're reflections?
Unknown: Is it-
DM: They seem like they're reflections, yeah
Kenzo: Do they look like they're... So they don't look like they're trapped in there.
Kenzo: They look like they're standing around the pool, but I just can't see them.
DM: Exactly. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Kenzo: And, uh, do they look like they were, um, like what, what was the way in which they died?
Kenzo: Were they, do they like have like battle wounds and stuff, or do they look like sickly, um-
DM: Sickly
Kenzo: Almost as though like a demonic red mist may have
DM: Kind of something like that, yes
Kenzo: Interesting. Okay.
Unknown: So the fucking plague mist came here.
Seeker: Does this feel like a dispel magic situation?
DM: That's up to you.
Kenzo: So yeah, don't look at that.
Kenzo: Um.
Unknown: Keep going?
DM: Keep going.
Delwath: I think keep going.
Delwath: Cleansing the island is sort of a bigger task than-
Unknown: Yeah, we don't want
Unknown: to do it
Kenzo: Oh, actually, you know, um, can I do cleansing touch to this thing?
DM: You wanna touch the water?
Kenzo: I mean, hold on. I, I mean, I can-
Delwath: The right answer when the GM says a question like that with that tone of voice is 100% of the time, "No, no, no, I don't."
Kenzo: Oh. [laughs]
DM: You have to touch somebody to do cleansing touch.
Kenzo: Yeah, cleansing touch is touching a creature.
DM: I mean, you could try it, but you'd have to touch the water for it to have any effect.
Delwath: I mean, bad ideas can be fun.
Kenzo: I don't know. I'll, I'll touch the water later.
DM: Okay. [laughs] So you ke- you keep going and, and you're now-
Unknown: We'll get that on the way back
DM: ... another-
Kenzo: All right. I will though
DM: ... um, it's another, uh,
DM: mile or so as you, the pa- the road begins to like go slightly up, um, and you can see about, um, half a mile ahead is the place where it curved that
DM: you can't, you couldn't see beyond.
DM: Forest is still open, the moonlight is shining down.
DM: Um,
DM: another like stream with another pool.
DM: This seems to be like all of the water that flows down off the mountain stops in this pool.
Kenzo: Right. Are we about two miles away yet?
DM: Um, at this point, yeah.
DM: I mean, the, the road is longer than two miles from here, but the-
Unknown: Straight off is two miles
DM: ... straight off is about two miles, yeah.
Kenzo: Fabulous.
Wellby: As we were coming in, was there any evidence of past stream beds?
Unknown: In other words,
Wellby: did the water used to flow all the way across the island and now it doesn't?
DM: Doesn't, you didn't see anything like that.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: This island is hollow probably.
DM: Um, Wellby's-
Kenzo: There's legs, there's legs at the bottom
DM: ... of course, now he wants to look at the other pool
Kenzo: For what it...
Unknown: What's that?
DM: Nobody wants to look at the other pool
Wellby: Kenzo, there's another pool to look at.
Delwath: Would you like to go check it out?
Kenzo: I think I know what's inside there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right.
DM: Clairvoyance?
Unknown: Um,
Seeker: yeah, so I'll use one glove charge
Unknown: and
Seeker: cast, what level is clairvoyance?
Seeker: Third, one, third level slot.
Unknown: Oh, second level slot.
Unknown: All right.
Seeker: And I'm gonna place the sensor...
Seeker: We don't really know anything about the layout of the buildings though, do we?
DM: I mean, all you could see from a distance was it looked like, you know,
DM: buildings around a central courtyard, and then there's like a, a bell tower in the central courtyard.
Seeker: I might learn nothing by looking
Unknown: from the center of the courtyard.
Seeker: We could gamble about a vantage point inside one of the buildings, but again-
Kenzo: I would just do the central courtyard
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: But I don't know, that might be wrong.
Wellby: With a, with a view of the bell tower?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I mean, the-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: Maybe in the bell tower
Kenzo: ... yeah, can you in the bell tower looking down around the, yeah
Seeker: Does the bell tower have like an open structure?
DM: So it's like, it's like solid base, and then there's a, a place where the bell is that's open.
DM: So, and then-
Kenzo: Maybe up there, so you can see all the way down around
DM: ... and then going up above the top, there's some s- some like crystal structure that extends up above the bell platform
Unknown: A crystal structure?
DM: You can't see any details. It's just like something.
Unknown: I, I think actually I'm gonna put it
Unknown: up high-
Kenzo: I like that
Unknown: ... near the bell tower-
Seeker: ... so I can look, I can inspect the crystal structure and also see down into the courtyard and through any windows.
Kenzo: That, that's great.
DM: All right.
Kenzo: Love that.
DM: So
DM: you see, um, this looks like, so
Unknown: there's the bell tower.
DM: The, the, the bell is intact.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Um, but this, the structure that stands on top of it looks like it once was like a,
DM: like a giant sort of crystalline light that's now broken and cracked.
DM: Like you can see mirrors, like it was clearly...
Unknown: It's like a lighthouse almost.
Unknown: Weird.
DM: But it would've sh- shown somehow, probably magic, but it's like clearly sort of also constructed, right?
DM: It's not just a crystal that glows magically, right?
DM: It's like-
Unknown: A mechanism
DM: ... a mechanism, but the mechanism is destroyed or cracked.
DM: Um, the bell is intact, and then looking down, the courtyard is in pretty good shape, right?
DM: Like it's paved, um,
DM: and-
Unknown: This is definitely where you steer the island from
DM: ... and it's [laughs], and there's eight, so there's eight temples that surround the courtyard, each one with a separate statue of the,
DM: of the eight gods of Mos Numena.
DM: No
DM: sign of anything there, just the moonlight shining over the stones.
Unknown: No lights?
DM: No lights,
DM: no torches, no fires, no movement, no weird creepy shadows, no
DM: dragons.
Seeker: Try sound for a minute just to see.
DM: You hear the sort of
DM: murmur of the wind.
Seeker: All's qui- all's quiet here.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Seeker: It seems we should approach quietly.
Kenzo: Do we, um...
Seeker: Oh, signs of just like recent foot traffic, like any wear on the stones or like leaves piled and...
Unknown: Make a investigation check
Wellby: So [die rolling] 18.
Unknown: [laughs]
Wellby: Oh, three.
DM: Is it your perspective is a little bit high to see any, like, careful detail because the...
DM: I mean, the bell tower goes up fairly tall, right?
Wellby: Mm. Oh, yeah. I'm high up.
DM: And you're up above the bell tower, so it's hard to make out any obvious details.
DM: But it definitely doesn't seem to be destroyed in the same way that, like, the town, the port town was destroyed.
DM: Like, there's not... The, the temples are all intact.
Wellby: Mm.
Unknown: Like, their roofs, they're, like, not...
DM: And there's no... There's definitely not signs of, you know, a large group of something living here, right?
Unknown: Like, there's no-
Wellby: No trash. There's no-
DM: There's no trash. There's no...
DM: Yeah, there's no, like, scraps of food.
DM: There's no, like, clothes hanging out to dry.
DM: There's no, like, signs of substantial inhabitation.
DM: But if, like, one dragonet is walking around, like, they wouldn't really leave enough right behind for you to notice-
Wellby: Mm
DM: ... from this high up.
Wellby: [sighs] Hmm.
Seeker: Well, that's what we get from clear voice, I guess.
Unknown: [sighs] I mean...
Unknown: I also want to create.
Delwath: I, I, I still wonder if it's worth sending a message
Unknown: rather than just walking in the front door.
Kenzo: And it can, uh, send a message back.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah, like, "We come in peace to seek an audience with you," kind of thing?
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: That kind of thing.
Delwath: I'll do that. I'll send the links with a message to this eldest creature.
Wellby: Okay.
Delwath: Just saying basically, we are
Unknown: travelers
Unknown: to this island
Unknown: seeking a piece
Unknown: of Rai's hand.
Unknown: We
Unknown: seek your-
Kenzo: Guidance
Unknown: ... guidance.
Kenzo: Counsel.
Unknown: And counsel.
Wellby: Piece of Rai's hand.
DM: Piece of Rai's hand.
Wellby: In, in the possession of the dragon.
Delwath: Seeking the piece of Rai's hand in the possession of...
Unknown: What was the guy's name? Uh, Ron-
Wellby: Ra- Ra'ghemdros.
Unknown: Ra'ghemdros.
Wellby: Gotta say something about our motivation.
Unknown: Yeah, exactly.
Wellby: In order to further
Wellby: Rai's...
Unknown: In order to further-
Wellby: To fulfill Rai's mission
Unknown: ... in order to, in order to
Unknown: preserve, continue...
Unknown: In order to continue Rai's
Unknown: mission.
Wellby: Nice.
Kenzo: Uh, or, uh-
Wellby: To hold back the-
Kenzo: Yeah. Do we want to specifically say-
Unknown: I wasn't gonna mention Hkar
Kenzo: ... we don't, we don't, we don't... We shouldn't have mentioned his name.
Kenzo: But, um,
Kenzo: um, uh, we can say something like, uh, um, you know, it's, like, maintaining the...
Unknown: I think continue, or, like,
Delwath: continue Rai's mission is pretty...
Delwath: If, if it's somebody who knows what Rai was doing,
Unknown: they know what Rai was doing.
Kenzo: Yeah, fair.
Delwath: Um, and then we,
Delwath: uh, we, we seek an audience and, and wish to know
Delwath: if it is safe and advisable to approach.
Kenzo: Oh, we could also ask the augury thing and be like, "Hey, is it okay?
Kenzo: It's... Should we just like walk up?"
Unknown: Sure.
Kenzo: I mean, I think we should do this too.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Let's just [clicks tongue] do this first.
Unknown: So the link goes off.
DM: Send a message.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: Yeah. So it'll take it, like...
DM: I forget how fast it goes.
DM: Like-
Delwath: Uh, it can go really pretty fast.
Unknown: It, if it's on- If it's within...
Delwath: If it's a short distance, it goes faster.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Um, so it's probably-
Kenzo: Should we short rest anyways while we wait?
Delwath: I mean, that I was just thinking maybe we should short rest while we're waiting.
Kenzo: That'd be great. That'll get all my ki back.
DM: Okay.
DM: Send it off. Short rest.
Unknown: Yes. No response comes.
Wellby: Is there, like, a delivery receipt though?
Kenzo: Yeah, exactly. Do you know that it got there?
Unknown: Um...
DM: You can... I think you can tell it to, like, wait for a certain amount of time for a response.
Delwath: Yeah. Hold on. Let me double check. Well, to...
Delwath: Let's see. Uh, the message is a written or spoken message of up to 1,000 words.
Delwath: It'll travel to the named person or described person, deliver the message, wait for a time you designate for a response, and then travel back to you.
Unknown: Uh...
Kenzo: Does it just, like, say all this out loud?
DM: You can either write it down or it says it all out loud, yes.
Unknown: Um-
Kenzo: Why not say it out loud if it's being held captive?
Delwath: I mean, it's, it's a...
Unknown: Let me just... Let's see. We can choose to speak.
Kenzo: We just, like, tell the [laughs] thing to lose all of our supplies.
Unknown: 50 miles per hour. [laughs]
Wellby: I'm imagining Kenza saying that as the link vanishes around the bend in the trail.
Wellby: [laughs]
Delwath: So it's going f- it can go 50 miles an hour.
DM: So it goes... Yeah, in, like, 10 minutes.
Wellby: Wow.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: But wait. But wait.
DM: How long do you want it to wait?
Delwath: I want it to wait an hou- I mean, 50 mi- it, we're only two miles by the most direct route.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: 50 miles an hour at two miles is 15 minutes.
Kenzo: So we just, we're, we just alert- we just alerted the, the demonic thing that's holding Dimitar.
DM: So it's gonna wait an hour.
Delwath: But it's gonna wait an hour for a response.
DM: No response.
Delwath: But we could write it down and we could give it a written message.
DM: You could.
Kenzo: That's what I was saying 'cause, like, it's, it's...
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... if Dimitar's being held captive, we don't want to, like, announce to his captor like, "Hey, we're the s-
Delwath: Yeah, yeah, but it's a written, it's a written message. I mean, obviously it'll still show up with a written message, but it's not gonna give it to someone.
Wellby: What if Dimitar's alert?
Seeker: It's the middle of the night, though.
Kenzo: Does it only give the message to the recipient?
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: It only gives the message to the recipient. It's, it's, uh-
Kenzo: Oh, if, if it's spoken, will it only be spoken to the recipient?
Unknown: Yeah. Yeah.
Kenzo: It's not, like, said out loud to everybody.
Unknown: Well, I don't know. If it-
Unknown: Anybody could hear it, but it won't...
DM: If it can't find the recipient, it won't speak it to whoever happens to be-
Kenzo: But the written message also would only be given to the, uh-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... would only be given to the recipient.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: All right.
DM: It, it is-
Kenzo: And do we know that it was delivered?
DM: It's 9:00 at night.
Wellby: It's night time.
Kenzo: Do we know that it was delivered?
Delwath: Do... I mean, I don't think there's anythi- I mean, there's nothing in what you wrote.
Unknown: I've never imagined this, like,
Unknown: knowing-
Kenzo: Is there a read receipt?
Delwath: I don't... Is there? I-
DM: Just left on sent
Delwath: I feel like I would know if the
DM: You would know if it didn't find the person.
Unknown: Yes.
DM: If it finds the person and doesn't get...
DM: Like, there's nothing to...
DM: Like, it could drop off a message, wait for an hour, the person could just ignore the dro- me-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... the written message, and it would come back, and you know it found the person.
DM: You, it doesn't have the ability to, like, communicate
Unknown: But so the lynx comes back, right?
DM: The lynx comes back.
Unknown: After an hour.
DM: After an hour.
Unknown: And?
DM: No response.
Delwath: But did it fi- I mean, it didn't, like, wander around for the hour looking for the person.
DM: Yeah, yeah. No.
Unknown: It found the person.
DM: It definitely found the person.
Kenzo: Wait, and so does... If it found...
Kenzo: Do you get information from the lynx about how, where it went and, like, how it got there?
DM: No, no.
Delwath: I can't really communicate with the ly- Like, it's not...
Delwath: The lynx is like a ghostly spirit.
Unknown: It's not like an actual-
DM: No, it's not something you talk to. It just
Unknown: It doesn't really have any intelligence.
DM: I see.
Unknown: Like
DM: It's not a familiar. It's just like a spirit messenger.
DM: So you finish your short rest uneventfully.
Unknown: Okay. Well, I'm gonna take a short rest. That's useful.
Kenzo: So that's ominous.
Delwath: That is. We also, by the way, anybody who had the bonus hit points
Unknown: Yeah, delete those bonus hit points.
Unknown: Oh, oh, oh, nope, don't delete them.
Delwath: I cast it again before the short rest.
DM: There you go.
DM: Don't tempt me.
Delwath: I mean, I used my, um, I used my once a day get back two slots.
Delwath: So I have one slot left. Is there anything else I want to cast?
DM: Uh
Unknown: Can I try and scry Dimitar?
DM: You can tr- You, you...
DM: There's nothing stopping you from trying to scry on literally anybody.
Kenzo: You should totally try to scry Dimitar.
Unknown: Yeah, fine. I'm gonna try and scry.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: 'Cause now, yeah, you got one more slot.
Delwath: 'Cause I have one more slot I can burn, but if we're short resting
DM: What are the, what are the scrying
Delwath: Uh, plus five for secondhand,
Unknown: and that's it.
DM: Okay.
DM: You have
Seeker: a giant crystalline magic light source on top of your bell tower, on top of your monastery, on top of your mountain, on top of your island.
Kenzo: It's like-
Unknown: What's your DC?
DM: Uh, 19, I believe.
Kenzo: But it's when you're like a walking island and you want to, like, let people know you're walking around.
Unknown: It's to prevent collisions more than anything.
Kenzo: Yeah, with other walking islands.
Kenzo: Yeah. [laughs]
DM: You see
Kenzo: Oh
DM: ... a very, um, elderly,
DM: um, dragonet.
Unknown: Same kind of creature as before.
DM: Their skin is almost a light gray.
DM: It seems like all color has faded from their skin.
DM: There's, like, a few faint little traces of purple that you can see.
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: And they're currently walking slowly around the inside of a temple.
DM: You can't tell which one it is from the inside, and seem to be in the process of rigging some kind of trap to drop from the ceiling on whoever enters the temple.
Delwath: [laughs] Um, I can't tell which temple it was?
DM: Uh
Delwath: There's no iconography inside the temple?
DM: Oh, I guess you have darkvision, right?
DM: So
Delwath: Yeah, darkvision to 120 feet.
DM: Right. Um, uh, this is
Unknown: No, I have eyes of the-
DM: Right, so you can see
Delwath: I can see in all darkness of any sort.
DM: So it's pitch, it's pitch black inside the temple.
DM: Um,
DM: uh,
DM: I guess there's, like, a faint little bit of moonlight through some windows.
Unknown: Um, you can see the, uh,
DM: um...
DM: Yeah, it's, it's the, the statue that you recognize would be The Sibyl,
DM: and it seems to be... But it seems like the inside of the temple has been kind of, like, a lot of the stones have been sort of shifted around, like clearly somebody's lived inside
DM: here.
Kenzo: So this is like, uh, Home Alone Dimitar or edition.
Seeker: For sure. Like, he detected the clairvoyance and was like, "All right, I know what's going on."
Delwath: Well, or the message, but
Unknown: maybe he just refused to read it.
Unknown: I can't tell if he read it or not.
DM: He just doesn't trust it.
Kenzo: Yeah, it's... He seems like he totally read it.
Unknown: All right.
Unknown: I'll watch him for a few minutes.
DM: Okay.
Kenzo: What kind of trap is he setting up?
DM: Um, there's like a giant stone that he's, like, kind of pulling on to a series of pulleys to lift
DM: up above.
Kenzo: Is there, like, a sandwich at the bottom or something in there?
Kenzo: [laughs]
Seeker: Some tiny but delicious looking snack.
DM: It's a little piece of fruit sitting on, in the door entrance here.
Kenzo: Well, he knows that he lives in Elsweyr, so.
Delwath: Yeah. What, like, I'm gonna study the trap for a little bit.
Unknown: What's the trigger mechanism?
Unknown: Is it obvious?
DM: Um, he hasn't gotten to the trigger mechanism yet.
Unknown: Oh, okay.
DM: Right now he seems to be just struggling with some pulleys and rope to, like, lift...
DM: Like, it looks like a pretty substantial-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... block of stone,
DM: presumably set up to fall on your heads when you enter the inside.
Kenzo: And there's only one door in here?
Unknown: There's only one door into the temple, just the main door.
Unknown: Because you don't live to be as grand as you are-
Unknown: By trusting people
DM: ... by trusting everyone.
Kenzo: All right.
Unknown: Um
Kenzo: Well, that's good though. He's not cap- he's not being held captive, you know?
Unknown: He's not being held captive.
Kenzo: Yeah, so.
Unknown: That is true.
Kenzo: This is, this was actually good. Thought we were gonna have to do some weird battle with demonic things, but
Unknown: I did too.
Unknown: Okay. So
Delwath: yeah, he's setting up a trap.
Unknown: He doesn't trust us.
Kenzo: It's fine. I wouldn't trust us either.
Kenzo: I barely trust you guys. [laughs]
Unknown: So do you continue, continue walking?
Kenzo: Trust is strong here. [laughs] Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, I think we-
Kenzo: Let's just go in. Let's go talk to him.
Delwath: I mean, yeah, we should avoid the trap.
Kenzo: Let's avoid the trap, but also, I mean, I'm, I've got a staff with four pieces of the jade on it.
Kenzo: I mean-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... he'll, he'll talk to us.
Wellby: And is there an obvious way to disarm the trap?
Delwath: Well, I didn't... I guess scrying doesn't last long enough to see the mechanism.
Kenzo: It only lasts 10, it only lasts 10 minutes.
DM: You just saw him, like
Delwath: And I wanted to short rest, so I didn't want to scry again.
DM: Struggling to pull the giant block of stone up, but you didn't see the mechanism that he was trying to set.
Delwath: So he's had an hour to still build it since we
DM: Yeah, this is right at the beginning.
DM: It's sort of been,
DM: this would've been shortly after-
Unknown: As soon as I sent...
Delwath: No, not even. As soon as I sent the lynx, we would've s- I would've cast scry pretty much.
Delwath: Or, like, it's not... 'Cause the hour, actually the hour, I would've probably seen...
Delwath: Okay, so the point was to short rest during the hour the lynx was gone.
DM: Okay, well this hap- this is all happening after the links came.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So maybe you didn't see it.
Unknown: Well, no, the links would have-
DM: Oh, the links would've been there faster
Unknown: ... the links got there in two minutes.
Unknown: It was the 50 mile an hour wind.
DM: Right, so you actually see the links waiting there.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: And your scribe is just standing there
Unknown: With the, like message glowing in its jaw or something.
DM: And it seems to be ignoring it completely.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: Oh, but, but he was, but he read the message.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Well, there's no way to tell.
Delwath: I can't tell if he read the message.
Delwath: The message isn't... it's not, I never envisioned it as like a piece of paper.
DM: It's not just a piece... it's not a piece of paper, right?
DM: It's like the, the spirit shows up and you either,
DM: it either starts speaking in Delwath's voice or like glowing letters appear in front of the person, right?
DM: And they can
Unknown: either speak or write a response.
DM: The only reason for the written is in cases where you might need to communicate without
DM: alerting-
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: Right. Right, so you could send a written message to like a prisoner and it wouldn't alert the guards or something.
DM: But it's all magic. It's not like...
DM: it's, it doesn't carry like a scroll in its jaw that it drops in front of you.
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: Right? It's just-
Kenzo: Let's go up to the temple.
Unknown: Well, yeah, let's do it.
Kenzo: Have a chat with this dude.
Unknown: Let's do it.
DM: So you keep walking.
DM: After another, like half an hour of walking, you, you come to the point where the road curves and it seems to spiral, to join, um, like a circular road.
DM: And just where it joins this road that's circling up to the top of the mountain, um, you see, uh, again, on the edge of the path,
DM: a sort of a slight clearing where there's two unusually tall trees.
DM: And almost like growing between the trees there's this sort of curving piece of, uh, sort of pale gray stone, but it looks like...
DM: this actually sort of grows into the trees.
DM: And written on the stone are hundreds of names of elves written in Elvish.
DM: But the s- the, the scripts almost seem to like drift slowly through the stone between the two trees.
Kenzo: You recognize any of the names?
DM: Uh, no.
Unknown: I'm gonna touch it.
Kenzo: Get any vibe from it?
DM: Um,
DM: you,
DM: uh-
Delwath: I'm gonna add my name if I can.
Kenzo: What?
Kenzo: This is like some sacred thing for like dead elves, and you're just like-
Unknown: This is a memorial to the elves that fell so many years ago.
Kenzo: Dead, yeah. Like you tag it.
Unknown: Well-
Kenzo: Ugh
Delwath: ... no, no, no. I think it's a...
Unknown: I mean, it depends on what the vibe I get is.
DM: Oh.
Delwath: But if it's about elves who are coming here in a ritual context.
Delwath: If it's not a memorial, if it's elves leaving their own like I'm here as a-
DM: So, so when you-
Delwath: Like, I can't tell if your vibe is Vietnam War memorial wall or like
Unknown: leave your name.
DM: So here's what happens when you touch it.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: So when you touch it, um, one of these like names kind of drifts towards your hand and you suddenly have a memor- A, you suddenly see a vision or a memory-
Kenzo: Mm
DM: ... of, um, an elf standing in a rank of hundreds of elves, um,
DM: on a battlements watching a
DM: fleet of ships sailing
DM: on a sea. You don't recognize any of this.
DM: Um, and as they're, um, drawing their, like arrows, suddenly they all draw their arrows and suddenly like all of the arrows burst into flames immediately
DM: as they're released from the bows, and this rain of fire flies down on the ships.
DM: And then something flies up from one of the ships, like a,
DM: not a dragon, like some sort of twisted beast like the Nazgul creatures in The Lord of the Rings, right?
DM: And dives down and grabs this elf and like rips him-
Unknown: That, that sounds like... never mind. I'm not, I'm not adding anything.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: My first impression was this is like a-
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... like as a pilgrimage to Posham.
DM: Yeah. Then you, you see echoes of like memories going back of this elf, of like the sort of history of-
Kenzo: This is cool though
DM: ... this elf.
Kenzo: Like learn more about the... this is, this is some histor-
DM: Yeah, no, I'm kind of-
Kenzo: This, this is some historical like...
Kenzo: yeah, learn, learn, this is like some like, you know, Netflix documentary of like, uh, you know-
DM: The-
Kenzo: ... True Crimes
DM: ... it, it seems like-
Kenzo: Downfall Elf
DM: ... it seems like the, so the, the sort of magic of it is when you put your hand there, some names sort of drift towards you, right?
DM: Like the ones that maybe are
DM: the, the closest to you and you,
DM: you, you see back in this person's life and you see that they were originally,
DM: uh, they first joined the army as a quarter master, and you see them cooking, right?
DM: You see like they were...
DM: you, you get a sort of reflection or echo of some of the
DM: things they left behind and the people that they, other elves and humans that they could afford.
Delwath: Any way of telling where they were born, Agrilak?
Unknown: Or-
DM: No.
Kenzo: But this is-
DM: Long ago and far away.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: But y- the sense, like the feeling you get is like this,
DM: your in- your intuition is that all of these are names of elves who died.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
DM: And the one that's drawn to you, the one that's like drawn to your hand when you touch it, is the one that's like-
Delwath: I'm gonna gesture for Kenzo to come over and see.
DM: Sure.
Unknown: We should see what happens.
DM: Hmm. Nothing.
Unknown: Racist.
Wellby: [laughs] Like Delwath knew that that would be the case.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I mean, you-
Unknown: Touch the point
DM: ... it's not nothing. I, uh, um, like you, you don't see the like flashes of memory, but you definitely feel the sort of vibe.
DM: Like you get more of a th- there's no specific elf that kind of is drawn to Kenzo.
DM: Um,
DM: but you get this sort of vibe, right?
DM: You get the sort of general sense of, you know, all of these are people who died in battle.
DM: Like you get this echo of like the lives of all of these people and sort of just a vague sense of-
Kenzo: Yeah
DM: ... you know.
Kenzo: Kenzo, Kenzo goes to, uh, talk to the tree.
Kenzo: 'Cause you know, there are two trees and then the-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... yeah.
DM: Um, what do you say to it?
Kenzo: Well, first, um, fir- you know, again, really, really critical when talking to trees.
Kenzo: Now step number one is always consent.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: So, so Kenzo gets close to the tree and, um, as it, as he, as he approaches, holding his, uh, you know, staff made out of elven, you know, whatever-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... um, uh, you know, kind of asks for permission to, to touch it and to get close.
DM: You,
DM: you get this sense of something kind of
DM: being drawn out from a deep sleep, but also yes, and also
DM: a weird sense of recognition.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: Like when you were in Ormos-
Kenzo: Mm-hmm
DM: ... and there was that giant tree in the middle of the city that you had to commune with for a while.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: It's like the same.
Kenzo: Cool.
Kenzo: Um, yeah, I'll, uh, get close to the tree.
Kenzo: I will, uh, take my staff and, um, you know, nestle it into-
DM: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: ... you know, part of the root structure, and then, you know, put, put my hand on it, and I will introduce myself.
DM: The tree kind of very slowly
DM: begins to talk.
DM: It hasn't in
DM: too long.
Kenzo: Oh, fuck, it's talking. All right.
Unknown: I mean, you're using Speak with Plants, right?
DM: Of course it's talking.
Kenzo: Cool. Um,
Kenzo: how long have you slumbered?
DM: There have been
DM: no pilgrims
DM: for
DM: 700 years.
Kenzo: 700 years ago was when-
DM: Mm
Kenzo: ... Drankor fell.
Kenzo: Uh.
Delwath: Wow, I wonder how precisely dating can we trust the trees?
DM: I wouldn't trust it to the year.
DM: I would trust it to the century.
Delwath: So, like, we can't determine if pilgrims stopped when Apollyon-
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: The pilgrims, humans, elves,
Kenzo: others?
DM: All of those of Drankor
DM: were welcome here.
Kenzo: All right, and really quick meta game, so, uh,
Kenzo: Drankor,
Kenzo: elves were down with Drankor, or certain elves were.
DM: Ear- So the, like, grand history of Drankor, early on it was, like, this
DM: very sort of open city where humans and elves and these Paranar, which are, like, the weird half elves, and anybody else, like, was super welcome.
DM: And then there was a civil war between-
Unknown: Between
DM: ... a civil war among Drankorian emperors between, like, Omnis Pura, who became the cleansed, and the other people.
DM: And Omnis Pura won, and then it got shifted pretty dark.
DM: And then 200 years after that, Apollyon came to power and everything fell apart.
Kenzo: Okay.
DM: So there was this... I mean, this you all learned from Orestes, right, the elf.
DM: Like, there was-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... this
DM: early period before the civil war when, like, elves were welcome in Drankor, like everybody, like there were all sorts of species in Drankor, right?
DM: Like dwarves and stoneborn and anybody,
DM: um...
DM: But then it became increasingly human as the-
Kenzo: Mm-hmm
DM: ... after Omnis Pura won the civil war.
Seeker: And so 700 years ago would have been before the civil war.
DM: No, after.
DM: No, that would have been after the civil war.
Unknown: 'Cause-
Kenzo: Civil war was like 900 years ago.
DM: Yes.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Oh, okay.
Delwath: The Drankor fell around 1,000.
DM: I mean, again, don't trust it to the year, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So sometime between when the civil war
DM: ended and when Drankor fell is, like, the basic idea of-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... when the last one fell.
Delwath: But it, it could have been when Drankor-
Unknown: Right after the civil war could have been when Drankor fell, right.
Unknown: Could have been when Drankor fell.
Kenzo: Huh.
Seeker: But so what, well, what was the role of the elves in all this?
Delwath: Well, the Paranar were part, were very much part of Drankorian-
DM: Yeah, like a lot of the early Drankorian emperors were Paranar.
Delwath: So I mean, the elves here could have been Paranar, right?
Unknown: Like, it's not...
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: And so the, the battle being commemorated?
DM: The one Delwath saw a vision of?
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Could have been the Downfall War.
Unknown: So I, I...
Kenzo: So really long time ago.
Delwath: Yeah. Or it could have been some battle that Drankor fought against, I mean, who knows, right?
Kenzo: Right.
Kenzo: So I, I asked the, I asked the tree, um,
Unknown: the names here
Kenzo: written on, on the, uh...
Unknown: Is it a walkway or what's the...
Unknown: Is it-
DM: Um, it-
Unknown: ... like the stone structure
DM: ... so what it looks like is, like, as if branches of the two trees grew, but they were not wood, they were stone until they met.
Unknown: But they, it doesn't block the path?
DM: No, it's on the side of the path.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
DM: It's along the side of the path.
Unknown: Oh, wait, the trees are-
DM: There's two trees on the side of the...
DM: The road goes like this. The trees are here.
Unknown: Ah, got it.
Unknown: And then there's these branches that go between them.
Delwath: I wasn't envisioning... Oh, so the trees aren't on either side.
Unknown: They're both-
DM: The trees aren't on either side.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: They're next to each other.
Unknown: I missed that.
DM: The branches grow-
Unknown: Got it. I thought they were-
DM: ... and where they touch, they kind of turn to this stone-like substance.
Unknown: Yeah, got it, yeah.
Kenzo: The, the names, the names of, uh, the elves here, who are they?
DM: They're who we re- remember, who left too soon.
Kenzo: Why these elves?
DM: They are who we remember.
Kenzo: You said there haven't been pilgrims for centuries.
Kenzo: Why?
DM: We don't know.
Kenzo: There is a-
DM: Hmm
Kenzo: ...
Kenzo: a b- uh,
Kenzo: uh, near here, I saw a pool
Kenzo: with the reflection of Tortured souls.
Kenzo: Do you know what that is?
DM: A pool?
Kenzo: A reflection.
DM: Not all the pools.
DM: Not all the memory pools could be saved.
Kenzo: What are the memory pools?
DM: They're how we remember
DM: the ones who passed on.
DM: All the ones who passed on.
Kenzo: Are the memories stored in the pool?
DM: The tree is sort of confused, like, "What are you talking about?"
DM: Like-
Kenzo: Yeah
DM: ... it's all part of the same thing.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: So.
Seeker: I wonder if that's why the rivers don't make it to the sea.
Delwath: 'Cause they're actually memories and you don't wanna lose them?
Seeker: Or if the rivers are just being diverted for this purpose.
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: I, I think they're more magical than that, right?
Kenzo: Like...
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: [sighs] anything else from the tree?
Kenzo: Is the island...
Kenzo: Are you at peace here?
DM: Seems to like think for a moment.
Unknown: We are at peace,
DM: but beyond
DM: us,
DM: who can say?
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: To the west.
DM: That is beyond us.
Kenzo: The dragon?
DM: Beyond us.
Seeker: I wonder if this is, this is a solitary tree or a network of trees.
Unknown: I mean, it's probably the whole... Yeah, the, the, the forest.
DM: Yeah, it's, I mean, it's clearly the, like it's the whole forest.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's all one thing.
Unknown: Awesome.
Kenzo: The elder dragon. The elder dragonet.
DM: Doesn't say anything.
Kenzo: Friend?
Unknown: I don't, we don't know you yet.
Unknown: Um,
Unknown: Delwath seems fairly, I mean-
Kenzo: You, you don't know me.
Kenzo: Uh, you know, the tr- the, the, um,
Kenzo: the, uh, staff,
Kenzo: jade,
Kenzo: the s-
Kenzo: the story, uh, um...
Kenzo: You don't know me,
Kenzo: but I hope you can sense the stories and the history
Kenzo: and the stories that are told from
Kenzo: my staff.
Kenzo: They tell
Kenzo: the story of me in a way.
DM: You have traveled many places.
Kenzo: I have.
Kenzo: And that's all it says.
Kenzo: Um-
Unknown: Ah. All right. Oh, oh, wait.
Seeker: Did it say you have traveled or I have traveled?
DM: To Kenzo. You have traveled.
Unknown: Might be interesting to ask the tree
Seeker: if it has any sense of the island having moved.
Kenzo: Oh.
Seeker: One way to ask it is if the climate conditions have changed radically [laughs] which we think would happen-
Kenzo: Oh
Seeker: ... if it moved 1,000 miles or whatever.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: That's what's happened.
Kenzo: Ask it that. H- have you ever moved?
Kenzo: Have you-
Unknown: Or have-
Kenzo: Have you ever traveled? 'Cause it, it said, what'd it say?
Kenzo: It said, uh, you, you've traveled.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Ask it if it's ever traveled.
DM: We came later.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: What?
Kenzo: When did you come?
Unknown: Hmm.
Wellby: Ask if there's anyone left on the island who came when the island moved.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: We came
DM: when a refuge
DM: became a memorial.
Kenzo: Oh.
Delwath: Ah, Delwath will ask, there are many elves...
Kenzo: You, you can't talk to the tree.
Delwath: Well, I'm just gonna talk to the-
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Um,
Delwath: there are ma- Delwath seems sort of moved by all this.
Delwath: There are many elves who have died with no one to remember them.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: Hmm.
Delwath: Can, can you accept more memories?
DM: We have not.
DM: We have been cut off for a long, long time.
DM: Once, yes.
Kenzo: Okay, so, so this is the last thing.
Kenzo: Um, this is less, like, communicated in words, but more like,
Kenzo: um,
Kenzo: I, I seek or, or, um,
Kenzo: your memorial, your mem- uh, your memorial is beautiful.
Unknown: It tells the stories
Kenzo: of those you seek to remember.
Kenzo: I also...
Kenzo: And, and you do it through these, through the names of the, those who- ...
Kenzo: uh, y- are to be remembered,
Kenzo: I also tell the stories of those I want to remember,
Kenzo: um, and can be remembered.
Kenzo: Uh, and I, I basically tell it that I want to also remember it, and I'm saying it as, like, the...
Kenzo: Like, and I- I'm asking for it to share back to me a memory or an image that I can put into the staff.
DM: You... Yeah, I guess what you're going for.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, you see, you see an image of
DM: what must be long ago, the moon still shining, um,
DM: and people walking on the road.
DM: A- you know, everybody's, you know, carrying different things.
DM: Like, there's a couple elves, there's humans.
DM: Um,
DM: there's, like, one stoneborn.
DM: Like, it's not... It's a mixed species flock, right?
DM: Like, there's this just people traveling, and, and you do get the feel it, like you have a sort of vibe, right?
DM: It's not a clear image. It's more of a vibe.
DM: Yeah. It is mostly humans and elves, but...
DM: And everybody is remembered in different ways, right?
DM: The, the
DM: humans have their gods, the elves have their gods.
DM: But everywhere through the forest, everybody is remembered.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: And then, and you get the vibe of, like, the forest.
DM: Y- you know, it's vibrant, right?
DM: It's like, you know, the s- the moon is shining, but the leaves are sort of rustling.
DM: The f- flowers are blooming.
DM: There's... And it seems it's much more alive than it seems now.
DM: Like, the trees are fine, right, but there's-
Kenzo: Hmm
DM: ... just less.
DM: Th- everything's duller-
Kenzo: Mm-hmm
DM: ... than it once was, and
DM: there's almost this echo of, like, a sense of loss.
DM: Like, something was
DM: cut off.
DM: Something was...
DM: The, the, the forest, the trees, all speaking as the collective sense, were
DM: isolated somehow.
Kenzo: And they don't know how.
DM: They don't know how.
Kenzo: Yeah. All right.
Kenzo: Yeah, 'cause I was gonna carve, like, a really cool, like,
Kenzo: forest thing, like, around the,
Kenzo: with the path and people walking through it.
DM: You're growing a bit elvish.
Kenzo: What's that?
Delwath: You're growing a bit elvish, Kenzo.
Kenzo: What you talking about? I'm just...
Kenzo: I just, I just honor, um, really cool stories.
Unknown: From all species.
Kenzo: From all species, 'cause all species matter, Delwath.
Unknown: [laughs]
Kenzo: All species matter.
Kenzo: All species matter. [laughs] Ah.
DM: I mean, the vibe of the forest is very much not, like, only elves matter, right?
DM: It's like-
Kenzo: Oh, interesting. Wow, mixed species must make you feel a little weird, huh, being in this, like, place where-
Unknown: Everybody matters. That's what we always say
DM: This memorial is an elven memorial, but it doesn't mean that there are no other memorials elsewhere.
Kenzo: Cool. Uh, Kenzo, you know, gratefully thanks the tree.
Wellby: Hmm. Do you ask if there are any other trees from before the island was here?
Kenzo: Oh, yeah. I ask it that.
DM: Trees from b- No, the...
DM: They don't really understand the question.
DM: There's not... They don't... There's not many trees.
DM: There's just one.
Kenzo: Oh, wait, it's, it's, it, it-
Wellby: No, so the whole of the forest has not traveled.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: It's like one-
DM: It's like one
Wellby: ... kind of thing.
Kenzo: But they... I, I also, when I asked it if it had, if it had traveled,
Kenzo: it said that...
Kenzo: So it's, but it said, yeah, that said-
DM: We came when-
Kenzo: After the memorial
Unknown: ... a refuge turned to a memorial.
Kenzo: Right. So, so they were here, they were here before the...
Kenzo: after the island moved.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Seeker: And it was a refuge. For whom?
Delwath: It was a refuge for the people fleeing Hkar.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: And then it became a memorial.
Delwath: And then it became a memorial of all the losses in the Downfall.
Unknown: I wonder if it was part of Hkar.
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, we'll find out when we play the Downfall-
DM: Oh, huh
Kenzo: ... campaign.
Delwath: Maybe it's part of Hkar and it has that same magic of-
Kenzo: Our, our, our characters from the Downfall campaign have to create the island, so-
Unknown: Wait, what's, what's the-
Kenzo: ... there's a whole-
Unknown: Finish that thought
Delwath: Well, there's a, there's a non-canonical idea, what Tim was saying earlier, that maybe Hkar has some special magic about it that makes divine...
Delwath: It makes it easier to birth new gods.
Unknown: Ah.
Delwath: But that's why Apollyon came here, is because he wants to become a god.
Unknown: Hmm.
Delwath: So how is he gonna birth himself as a new god?
Delwath: Well, there's a magic to Hkar.
Seeker: How would we find out if this was actually part of Hkar?
Delwath: Well, I think the next step is to explore the various places that Tim has set on the island.
Unknown: Trust your leader.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: I mean, Dunmire Seeker has, like, various abilities.
Seeker: Shit. What do you n- [laughs] There's something that I can find out by doing something that I'm supposed to know, but I don't know that I know.
Kenzo: [laughs] If only I read my character sheet.
DM: You can do things like Kenzo does.
Kenzo: Talk to the stone.
Unknown: Oh, wait.
Seeker: I have, like, my stone sense and my tremor sense, but those are just to, like,
Seeker: find out what kinds of stone are there, not, like, talk to the stone.
Unknown: Is it-
DM: No, you can't talk to the stone.
Unknown: But what are...
Kenzo: [laughs]
Seeker: The stone sense ability just changed, so let me just-
Kenzo: I mean, we are walking on, like, weird magic stone roads and stuff, or...
Seeker: Can I... How do I
Seeker: do... What characterizes Hkar
Unknown: stone-wise?
Kenzo: Can you talk to the, or can you sense the weird clip material stone things?
DM: I mean, you can alternately replace one or both of your questions with information of a similar scope.
Kenzo: What is it?
Unknown: About, like, age.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: But, no, would that tell us anything about Hkar?
DM: Well, I don't know.
DM: You could certainly find out how old the stone is, though.
Kenzo: That would be super useful.
Seeker: I missed that part about the scope.
Seeker: Oh, I will ask about tunnels, burrows, or other significant undergroun- underground excavation You get two.
Delwath: Ask for how old it is and underground.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Okay, okay.
DM: It's only within 1,000 feet though.
Seeker: But, but we're up, we're up near the top of the mountain, right?
DM: You could wait till you're like within 1,000 feet from the top of the mountain, yeah.
Seeker: It sounds like we should wait till within, we're within 1,000 feet of the top of the mountain to do this.
Unknown: Yeah. Uh, that sounds wise.
Wellby: Aren't we within...
Delwath: I mean, we're not, but the trees were further down.
DM: Oh, I guess actually as, as, by a straight line you are probably within 1,000 feet of the top.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: 'Cause the trees are where, the trees are like partway up, so the, like all of the roads come in to like this central
DM: circular road that like spirals up-
Wellby: Right
DM: ... to the top. So.
Wellby: Fine.
Kenzo: I only ever eat Swedish Fish with you guys.
DM: Evil.
DM: Um.
Wellby: Eric's-
DM: So yeah, okay.
Unknown: Eric's like...
Delwath: There's a smarter end of the table and a stupider end
Wellby: ... Eric, I need more Ted to the table.
Unknown: All right, I'll just have, I can only have the one.
Kenzo: This is ce- this is ceremonial right now 'cause it's all of us together.
DM: Okay, so you come, so as you-
Wellby: Oh.
DM: So you're probably [laughs] if you follow the spiral-
Unknown: [laughs] I'm still not done
DM: ... if you follow the spiral up the road, you're probably still about a mile from the top, but by, if you just went straight up you're like 1,000 feet from the top.
Unknown: Just like him to do that. Okay.
DM: 'Cause the road sort of goes in a very gradual-
Unknown: All right, so now's actually a reasonable time-
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... to do this tense. All right, I'm gonna.
DM: So
DM: the stone is
DM: like...
DM: Oh my God, I look at my tense roll.
DM: Um,
DM: yeah, it's very old. It's like,
DM: I don't know, 3,000 years old.
Wellby: Oh, okay.
DM: Something like that.
Unknown: Would that line up historically?
Unknown: That'd be well before the Downfall Wars.
Unknown: All right.
Wellby: But, but if the stone is anything less than the age when time began, then it was-
Unknown: No, humans weren't created when time began
Unknown: ... humans weren't created when time began.
DM: The, the timing is roughly when humans were created is the age of the stone.
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah, that's part of the time. All right.
Unknown: All right.
DM: And there is one tunnel.
Unknown: Word.
Seeker: And crap, it's weather present.
Unknown: [laughs] It's not where.
Unknown: Okay.
Unknown: Cool.
DM: Actually a non-trivial amount.
DM: I mean, it's not just one tunnel, right?
DM: Like it's a, there's a
DM: little bit of a tunnel complex
DM: somewhere.
Seeker: Probably underneath the monastery up there.
DM: Nope.
DM: So you continue.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: You reach the top
DM: around, I don't know, 10:00 PM.
DM: No. Yeah, probably 10:30, something like that.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I should have had four. That was too many.
Wellby: You had four?
DM: [laughs] That's just how many came out of the bag.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: It was a mistake.
DM: Um,
DM: so you, so as you come, you come out into this sort of clear area, the top, you know, 500 feet of the mountain is exposed.
DM: And you can see now clearly the structure, right?
DM: There's these eight temples arrayed, arrayed in a circle.
DM: There's the courtyard, there's the bell tower with the lighthouse like thing on top, and then on the outskirts there's like a number of administrative buildings.
DM: There's like clearly like one building that's fairly large and that would have been the like hostel where pilgrims could spend the night before they make the journey back the next day,
DM: right? If they arrive at dawn and they do their prayers or whatever.
DM: Um,
DM: there's,
DM: ah, you know, there's like clearly like living quarters for, um, you know, for it, whoever would've staffed this.
DM: There's, um,
DM: what... You haven't seen this before, but it looks like a,
DM: uh, like a,
DM: a mess hall where you can see it's, it's all open.
DM: It, like the, the living quarters in this are, are, and the hostel are like, you know, stone buildings basically intact, so you can't see into.
DM: But then there's like a large area where there's, um, I don't know, maybe 15 of these little arcane circles arrayed in a sort of nice way with
DM: stone benches sort of carved so people could like sit and congregate and eat.
DM: But it looks like space for a pretty large number of people, like 100 people could have ha- shared a meal there.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Peak pilgrimage season was heavy traffic.
DM: Yeah.
DM: No signs of anything moving.
DM: You can see the Temple of the Sibyl.
DM: It's obvious.
Unknown: Tell us about the Sibyl.
DM: So the Sibyl is the,
DM: the
DM: deity who is associated with
DM: magic
DM: and,
DM: um,
DM: knowledge, but also like song and love and beauty, and sometimes like obsession.
DM: [coughs] Um, her, but she's most known as, she's most like associated with like-
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: ... scholars and magic.
Unknown: Hmm. So are we knocking on the front door?
Wellby: There's only one entrance?
DM: There's only one entrance to the temple.
DM: E- all of the temples have like one main door facing the courtyard.
Unknown: I wanna check for traps.
Wellby: [laughs] Is it a single block of stone that's fr- Yeah, so I'll sneak over very stealthily to
Wellby: check out the operation of this. What I'm thinking is we have the immovable rod.
Wellby: Can we just put it above the door and hold the stone up and keep it from falling down?
Wellby: Would it just hit and tilt?
Seeker: It'll bound, it'll tip over, yeah
Wellby: Uh, depending on the geometry of the thing.
Kenzo: Would you like mage hand or like hold the stone in place?
Wellby: It's heavy.
DM: It's, it's too heavy, yeah.
Kenzo: So actually, is this like a formidable trap?
DM: Side door?
DM: Rear door?
Wellby: [clears throat]
Wellby: Mystica.
Delwath: I mean, we could just dimension door to the other side.
Wellby: Anyways, so-
Unknown: How many, how many people can dimension door?
Wellby: Oh.
Unknown: Okay. Yeah.
Wellby: Very, very stealthily look for how to disarm it.
Wellby: Willby, stealthy?
DM: Okay. Uh, make a stealth check and a, a, a investigation.
Wellby: Stealth's 25.
Wellby: Investigation is tw-
Wellby: uh, investigation is 12.
DM: Um, yeah, so you can tell there's a, what looks like, I mean, it's a very fine, very fine tripwire that runs along, and it's actually like, so
DM: the doors,
DM: um,
DM: the, the doors swing out.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: And the way it's been rigged is so that in order to swing the doors open, you would have to break this little tripwire.
Unknown: Wait,
Delwath: is the stone above us or is it inside the temple?
DM: It's inside the temple.
Unknown: Okay.
DM: You can't see the stone, but there's, there's a little hole that goes through one of the doors, like on the side of the temple, right?
DM: So it's like you swing it open, this tripwire breaks, some mechanism
DM: on the other side is released, and that moves a block that drops the pulley or something like that.
Unknown: But-
Wellby: So-
Delwath: ... if we just open the doors and don't walk through them, is it just gonna fall on us from above?
DM: No, it's, it is on the front of the door, so if you pull the doors open, the doors break the tripwire.
DM: It's like right, so there's two double doors.
Unknown: Right, but I'm so confused. Okay. So-
Kenzo: Is the stone gonna swing down and smashes the face or is it like just drop straight?
DM: It's probably gonna swing down and smash you in the face.
Unknown: Ah, okay.
Wellby: Yeah. [laughs]
Delwath: So I'll just open the door with mage hand.
Delwath: I mean, is it worth doing anything else?
Wellby: You know, it seems like he went to a lot of trouble to make the trap, like-
Unknown: You mean let's not trigger it?
Wellby: ... springing it seems rude.
Delwath: [laughs] Well, do you want to dimension door to the other side?
Wellby: Let's, um, tie another rope onto the wire and keep a constant tension, and then you can-
DM: Yeah
Wellby: ... open the door without tripping the wire.
Unknown: Great.
Wellby: I'll try that. I'll jump out of the way if the stone-
DM: Okay
Wellby: ... falls, right?
Wellby: What's disarm traps?
Wellby: Is that a-
DM: Um,
DM: I mean-
Wellby: ... use tools?
Wellby: I don't know.
DM: Sure. I think given that you have an idea for how to work, it's pretty easy to set it off.
Wellby: 24.
DM: Yeah. Okay. So Wellby takes a bit of rope and like ties it so it keeps constant tension,
DM: and then you just open the doors.
Wellby: All right.
DM: What happens,
DM: you can see there's a giant stone block that's like angled down.
DM: It would like swing. It's the size of the doors.
DM: So if you normally open the doors, it would swing and clip you in the middle of the chest.
Wellby: Oh, I'm gonna give a good appreciative look and just gonna say, "Yes, that's some pretty nice work."
Wellby: Uh-
Unknown: Hello?
Wellby: And then let's, uh-
DM: Well, go in
Wellby: ... go in, yeah.
DM: Um,
DM: there's nothing inside.
DM: I mean, there's no movement.
Wellby: Oh.
DM: You say hello.
Kenzo: God, I really want to say Dimitar, but we wouldn't have it at all.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: You wouldn't. You s-
Delwath: I'll say, I'll say hello, Elder Dragonet in Elvish.
DM: The, the [laughs]
DM: the-
Delwath: Eldest. What, what did the rumor call him, the eldest?
DM: The, just the, just elder.
Unknown: Elder.
Wellby: Elder, yeah.
Unknown: I'll, I'll call out hello, elder.
DM: So the layout inside is like there's, you know, there's like-
Unknown: I'm also just casting detect thoughts, by the way
DM: ... there's a,
DM: um,
DM: you know, there's like p- there's like places people sit.
DM: There's like, it's like a sort of, sort of standard like temple arrangement.
DM: It's, it's circ- it's like sort of circular.
DM: There's seating in the middle.
DM: There's like an altar and a statue of The Sibyl at the far end.
Unknown: Bullshit. [laughs]
DM: And when you say in Elvish, um, the temple of The Sibyl booms out in a booming voice in Elvish, "Who dares disturb the rest
DM: of the gods?"
Unknown: Hmm. Is there any-
Wellby: That doesn't sound like-
Unknown: ... thinking-
Wellby: ... the temple of The Sibyl
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: No. Is there [laughs] it doesn't.
DM: Is there-
Unknown: It sounds like the Wizard of Oz
Unknown: ... it, it does. It sounds like a magic mouth.
Wellby: Yeah.
Delwath: Is there any thoughts within 30 feet of me?
DM: Uh, within 30 feet?
DM: No.
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: Can I look very, very perceptively
Wellby: around the room?
DM: You want to like walk around and search?
Delwath: Oh, I'm also gonna see invisible before we go in.
DM: Okay. [laughs]
Wellby: I'm gonna try and hear invisible.
DM: But are you... You're currently all like standing in the doorway, right?
Unknown: I'm-
Wellby: On the inside, out of the way in case the trap springs, but yeah, swinging
DM: ... yeah, yeah.
Delwath: Yeah. I'm gonna walk like, uh, how big is it and how far is it from here to the other end?
DM: Like
DM: 80 feet.
Unknown: Okay. So I'll walk towards the middle.
Delwath: I'll call out hello a few... I'll, I'll ignore, Delwath's gonna ignore the booming voice.
DM: As you start walking, the booming voice says, "Halt, or the gods will punish you."
Unknown: Okay.
Wellby: I'm gonna check for traps.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Hold on. K- Kenzo, Kenzo just, just, uh...
Kenzo: So I saw a vision of this creature with Rai
Kenzo: in a d- in, when was the-
DM: In Dranikor with the Rai statues talking to the awakened soul monks.
Kenzo: Okay. And, and, and I had that vision when?
DM: You had, it was like a dream you had like long ago in Dun.
DM: It was like,
DM: you don't know what time it was, but you had it like around the time you were exploring the monastery of the-
Kenzo: Okay
Unknown: ... of the Beachmen monks and sort of Dranikor.
Kenzo: Okay. I say, I just say,
Kenzo: "Elder Dragon, I've seen you before
Kenzo: in the presence of..."
Kenzo: Do I, we, we, I know that that statue is Rai, right?
DM: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: We know who Rai is.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I've s- I've seen you before in a vision
Kenzo: with Rai as a statue being visited by monks of my order.
Kenzo: I've seen a vision of you.
Kenzo: I have in my possession...
Kenzo: Or,
Kenzo: when I was born
Kenzo: my parents gave me
Kenzo: a piece of jade that I've carried with me my entire life.
Kenzo: I think you know what that is.
Kenzo: And my companions and I over the past
Kenzo: years...
Kenzo: A year? A year?
DM: Yeah, it's been more than a year.
DM: It's like a year and a half
Kenzo: ... have found more of these pieces which we know are important
Kenzo: as a part of Rai's quest.
Kenzo: And then Kenzo will make a little motion and then the top of his staff which has, is currently covered-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like will re- will, will warp back and reveal.
DM: There's a booming voice that says, "The gods demand proof that you are friends and allies of this great wizard before they will speak to you."
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Wellby will say, will point to the staff and say, "It, isn't that what he just did?"
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] You might be thieves.
Kenzo: I mean,
Wellby: I mean we might but-
Seeker: Should I just turn this thing off with the spell magic?
DM: Sure.
Kenzo: Turn, turn, I'm not even [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Have the little tiny voice.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: He's like he's got a teeny voice. That's fine.
Seeker: It's just Dimitar like behind it pulling strings.
Kenzo: Yeah, but it's fine. It's fine.
Kenzo: Um, uh, we, we share, we share Rai's purpose of making sure
Kenzo: W- Apollyon stays captive.
DM: Delwath is now standing in the middle.
Delwath: Could I detect where Dimitar, where this creature's thoughts are?
Wellby: Nope.
DM: I, I say that then.
Unknown: Oh.
Kenzo: Mm.
Seeker: I put my hand to the f- to the stone floor and use tremor sense.
DM: Uh,
DM: there is something moving about 10 feet below the ground in a tunnel.
Seeker: I just look around and go like... [laughs]
DM: It's blocked by one foot of stone.
Unknown: Detect thoughts. Uh.
Kenzo: Wait, hold on. Hold on.
Wellby: I look for, uh, entrances to the tunnel.
DM: Wait, but it's kind of cool.
Wellby: Circular Island.
DM: We just need-
Wellby: Yeah, yeah. While, while we're still talking
DM: ... yeah, we just need to prove that we're friends.
Delwath: What, I'll, I'll, I'll ask what proof would you accept?
Unknown: [laughs]
Delwath: If you're not accepting this proof, what proof would you accept?
DM: The, the gods are thinking for a moment.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs] Wait, can, can you see us right now?
Wellby: Like could you see the staff?
Unknown: There's four pieces. Four, four.
Kenzo: That's the-
Wellby: You see the jade.
DM: The gods can only hear.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs] Man, it's amazing.
Wellby: But that was a really dramatic reveal.
Unknown: It was a, it was awesome.
Unknown: The gods can hear no evil.
Unknown: [laughs] They cannot see no evil.
Unknown: Uh, what, hmm.
DM: Walk forward into our presence.
Kenzo: Walk forward.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Show me that again. [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, mighty gods. [laughs]
Wellby: I sort of subtly gesture where the spy hole is to look up to.
DM: You notice that like, okay, so in, um, there must be a tunnel that runs underneath the floor and then goes up like at the base of the statue and you can, Wellby would notice this.
DM: You can see that there's...
Unknown: A little peephole
DM: ... a little peephole like cut into the-
Unknown: That's great
DM: ... like base of the statue.
Kenzo: Yeah. So, so Kenzo, "Oh, mighty gods," [laughs] and then shows the, shows the, shows the staff.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah, he has the staff out.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That would have been much more dramatic if you had waited.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs]
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: The gods do not appreciate your sense of timing.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: [laughs] Forgive me.
Kenzo: Forgive us, oh, mighty gods, for our poor timing,
Kenzo: and like le- and poor sense of dramatic timing.
DM: Um, you hear a tu- like, uh, behind the altar you hear like a scraping stone and the
DM: like so like somebody's moving a, like a, um, a stone tile, and then like climbing up you see this ancient, um,
DM: elderly dragonet, like again sort of grayish, the, what you saw in scrying.
DM: Um, and he's walking slowly.
DM: He's carrying like a short staff in one hand and a wand in the other that he's still kind of pointing at you.
Kenzo: Oh, shit.
DM: Um,
DM: and he says,
DM: not in a booming voice anymore, um,
DM: kind of blinking a little bit, "I would know the story of where you got those fragments."
Kenzo: You want to know the story?
DM: It seems important.
DM: You say there's... Wait, did you say that you were seeking one on the island?
Delwath: In our letter, but not since, not-
DM: Oh, okay. Not that-
Kenzo: Yes
DM: ... he doesn't say anything about that.
DM: He obviously didn't read the letter.
Kenzo: Yeah. [laughs] Um, well,
Kenzo: as I mentioned, um,
Kenzo: one I've had carried with me.
Kenzo: One was in, uh, what was the elvish forest thing?
Kenzo: Uh.
Delwath: It was in the Elderwood.
Kenzo: One was in the Elderwood.
Kenzo: One was with the merfolk,
Kenzo: and-
Unknown: Irske, in the far north.
Kenzo: And one was in Irsk, in the far north.
Kenzo: What do you know of this,
Kenzo: these pieces?
DM: Nothing.
DM: I mean, I know what they are.
Kenzo: You know about the other one that's here on this island?
DM: No.
Unknown: Really?
Kenzo: Is he a- aura sense. So it's, yeah, detecting-
Delwath: I'm detecting thoughts. What are his surface thoughts?
Unknown: He doesn't get a save.
Kenzo: Um.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: Worn out.
DM: He's, like, super curious about...
DM: Like, he's...
DM: I mean, he's definitely...
DM: He's, like, thinking of Rai and, like, where did these people come from?
DM: Like, obviously they're...
DM: I mean, like, pretty much trust that Rai wouldn't let
DM: strange evil people carry around fragments of-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... his hand, but doesn't seem to know anything about the jade.
Unknown: I mean, I, I only get, like...
Unknown: Without him getting a save-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... I only get, like, basic surface thoughts.
DM: Okay.
Unknown: So not, like, deep motivations.
Kenzo: So yeah, like, aura, aura read.
Kenzo: Like, what's his, what's his deal? Is he, like, a ultra powerful...
DM: No.
Kenzo: Like that guy.
DM: He's not ultra powerful.
Kenzo: He's like a normal... What, what's his, uh, what's his-
DM: Eh, he's like, you know, he's...
DM: He spent, like, hundreds of years associated with Rai.
DM: He's not without his tricks.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: But he's definitely weaker than you.
Kenzo: Right. Right, right.
DM: He'd be, like, level seven or something.
Unknown: Okay. So it is Dimitaur.
DM: Yeah, it's Dimitaur.
Unknown: Wow.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: yeah. There's a- another piece.
Kenzo: In fact, we believe the final piece.
DM: Where did they come from?
Kenzo: The...
Unknown: Man, where to begin with all this?
Delwath: When did you last see Rai?
DM: 39 years ago.
Unknown: And he left to-
DM: I think that's right
Unknown: ... try to heal the,
Delwath: the land, and you did not go with him?
DM: No.
Delwath: But that was... Was that the last time?
DM: When he left.
Kenzo: Is he still alive?
DM: I mean,
DM: in some sense. I don't think he can die.
Kenzo: Where is he now?
DM: Still in
DM: Drankor, I think.
DM: I don't know.
Delwath: Wait, we don't know if only his hand shattered or if all of Rai shattered,
Unknown: do we? Do we know?
DM: No.
Unknown: We don't know.
Kenzo: When we found each of these pieces, we've received a vision,
Kenzo: and we've been able to see the moment when his hand shattered.
Kenzo: Were you there?
DM: No.
Unknown: No, that was when he was off trying to-
Kenzo: Yeah
Unknown: ... heal the-
Delwath: ... with the awakened soul monks, right?
Kenzo: Do you know about Apollyon?
DM: I know the stories.
DM: Many stories.
Delwath: But do you know Rai was holding his prison closed?
DM: Of course. What do you think?
DM: I'm not stupid.
DM: What is up with this Alf?
Kenzo: Yeah, we deal with him.
Kenzo: We manage. We just, it's...
Unknown: He means well.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: [laughs]
Kenzo: Um, so you understand the gravity of our quest.
Kenzo: We're trying to find the last piece.
DM: I don't know why.
DM: I mean...
Delwath: He, Rai is no longer holding Apollyon's prison closed.
DM: Oh, well, that's pretty bad.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. That's why, that's why-
DM: So you didn't know that.
Wellby: He's getting out in, like, what, 10 days?
Unknown: 10 days.
Kenzo: 10 days. Yeah.
Wellby: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yes.
Wellby: So are we gonna have-
DM: Oh, shit.
Wellby: [laughs]
DM: Rogam's gonna be pissed.
Wellby: What's gonna be pissed?
Kenzo: Pissed about what?
Delwath: Why is Rogam's gonna be pissed?
Delwath: What do you know about Rogam- Rogam'dros?
DM: I mean,
DM: I don't think she knows about me, and I wanna keep it that way.
DM: So I only get, like, little bits and pieces of rumors.
DM: Uh,
DM: but, like, you know
DM: Chaumut and Apollyon had a big fight, right?
Kenzo: Yeah, we know about that, yeah.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: You know Rogam'dros is Chaumut's daughter.
Unknown: What?
Kenzo: What? Did not know that.
DM: Some
DM: task she was appointed on this island.
DM: Something to guard, I think.
Unknown: Something to guard.
Unknown: Why do I think of Chaumut having sex?
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: Who's to say dragons have-
Unknown: Could, could be-
DM: ... children the normal way?
Kenzo: Immaculate conception. Immaculate conception.
Unknown: Sure. Wow.
DM: Uh.
Unknown: What, what is she guarding?
DM: I don't know.
Unknown: It's not the jade.
DM: What, no.
Unknown: Because that's a more recent arrival.
Wellby: I mean, could it be the island itself
Wellby: somehow?
Kenzo: Could it be the divine forge that Apollyon used to make the scepter of power?
Wellby: Hmm, where is that, by the way?
DM: Somewhere west.
Kenzo: Uh.
Seeker: And, and how did you...
Unknown: Somewhere west on the island?
Kenzo: Yeah, that's the western part of the island. It's all weird.
Unknown: Yeah, the, the, the scary thing.
Seeker: How did you come to stay here, Dimitaur?
Kenzo: Oh, we don't know his name yet.
Unknown: Oh,
Unknown: I thought, I thought we confirmed the name earlier.
DM: That was out of game.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: You can ask his name in game.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah. Actually, yeah. What, what is your name?
DM: Dimitaur.
Kenzo: Huh.
Unknown: How did you come to stay here?
DM: Well,
DM: Rai never came back.
Kenzo: Back here?
DM: Back to where we were in Drankor keeping watch over Apollyon.
Kenzo: Hmm.
DM: I knew he had trained here.
DM: I thought,
DM: let's see.
Kenzo: How long have you been here now?
DM: Like...
DM: 35 years
Kenzo: Are you waiting for Rai here?
DM: Well, I didn't know so many of my people lived here.
DM: Now I'm kind of...
DM: I don't know what to do.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Seeker: What's your relationship like with, with the Dragonets?
DM: I'm pretty sure Ra'ghemdros would kill me if she knew I was here.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: So I don't really talk to them much, but some of them come find me secretly.
Seeker: Do you think you could enlist them to help us?
DM: Help you do what?
Seeker: We're trying to figure that out, but we need to get that jade.
DM: Ah,
DM: planners, I see.
Kenzo: [laughs]
Unknown: Planners, I see.
Kenzo: Does he say that with contempt or [laughs]
DM: A little bit with contempt.
Kenzo: I... We, we don't plan that much.
Kenzo: Don't worry. Um,
Kenzo: so you say-
DM: The important thing is to just not keep the plans you make.
Kenzo: Heh, we never do that.
Wellby: Yeah, we do. Yeah, yeah. Right.
Kenzo: So
Kenzo: the dragon, uh, is she, is she free?
Kenzo: We had a feeling she may also be captive.
DM: Eh.
Kenzo: Can she travel freely?
DM: You mean, like-
Kenzo: Can she leave her lair?
DM: Yeah.
DM: Is that...
DM: Where did you get this idea from?
Kenzo: Uh.
DM: I mean, do you know many dragons that don't leave their lairs?
Delwath: She hasn't seen too much
Delwath: according to the Dragonets down there.
DM: Well, she has some task.
DM: Maybe it's too important.
DM: I don't know.
Seeker: An important task underground?
DM: I'm not here to solve your problems, guys.
Wellby: [laughs]
Unknown: Well, what can we do to help you?
DM: [coughs] Wait, you want to help me?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Well, um,
DM: something more interesting to eat would be nice.
Kenzo: We can help you with that.
Wellby: We've got these berries. They're pretty good.
DM: Oh, well, fruit's easy.
DM: My circles make it.
Delwath: Hmm. I'll send the...
Delwath: my lynxes out to go collect some food.
Kenzo: I can make you a meal, Dimitar.
Seeker: I suppose this runic food gets a little old
Unknown: day in and day out.
DM: Yeah, it's like 12 menu choices.
Kenzo: That's...
DM: You gotta go out there. There's...
DM: The biggest thing is none of the ones up here are seafood.
Kenzo: Ah.
Seeker: Of course, you like a little seafood once in a while, but it's hard to get down there 'cause of all the other Dragonets, so...
DM: Also, you know, at my age,
DM: I'm not as agile as I once was in the air.
Unknown: Hmm.
Kenzo: Hmm. Yeah.
Unknown: Of course. Of course.
Kenzo: Yeah. Hmm.
Kenzo: Uh, so just so you know,
Kenzo: this is our plan.
Kenzo: I know you're not, you know, but just curious your thoughts on it.
Kenzo: We, uh, want to get that last piece of jade.
Kenzo: Um, I think when we put those pieces together, um, you know, I mentioned I got a...
Kenzo: been getting a vision of, of Rai basically every time we find one of these pieces of jade.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: we
Kenzo: suspect at least that once we get the final piece together,
Kenzo: we're gonna get a pretty important piece of information about where Apollyon is,
Kenzo: um, storing himself,
Kenzo: and probably in Drankor someplace.
DM: Where-
Kenzo: Probably gonna have to go in.
DM: Wait, you don't know that already?
Kenzo: Do you know?
DM: You haven't, like, scouted?
Kenzo: We haven't been to Drankor yet, no.
DM: His tomb is pretty obvious.
Kenzo: Yeah?
Delwath: But his tomb is not where his, uh-
Wellby: Phylactery is
Unknown: ... phylactery is.
Unknown: That would be pretty tough.
DM: Oh, you want to kill him,
DM: not just lock him up?
Unknown: If you can.
Wellby: Yeah, how would we lock him up?
DM: I don't know. Retie the knots.
DM: Aren't you magic?
Kenzo: Eh, not that way.
Wellby: Yeah, no.
Kenzo: I mean, maybe Rai could help us.
DM: Oh, well, that's much harder.
Kenzo: Why is that much harder?
DM: Well, I don't know where his phylactery is.
Kenzo: I... But, well, that's why we get the last piece of jade and then we figure out where the phylactery is.
Unknown: [laughs] Have you been listening to our story?
DM: Oh, you think Rai knows where his phylactery is?
DM: Oh, maybe he does, actually.
DM: Hmm.
DM: Interesting.
Kenzo: Can you help us find Rai?
DM: I looked.
Kenzo: Yeah, in Drankor, huh? Couldn't find him.
DM: He never came back.
Wellby: Hmm.
DM: He went off with the monks.
Wellby: Oh, the monks.
DM: Wait, that was your friends who convinced him to do that?
Kenzo: I think Rai was the one that was convincing them.
DM: Oh, that's possible.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Wellby: [laughs]
Kenzo: The other way around with the convincing.
DM: I know he did. Like, they had a few little successes.
Kenzo: Successes doing what?
DM: Cleaning up the Seeds of Chaos.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Then they went for the big one.
DM: I thought it was a mistake.
Kenzo: Does Cha'mut have other children?
Unknown: If only he'd listened.
DM: Yeah, if only Rai... Rai never...
DM: He didn't listen to me.
DM: Damn it.
Kenzo: What, what, what, what, what was your advice to Rai?
Kenzo: What were you trying to get him to do?
DM: Don't go to the gi- the biggest, giantest Seed of Chaos and try and fix it in Isingue.
DM: That seems like a stupid thing to do.
Seeker: That's how all those, those monks were lost, presumably.
DM: Mm.
Delwath: Remember, that's the acidic ooze that we flew over.
Kenzo: What is?
DM: Oh.
Kenzo: Oh.
Wellby: Yeah. No, I think you were right.
Unknown: [laughs] Dimitar's-
DM: This one's smart
Seeker: ... Dimitar's got some insights into how the world works.
Delwath: But maybe after we kill Apollyon we should go figure it out.
Seeker: Well, we should see what Dimitar says about that.
Kenzo: Yeah. Wait, but, yeah, but, but what were you trying to tell Rai?
Unknown: So your, your, your advice to Rai was-
Unknown: It did hurt our ship after all
DM: ... don't go. It's the biggest place of all.
Unknown: We gotta take revenge
Unknown: It's true.
DM: But he was pretty sure he could do it.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: Huh.
Kenzo: Um,
Kenzo: Shemut has other children?
DM: I don't know.
Kenzo: How do you know this is Shemut's daughter?
Unknown: You haven't heard her brag?
Kenzo: What's brag?
Unknown: When did you talk to her?
DM: I didn't talk to her. You didn't ask it.
DM: You just never bothered to ask.
DM: Like-
Kenzo: Ask who?
DM: Any of the stupid dragonets flying around.
DM: I am... He's, like, imitating somebody.
DM: I am Ra'ghemdros, daughter of Shemut.
DM: I am the Light Stealer and the Final Shadow, the Devourer of Drankor, known as the Eternal Night.
DM: She's not shy about it.
Kenzo: She's pretty boastful, huh?
Unknown: Those are some good names though.
Kenzo: Yeah?
Unknown: Uh, we haven't seen the ending though.
Kenzo: Yeah, we have. We just, we just haven't been there that long.
Kenzo: We've only been here for half a day. So, so okay, so she's Shemut's daughter.
Kenzo: She's here on some task that Shemut
Kenzo: has put her to.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Nominally.
DM: Yep.
Kenzo: And you don't know what that task is.
Delwath: Hey, did the hobgoblin wizard who's in the...
Unknown: She was against Shemut, right?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: You know who might be an ally killing Shemut's daughter?
Seeker: Is the hobgoblin wi- wizard we have trapped in the mirror?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Wellby: She's not gonna go back in the mirror again after what's happened.
DM: No, of course not.
Seeker: No, her... What she gets in re- in return is...
Unknown: Well, no, we can't give her the island.
Wellby: We can't exactly stop her from taking [laughs].
Delwath: We could, we could try to kill her though.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: Double cross her.
DM: Maybe a bad idea.
Unknown: I, yeah, that's-
DM: But, like, there's something here.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: But she was an ally of Shemut?
DM: Enemy.
Kenzo: Enemy.
DM: But she was trapped by...
DM: She tried to trap Shemut in the mirror, and he was like, "No, no, no, you go in the mirror."
Kenzo: Yeah.
Wellby: Oh, maybe we could s- maybe she knows about Ra'ghemdros.
DM: We could talk to her.
Unknown: That'd be a great person to talk to.
Unknown: I think it's a good idea.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah, uh-
Delwath: She might help us just to see Ra'ghemdros die, even in not being freed.
Wellby: But also, what if she's been biding her time this entire time, and, like, could have left the prison at any moment, and now we take her out and talk to her and-
Unknown: We're not taking her out to talk to her.
Unknown: We're talking to her in the mirror.
DM: No, we can talk to her in the mirror.
Unknown: Hm.
DM: I, I think we should talk to her.
Kenzo: Hold on, hold on. But let's just... We're, th- we're talking to Dimitaur now, right?
Kenzo: So what else do we do- want to learn from Dimitaur?
Kenzo: Can you help us find Rai
Kenzo: now? 'Cause we're going to Drankor next after this, almost certainly.
DM: I do not wanna go back to Drankor.
DM: [coughs]
Delwath: But you know it pretty well.
DM: I do.
Unknown: Okay.
Kenzo: One favor.
Kenzo: Maybe you can help us with a map.
Delwath: Hm. I was gonna say, can we spend, like, two hours
Delwath: digging through everything he knows about Drankor?
DM: You can, but you can't hear it now because I haven't made it up.
Unknown: Yes, I know. That's what I was just gonna say.
Kenzo: That's fine.
DM: Um-
Delwath: I mean, would he... What, why don't we just, like, c- c- could you tell us everything you know?
DM: Yeah, I could tell you some stuff.
Kenzo: Look, here's the basics.
Kenzo: We get the last piece of jade.
Kenzo: Hopefully, that tells us where the phylactery is.
Kenzo: Almost certainly it's gonna be in Drankor, and then we're gonna go and try and destroy the phylactery.
Kenzo: We expect it's gonna be really hard going there.
Kenzo: Is Drankor now, like, is it, like, some haunted, like, fucked up place that's gonna, like, try to kill us at every turn?
DM: It wasn't really like that when Rai was there.
DM: I bet it's gotten a lot worse.
Kenzo: Since when?
Unknown: Since Rai left.
DM: Since Rai left.
Kenzo: Like 39 years ago?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I couldn't stay much,
DM: like, only a few months.
DM: I only stayed there a few months waiting for him, and it got dark and scary, and there was this, like, aura of fear that radiated out through the whole place coming
DM: from Apollyon's tomb. And every morning, I woke up wanting to run away, and eventually I did.
Kenzo: Hm.
DM: And I'm not sure I could go back.
Kenzo: Yeah, it doesn't sound like a good place.
Kenzo: Um-
Delwath: Collect immunity to fear artifacts.
Kenzo: Or a feast.
Unknown: I think one of the binding-
Unknown: Or Rizwin
Unknown: ... things can
Unknown: be Rizwin. Or Rizwin.
Seeker: I wonder how Rizwin's doing. Oh, well.
Kenzo: So, so-
Unknown: Who knows?
Kenzo: Okay. Anyways, yeah, we appreciate any insights you have 'cause I think we're gonna have to go there.
Kenzo: It sounds pretty scary, but we are gonna try to go there.
Kenzo: And when we go there, if Rai is still there, if, do you have any tips on if we wanna try to find him?
Kenzo: Would you want, would you want his hand back?
DM: I mean,
DM: if I took your hand from you and then showed up, would you want it back?
Kenzo: How do we give it back to him?
DM: I don't know. Like, maybe you could take it and hand it to him.
Unknown: Hand it to him?
Kenzo: Here he is.
DM: This one's got it.
Unknown: Nice.
Kenzo: So, so, so-
Unknown: Nice
Kenzo: ... but yeah, but do you, any, any, any ideas how to find him?
Unknown: Do, do we even know he's findable?
Unknown: I mean, we don't actually-
Kenzo: We're asking. I mean, I don't know.
Unknown: Didn't Dimitaur say that-
Kenzo: Would we even know if he was dead? No, he said he d- can't ever die.
Kenzo: The part is something, somewhere-
Delwath: I mean, he said he couldn't find him and he went looking, and he also said he doesn't think Rai can ever die.
DM: But he wasn't in... Dimitaur could not find him in Drankor.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: Maybe he was, like, trapped for a while and then came back to Drankor somehow.
Kenzo: But what, what I'm trying to say is when you're, when you're looking for some kind of weird, you know, immortal sorcerer or whatever, like, does he respond to anything or, like, is there anything that-
DM: I don't know. Send your, like, spirit dog after him.
Kenzo: Is that what you try to do when you find him?
Kenzo: Like, what do you do when you try to find him?
Delwath: Actually, that's not a bad idea. Why didn't we think of that?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: I don't know. You're just not as smart as he, I guess.
Kenzo: I mean, we're clearly not, but, like, any, any other tips, any other advice for, for finding him?
DM: I mean,
DM: the last place I know he was was Isingay.
Kenzo: Isingay?
Unknown: That's where that acidic ooze is
Kenzo: Huh?
Unknown: When we're all... The whole...
Unknown: It was like-
Delwath: Remember we flew, we flew over Isingue in Vincharna.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: And we went down to investigate 'cause it looked cool, and a tendril of acidic ooze-
Unknown: Yes, totally. I totally remember that
DM: Punched a hole in the-
Unknown: That's the last place where I was?
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: That's when we went with the monks to try and-
Delwath: That is apparently where he was trying to heal the land.
Delwath: That's the seat of chaos. He was trying to get rid of it.
Seeker: So that was a portal or something.
Kenzo: Fuck.
Seeker: But, and all those monks basically died or didn't come back anyway.
DM: They either died or they got scattered around the planes when they were...
DM: when the chaos happened.
Wellby: What do you, what do you think the odds are of killing that dragon?
DM: I couldn't.
DM: I don't know.
DM: You're, like, not too shabby from what I've seen.
DM: I mean, you certainly avoided my trap neatly.
DM: [sighs] But, like...
Seeker: What would it take to lure her out of her lair, though?
Wellby: Yeah. What would get her out?
Kenzo: Yeah. We, we don't want to fight her in there.
Seeker: We've heard that she l-loves shiny things.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: But [coughs]...
Wellby: Why would she kill you if she knew you were on the island?
Wellby: 'Cause of your, like, escape attempt that you led?
Kenzo: Bad influence on the other dragonets.
DM: Yeah. She thinks I'm a bad influence.
Delwath: I mean, she might have a hatred of Rai who killed her father.
Wellby: Yeah, that's fair.
DM: I think she just likes her little simple empire here.
DM: She doesn't like anybody who kinda
DM: speaks up.
Unknown: So you're saying her, um,
Seeker: ambitions aren't as grandiose as Cha'mutte's.
DM: I see no reason why she couldn't leave this island if she wanted to.
Kenzo: So she's s- she's serving some kind of function here that's useful, of use to her deceased dad.
Kenzo: Um, if you were us and, uh,
Kenzo: you needed to
Kenzo: get that piece of jade back from the dragon,
Kenzo: any advice?
DM: If I were you?
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I'd pick an easier quest.
Kenzo: Eh.
Kenzo: Let's say you had to do this one, though.
DM: [laughs] Good.
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh, Dimitar.
Kenzo: Does, um,
Delwath: she keep her deals for the most part?
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: You think she would trade?
DM: She might. I mean, she might just, like, say, "I'll kill you and take your stuff anyway."
Kenzo: But that'd be fine with us.
Wellby: That's okay.
Delwath: Isn't that kind of the opposite of keeping your deals?
DM: Uh... [laughs]
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: She-
Unknown: When you said yes, did you mean no?
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: No, no, no, no, no.
Kenzo: No.
DM: She's never, uh, she's never taken away a tower she gave to a dragonet.
Kenzo: Hm.
DM: But, you know,
DM: who knows? Many of them might go in there and be like, "Hey, here's some stuff," and she says, "I don't like you, so I'll just take that stuff."
Seeker: And she sometimes kills them to prove a point or to make an example of them.
DM: Yeah, sometimes. I mean,
DM: gotta keep a little bit of an aura of fear.
Unknown: But she's consistent, at least.
DM: Patten.
Kenzo: Was she, um...
Delwath: Do you know anything about her relationship with her father?
DM: Not really.
DM: I mean,
DM: all I know is
DM: she's quite boastful and has told many, many dragonets that she is the daughter of Cha'mutte.
Kenzo: Mm.
DM: They've told me, the few who come up here every now and then.
Delwath: Have they been here since, uh...
Delwath: How long have the dragonets been here? Do you know?
Unknown: Oh, you, you didn't know?
DM: [coughs] You guys, like, don't really do your research, do you?
Kenzo: We just got here. Come on. Cut us a break.
Kenzo: Cut us a little... Give us a little break here.
Delwath: I... They said forever, which is clearly not true.
DM: Yeah. They're... We were, we were here...
DM: My people
DM: were on Hkar with the humans.
Unknown: Oh.
DM: We came across.
Delwath: Didn't you just say you didn't realize there were so many of your people here?
DM: I didn't know they survived the plague.
DM: The story that I've fled, like many of us fled to the Feywild, to the Far East, all sorts of distant places when Drancor fell.
DM: Well, even before Drancor fell.
DM: A few,
DM: you know, took in with the Polyron, and a few took in with Cha'mutte, but most of us just got out of dodge.
Kenzo: Hm.
DM: But we were there all the way from the beginning.
DM: I just thought they were all slaughtered on this island.
DM: If they say forever, I think they, like, mean it, probably since the island was made.
Kenzo: Who made the island?
DM: I don't know, like, wizards.
Kenzo: Like human wizards?
Wellby: Wizards don't, uh, don't do your research, huh?
DM: Oh, well, do you have an answer for me?
DM: Do you know who made the island?
Wellby: Yes, but it's a secret.
Kenzo: [laughs]
DM: I don't like this one.
Unknown: [coughs] Yeah, I don't know.
DM: Like, there were all sorts of wizards back in the day.
DM: They could do all kinds of things.
DM: You didn't hear Rai's stories?
DM: Oh, wait, how would you hear Rai's stories?
Kenzo: Yeah. Never met the guy.
Kenzo: Just had some weird rumors about him.
DM: Yeah, he could probably have made this island.
DM: Well, maybe not alone.
Kenzo: He didn't... But he didn't make it, though.
DM: No. It's way older than him.
Kenzo: Yeah. Hm.
Kenzo: Mm-hmm.
DM: Yeah, they could do like, you know, Hkar, with like magic stuff.
Kenzo: Is it, is it true that this island walked?
DM: I, I think so.
Seeker: Where did it come f- walk from?
DM: Hkar.
Unknown: Weren't you listening? [laughs]
DM: Yeah. This guy gets it.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: This one looks like an absent-minded professor.
DM: I think that's what I'm gonna call him.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Dr. Absent-Minded.
Unknown: Yes.
Kenzo: Yeah, that's about right.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Kenzo: Uh, any idea who started the plague?
Unknown: Shemuhitte?
DM: Shemuhitte.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Are you not listening?
Kenzo: Eh.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Eh-
Kenzo: So the plague came here too?
DM: I mean, Shemuhitte and Apollyon hated each other.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: His... Like he had some crappy tower.
DM: Well, it probably wasn't that crappy actually.
DM: It's kind of crappy now.
Kenzo: Apollyon did?
DM: I mean, nobody's been here.
Unknown: Out in the west.
DM: What, where you hide the forges?
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. That's where the forge is.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: So is Shemuhitte's daughter's mission to d- protect the divine forge against Apollyon's return?
DM: Maybe.
DM: I know she doesn't like Apollyon.
Unknown: Would she help us-
Delwath: Yeah, see, I was going there earlier
Unknown: ... to defeat him?
Kenzo: Keep him imprisoned?
DM: Maybe.
Unknown: Like
Unknown: there's an argument that we just-
DM: If she genuinely thought you could kill Apollyon, she might be like, "Hey, go do it."
Seeker: [sighs] Maybe we could even forge something
Unknown: to help us.
Kenzo: Hmm.
Kenzo: If only we had an artificer.
DM: [laughs]
Wellby: Or to help us find the phylactery especially.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: I mean, there is the, we team up with Shemuhitte's daughter and an evil hobgoblin wizard to kill Apollyon and let the consequences be somebody else's problem.
DM: Wait, the evil hobgoblin wizard is against Shemuhitte.
Delwath: Oh, oh, oh, right. Never mind.
Unknown: We gotta pick one.
Kenzo: My enemy's friend is my friend's enemy's enemy.
Unknown: Ah! [laughs]
Delwath: We either team up with the evil hobgoblin wizard to kill Shemuhitte's daughter.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Delwath: Or we team... But she'd probably go join up with Apollyon.
Delwath: Or we team up with Shemuhitte's daughter to kill Apollyon.
Unknown: I like that one.
Seeker: Well, could you get us an introduction?
Unknown: No, I wouldn't-
Delwath: Have you been listening? [laughs]
Delwath: [laughs] But have you been over to the west where Apollyon's tower was?
DM: I will be honest.
Wellby: Is this a change?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That scares me.
Kenzo: What? Why?
Wellby: Hmm.
Delwath: [coughs] So you've been there and it terrifies you, or you're just too scared to go?
DM: Too scared to go.
Wellby: Yeah.
DM: You... Th- th-
Delwath: Weren't you listening to the whole story of Apollyon and the fear?
DM: Apollyon, like super evil.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah, yeah. Oh, yeah.
DM: Uh-
Kenzo: He visits. I've seen him.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I've made eye contact with the guy.
Unknown: Okay. Okay.
Kenzo: Yeah.
DM: I have a, I have a, I have a task for you.
Kenzo: Yeah. Hit me. Go ahead.
DM: If you are a super e- evil wizard who had built a tower on top of a powerful divine forge, would you leave magical defenses or would you leave it completely undefended so anybody
DM: could just walk in without doing...
DM: without any care in the world?
Kenzo: Magical defenses.
Unknown: Bingo.
Kenzo: Yes.
Unknown: Why do you think I don't wanna go?
Kenzo: Magical defenses.
DM: Yes. You got it in one.
Kenzo: Okay.
Unknown: We- we're good at that though.
Unknown: I mean,
Unknown: yeah.
Unknown: Or so we think.
Unknown: We haven't been
Seeker: completely annihilated as a group.
Unknown: So maybe you should go there.
Seeker: Yes. Tangling with those.
Kenzo: Hmm. Hmm.
Delwath: All right. What we should do is stay up for another hour to pick his brain about Drankor, meta write that down that we picked his brain about Drankor.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Take a long rest, and then either go to Apollyon's tower
Unknown: or-
Unknown: Yeah. To negotiate with the dragon
Delwath: ... hatch a plan, which we need to decide what it would be.
Delwath: But it's 2:20. I don't know if you wanted to take a break.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. I actually, I actually need to go do, do my call here.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Let's take a break.
Kenzo: It's the perfect, perfect time.
Unknown: This is a good time to.
Kenzo: Yeah.
Unknown: So, I mean, let's...
Unknown: That was really fun.
Unknown: Let's see-
Kenzo: Well, and I, I thought, yeah, w- we wanna hear some more ride stories too.
DM: We can, we can do a little more Dimitar over the campfire.
Kenzo: Yeah. Yeah. We can do that. We can do that like later.
Unknown: A flashback.
Kenzo: Like, like a flashback or like...
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: We can do a flashback.
Wellby: Yeah. So the choice when we c- reconvene is do we go to the dragon and start with negotiation of some kind to be figured out or do we go to Apollyon's tower and see what's going on there?
Kenzo: So this is the thing-
Delwath: Or do we just decide we should try and kill the dragon possibly by consulting with our hobgoblin wizard who's trapped?
Kenzo: That's what we should do next. We should, we should consult with the hobgoblin.
Kenzo: No matter what, we should talk to the hobgoblin wizard next.
Unknown: That's true. Actually, that's true.
Kenzo: Just to learn, just to get as much from her as we can.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: 'Cause this is the thing,
Kenzo: the dragon,
Kenzo: like we don't know yet the weird purpose that it is staying here for.
Unknown: Right.
Kenzo: Which is gonna be important and maybe potentially linked to whatever's going on in the west.
Kenzo: So if we just go... So we need to s- we just need to understand a little bit more about the dynamics here 'cause there c- it could be that there's like a cool item or a thing that's in Apollyon's tower that the dragon can't get
Kenzo: to, that if we got it, she would willing, be willing to trade with us or, you know...
Wellby: Yeah. Or when Apollyon's prison breaks, this is important for some reason that she has to defend it or-
Unknown: Right
Wellby: ... something else.
Kenzo: Well, we just need to learn a little bit more if we can figure it out.
Unknown: Yeah. I mean,
Unknown: I think
Delwath: that if we wanted to negotiate,
Unknown: it sounds like
Unknown: she would probably...
Delwath: The challenge would be more than anything convincing her that we're not bullshitting when we're actually saying we're gonna kill Apollyon, right?
Unknown: Anyway, let's take a-
Wellby: This feels like a good night's rest. Yeah.
Unknown: Let's, let's take a break.
Wellby: When are we reconvening?